<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Laurel's Works in Progress</title>
 <link href="http://llord1.github.io" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://llord1.github.io"/>
 <updated>2022-04-14T01:26:54-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://llord1.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Laurel Lord</name>
   <email>lalord@my.harrisburgu.edu</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Data Sci. Discussions: Cross-lingual frameworks and natural annotation of crowdsourced online dictionaries</title>
   <link href="http://llord1.github.io/papers/2020/12/02/overview"/>
   <updated>2020-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://llord1.github.io/papers/2020/12/02/overview</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Note: There is an alternative view of this document available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1HfBeQ70vvcXL16Eks098Fbvhe7NWokwA?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;Google Colab&lt;/a&gt;. This is functionally very similar to shared Google docs; offer comments where necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the original iteration/outline of this language study &lt;a href=&quot;https://llord1.github.io/2019/12/01/OriginalLangProposal&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;quick-overlook&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick overlook&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the realm of cross-lingual or multilingual natural language processing (NLP), it does appear that some languages tend to get more attention. Typically well-established languages, with a plethora of linguistic resources to build from, often thrive while low-resource creole languages are left to languish. Creoles are a particular challenge of the NLP community as these languages often arise from often frantic and urgent needs to establish harmony in communication within cacophonous settings. In the Caribbean, creole languages often emerged as a means of survival, and endured as a result of resilience; often speakers struggled to work within the bounds of a dominant prestige language while retaining unique traces of their heritage languages or contact languages. The resilience of this language is currently being tested with the advent of the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic threatening the lives of older language-keepers. Therefore, the careful creation of tools and frameworks is needed to facilitate society’s creole language needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, it is this very discordant origin and complexity of structure that presents issues to the preservation of creole languages. For example, most words in Saint Lucian Kwéyòl/creole focus on emotions, the weather, and other aspects of the natural environment, including animals and food sources  &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#frank2007sources&quot;&gt;(Frank, 2007)&lt;/a&gt;; therefore, finding domain-equivalent literature sources outside of certain contexts can be challenging. Moreover, it is said that just over 83% of vocabulary words have French origins; roughly 3% is English-based, and Amerindian, African, and East Indian sources account for about  ½ % of the total each  &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#frank2007sources&quot;&gt;(Frank, 2007)&lt;/a&gt;.  Even the author of the official creole dictionary acknowledged gaps in its vocabulary was due to the lack of official etymological details of over 11% of documented words &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#frank2001kweyol&quot;&gt;(Crosbie et al., 2001; Frank, 2007)&lt;/a&gt;. Despite the advantage of cross-referencing parallel language data sources, the language challenges are made more complex by many of the vocabulary words lacking details on their origins. Ultimately, the situation could be described as a “Mondrian-like” language setting. This image seems apt to explain this low-resource creole being close to parallel and monolingual data with high-resource languages (like French and English), yet the present language data may belong to different domains (missing reference). Not much NLP research has been done on adapting its components to creole languages, however, the academic tide has been changing as of 2020 &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#soto2020language&quot;&gt;(Soto, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are multiple ways to utilize NLP functions. The increasing popularity of opinion-rich resources such as blogs &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#kweyol_works_joseph&quot;&gt;(Joseph, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;, shopping websites, review portals, and social media platforms &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#kweyol_fb_joseph&quot;&gt;(Joseph, 2020)&lt;/a&gt; are rapidly attracting business people, governments, and researchers alike. Sentiment analysis often garners high interest from businesses. However, there are challenges present in natural language processing, particularly when dealing with sentiment analysis, word-sense disambiguation, and issues with dependency parsers in cross-lingual settings. A major challenge of lexical semantics is creating training data and algorithms that facilitate downstream tasks. Moreover, it has also been said that while there is a lingering ‘bias towards contemporary Indo-European languages’, treebanks for other language families and treebanks for classical languages are on the rise &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#nivre2016universal&quot;&gt;(Nivre et al., 2016)&lt;/a&gt;. It has been suggested that categorizing the challenges and formalizing their interpretation using Universal Dependencies may help create a Saint Lucian Kwéyòl dependency treebank, and later facilitate other needed NLP tasks (such as sentiment analysis of texts). A Saint Lucian Kwéyòl parser may be constructed by leveraging the base knowledge of French syntax. However, these may not be the only tools required to tackle the challenges of digitizing and analyzing creole languages. Therefore, it may be helpful to develop a framework to improve the models for linguistics. Perhaps an extendable framework that can demonstrate its application to low-resource creole languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My current overarching scholarly inspirations deal with universal dependency parching, POS Tagging, and possibly sentiment analysis. Some works have suggested that the lexical deviations inherent to creoles can be accommodated by applying the existing language (like French or English) dependency relation definitions while ensuring consistency with the annotations in other non-French or non-English Universal Dependency (UD) treebanks &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#Wang2020FromGT&quot;&gt;(Wang et al., 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. The document ‘From Genesis to Creole Language: Transfer Learning for Singlish Universal Dependencies Parsing and POS Tagging’ &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#Wang2020FromGT&quot;&gt;(Wang et al., 2020)&lt;/a&gt;, is my main point of reference for now. This is due to the relevance of the topic, and the creativity of the work. Additional considerations may be given to a paper that focuses on ‘NLPyPort’; the authors discuss an ‘NLP pipeline in Python, primarily based on NLTK, and focused on Portuguese’ &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#ferreira2019improving&quot;&gt;(Ferreira et al., 2019)&lt;/a&gt;. This was said to be constructed, in part, from ‘pre-existent resources or their adaptations, but improves over the performance of existing alternatives in Python, namely in the tasks of tokenization, PoS tagging, lemmatization, and NER’ &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#ferreira2019improving&quot;&gt;(Ferreira et al., 2019)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do also acknowledge that I do need to delve into the discussion of treebanks and their creation. Since I am dealing with a creole that is mostly french based, it might be wise to review the works of Anne Abeillé. Her most relevant works might be ‘Treebanks: Building and using parsed corpora’  &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#abeille2012treebanks&quot;&gt;(Abeillé, 2012)&lt;/a&gt;, ‘Building a treebank for French’ &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#abeille2003building&quot;&gt;(Abeillé et al., 2003)&lt;/a&gt; and ‘Enriching a French treebank’ &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#abeille2004enriching&quot;&gt;(Abeillé &amp;amp; Barrier, 2004)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I just wanted to highlight my three sources of inspiration concerning meaningful social and linguistic projects; these were the works of Abraham Maslow, Luisa Maffi, and Dr. Bruno Gonçalves. Consideration of Maslow’s theory on a hierarchy of needs allows individuals (persons or businesses) to approach projects with deliberate recognition of motivations; his works allow for careful prioritization and planning of resource allocation &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#maslow_1943_2000&quot;&gt;(Maslow, 1943; Matias et al., 2020; Wong et al., 2020; Casale &amp;amp; Flett, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. Luisa Maffi is associated with the coining of the term ‘biocultural diversity’ (BCD). Projects on this topic tend to have some connection to conservation efforts and have strong ties to linguistics (particularly endangered languages); according to Maffi, biological, cultural, and scientific complexity add to the various forms of diversity in life &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#terralingua_2019&quot;&gt;(Terralingua, 2019; Maffi &amp;amp; others, 2007; Maffi, 2005; Terralingua, 2020; Terralingua, 2014; Maffi &amp;amp; others, 2007; Maffi, 2005)&lt;/a&gt;. Gonçalves is a linguist specializing in multiple languages and their presence in social media like Twitter, yet manages to visually tie his findings to his appreciation of the physical environment from which the messages originate. His works seem to have cross-domain appeal; in fact, one could assert that these could have some significance to the topic of ‘biocultural diversity’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gonçalves’ works on the ranking of touristic-sites worldwide based on their attractiveness (measured with geolocated data as a proxy for human mobility), and ‘mapping world languages through microblogging platforms’ &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#BrunoGonccalves2016touristic&quot;&gt;(Bassolas et al., 2016)&lt;/a&gt;. He also worked on ‘learning Spanish dialects through Twitter’ by employing a corpus based on geographically tagged messages &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#BrunoGonccalves2013twitter&quot;&gt;(Mocanu et al., 2013; Gonçalves &amp;amp; Sánchez, 2014)&lt;/a&gt;, and exploring a global language network (as a form of ranking languages) &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#BrunoGonccalves2014links&quot;&gt;(Ronen et al., 2014)&lt;/a&gt;, were all visually fascinating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, replicating his works, with the inclusion of a creole language may be a bit difficult. Still, one may yet garner inspiration from his 2017 paper on ‘Semantic homophily in online communication’ employing confirmation from Twitter &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#BrunoGonccalves2017semantic&quot;&gt;(Šćepanović et al., 2017)&lt;/a&gt;; his discussion of ‘value homophily’ as it relates to one’s ‘internal states’ that might influence future behavior, can be adapted to discuss the similarities yet differences between the islands that observe mutually intelligible creoles (like the Antillean creole spoken among the inhabitants of Dominica and Saint Lucia). Based on the works of Wang, Abeillé, Gonçalves, and even Maffi, one may ponder the possibility of leveraging existing tree-banks and focusing on POS tagging and sentiment analysis, for languages that do not have an extensively established digital presence or corpora.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bearing this in mind, it may also be useful to leverage the natural annotation provided by crowdsourced online dictionaries related to low-resource languages, such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiwords.com/&quot;&gt;Wiwords&lt;/a&gt;. For example, this could actively/continuously address word sense disambiguation issues that arise from the text analysis of the Saint Lucian Kwéyòl’s online social media chatter on various platforms, like Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, etc. By improving word sense disambiguation issues with the creole language, one may be better able to evaluate the language’s vitality via assessing the frequency of its usage in social media posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, avocado translates to zabòka&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webonary.org/kweyol/gfdb5d87c-f3e9-49f6-a80e-f9dddeb2e358/&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; in the official Saint Lucian Kwéyòl dictionary. However, on Instagram&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/explore/tags/zaboca/?hl=en&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;, Facebook&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/embracedominica/posts/known-locally-as-pear-or-zaboca-the-avocado-is-a-flowering-plant-native-to-mexic/1796956037194101/&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;, and Twitter&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/itzbuellzfool/status/1312498381860659200&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt; (and even a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Under-Zaboca-Tree-Glynis-Guevara/dp/1771333294&quot;&gt;book on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, refers to the same item using the spelling ‘zaboca’, ‘zabocca’ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/BarbadosCulinaryJourney/photos/avocado-or-zabocca-originally-found-in-the-deep-forests-of-south-america-and-tak/1037910523023415/g&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/5204/05cfd523532ee8a3d9470bbeb200c17af9cc.pdf&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;, and ‘zaboka’&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lylythervil/status/998975906738733058&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;. Yet, the crowdsourced online dictionary Wiwords notes the same item with the spelling ‘zaboca’&lt;a href=&quot;http://wiwords.com/word/zaboca&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt; and includes pictures for clarification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cursory search of Twitter revealed that the ‘zaboca’ spelling was just about as common as ‘ zaboka’,  yet the accented spelling, ‘zabòka’, was not present. One could say that Wiwords did indeed reflect the term’s typical informal (social media) form. While Wiwords does not list the official spelling or all other alternative spellings, it does assist with understanding instances of the presence or absence of diacritical marks and providing needed context to improving the word sense disambiguation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of creole data, I currently have access to traditional folk songs &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#joseph_songs_2020&quot;&gt;(Joseph, 2020; Yannucci, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;, discourses &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#weekes2014bodies&quot;&gt;(Weekes, 2014; Frank, 1990)&lt;/a&gt;, and stories &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#sil_readingbook_1989&quot;&gt;(SIL, 1989)&lt;/a&gt;. Digital versions of a bible (new testament) &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#SLUnewtestament_1999&quot;&gt;(“Tèstèman nèf-la: Épi an posyòn an liv samz-la,” 1999; “Saint Lucian Creole French New Testament,” 2004; “Glory (Saint Lucian Creole French),” 2020)&lt;/a&gt;, a few documents from the government such as the Saint Lucian national anthem &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#anthem_2016&quot;&gt;(“Kwéyòl National Anthem approved,” 2016)&lt;/a&gt; and Kwéyòl public service announcements &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#louisy_govt_2004&quot;&gt;(Louisy, 2004; SLU, 2020)&lt;/a&gt; are also accessible. Public social media data are also useful, particularly the postings by verified Saint Lucian Kwéyòl writers &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#kweyol_fb_joseph&quot;&gt;(Joseph, 2020; Joseph, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. In 1993 a document entitled “Dances and Songs from a Caribbean Island” was created and in 1996 one named “Select Bibliography of the Literature of the English-speaking West Indies” was also created; if the documents above are insufficient, I will consult these two anthological works for additional data &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#islandsongs_1993&quot;&gt;(“Musical Traditions of St. Lucia, West Indies,” 1993; Carnegie, 1996)&lt;/a&gt; There are few books but they are mostly physical documents (I need to finish looking into their digital versions).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have access to a partially labeled XML version of the Saint Lucian Kwéyòl dictionary dataset (but no sentiment data) (missing reference). There are numerical indicators to signify the differences between homonyms, and according to the dictionary’s creator&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘the set of parts of speech, or word classes, used in this dictionary is as
follows: N (noun), PRO (pronoun), ADJ (adjective), ART (article), V (verb),
ADV (adverb), PREP (preposition), CONJ (conjunction), and INTERJ
(interjection). These are only broad categories. In a more complete
a grammatical description of Kwéyòl, these broad categories could and should be further broken down into subcategories’&lt;/em&gt; (missing reference).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of technology and tools, I have found Python to be very useful. Please note that Github has proven useful in allowing one to explore various topics through shared community efforts; there are Universal Dependencies of various languages like Tamil, Spanish, and French, however, there are creole ones as of yet. I am currently reviewing a few of Abeillé’s works, including “The Universal Dependency version of the French Treebank” &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#abeille2003building&quot;&gt;(Abeillé et al., 2003)&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/UniversalDependencies/UD_French-FTB&quot;&gt;‘UD_French-FTB’&lt;/a&gt;, and the presentation on &lt;a href=&quot;https://syntaxfest.github.io/syntaxfest19/slides/slides_91.pdf&quot;&gt;‘Deep Universal Dependencies’&lt;/a&gt;, created by Daniel Zeman. It is stated to be a ‘treebank of sentences from the newspaper Le Monde, initially manually annotated with morphological information and phrase-structure and then converted to the Universal Dependencies annotation scheme’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, Google Colab has proven to be an interesting environment that facilitates document and code sharing and commenting, and version control. One also has access to a GPU, which tends to be useful for &lt;a href=&quot;https://towardsdatascience.com/superpower-your-google-colab-720d54dd6a06&quot;&gt;deep learning and some parallelizable data science algorithms&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally, there is access to a research &lt;a href=&quot;https://aihub.cloud.google.com/u/0/&quot;&gt;‘Seedbank’&lt;/a&gt; where Google has an entire repository of deep learning and data science proof of concepts hosted. This includes code concerning &lt;a href=&quot;https://aihub.cloud.google.com/p/products%2F024b89fd-9bc8-4c24-b8a8-e347479f3270&quot;&gt;‘Neural Translation with Attention’&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://aihub.cloud.google.com/u/0/p/products%2F760da8f1-439f-44cb-af51-3680987b9786&quot;&gt;‘Tensor2Tensor: Translate from English to German with a pre-trained model’&lt;/a&gt;, and even a &lt;a href=&quot;https://aihub.cloud.google.com/u/0/p/products%2Fbd3b0d5c-e4d0-450a-890f-e7b4027e8d09&quot;&gt;‘Multilingual Language Model Dataset’s&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Python is so useful, I am, however, also currently reviewing the treebank construction feature and pre-trained annotation models offered by ‘UDPipe Natural Language Processing - Text Annotation’. According to its &lt;a href=&quot;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/udpipe/vignettes/udpipe-annotation.html&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, the most relevant features would be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Allowing R users simple access in order to easily tokenize, tag, lemmatize or perform dependency parsing on text in any language&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘Provide easy access to pre-trained annotation models’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Allow R users to easily construct your own annotation model based on data in CONLL-U format as provided in more than 100 treebanks available at https://universaldependencies.org&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#wijffels_2020&quot;&gt;(Wijffels, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, improving the status of an endangered language through careful application of the technology would also exemplify the core principles of biocultural diversity. Overall, this investigation has implications across various domains including data science, computational linguistics, digital humanities, and biocultural diversity. Bearing this in mind, this will open up the publication opportunities for the various aspects of this dissertation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please note:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I do know I need to create a visual to better summarize the core concepts of the framework&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I do know I need to clean up my overall work to fit into the following format:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Statement of Research Questions or Hypothesis&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Literature Review&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Theoretical or Conceptual Model&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Data and Analytic Method&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I need to add the references mentioned above&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;brief-literature-review&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brief literature review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;setting&quot;&gt;Setting&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the extended period of social disruption caused by the 2020 SARS-CoV-2 pandemic, many gained a newfound appreciation for Maslow’s theory on a hierarchy of needs &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#maslow_1943_2000&quot;&gt;(Maslow, 1943; Matias et al., 2020; Wong et al., 2020; Casale &amp;amp; Flett, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. Global citizens reflected on the loss of lives, the loss of a sense of justice, the loss of financial stability, the subsequent loss of housing stability, and an overall sense of the loss of social normalcy; concerns grew for the increasing severity and frequency of natural disasters impacting all forms of life within our complex global socio-ecological environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a time of crisis, Maslow’s theory can aid in visualizing and prioritizing scarce resources according to one’s needs, and data science can be used to explore, assess, and address those needs; data science can serve as a tool of establishing a degree of certainty, in uncertain times. Often, obtaining our needs is intrinsically linked to the ease with which we can communicate - our ability to understand and to be understood. To effectively facilitate the communication of various societal needs, data science can be employed as a means of monitoring and maintaining the standards of numerous fields through the careful study of an environment’s linguistics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consideration of the ease with which one is able to communicate with others can impact their need for belonging. Language allows messages to be conveyed. The ability to understand and to be understood is crucial in times of great uncertainty and the constant fear of possible emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;introduction-to-language-study-creole&quot;&gt;Introduction to language study: creole&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1863, August Schleicher, the German linguist, discussed languages as &lt;em&gt;natural organisms that come into being, develop, age, and die according to laws that are quite independent of man’s will&lt;/em&gt; (cited by Arens 1969:259). This perception of language is contrary to recent the modern view that it is one’s set of communication habits that have principally been defined by their social experience, led by an innate sense to decipher and learn the language practices of others. However, despite having a few members of the “native speaking generation” left, often communities lack the implementation of structures dedicated to the retention of language. Therefore, successive generations may require resources that express the necessity of the language as well as its desirability to ensure its continuance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mohan is of the view that living languages can die before “the last trace of memory has vanished”; that these languages may be experiencing a feigned guise of life through its observation of “sympathetic post-users from outside its system” (1979:42). To further quote Mohan, an obsolescent language:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;is actually dead before its forms have totally disappeared, in two different senses. A small part of the non-native speaking generation has preserved dead tokens of the language. Also, the time gap between the age of the youngest native speaker and the latest possible age of language acquisition, in infancy, shows the language dead at its source, but with a now finite community of native speakers continuing, like the earlier light of a dead star, to travel its original course and give an illusion picture of vitality. (313)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bad format and sourcing for this paragraph. Need to clean this up and add the references mentioned in the paragraphs above. Some chunks were copied and pasted so I would not forget to include them; how do you quote someone who quoted an original writer, when you have no access to the original document??? Plus I am unsure if &lt;a href=&quot;https://enacademic.com/dic.nsf/enwiki/53856&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; is a proper academic website that I can quote from&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, Sasse (2001) lists ten changes occurring during language obsolescence;  several of which bear similarities to those described by Campbell &amp;amp; Muntzel (1989) and Palosaari &amp;amp; Campbell (2011), namely: &lt;em&gt;loss of phonological distinctions, regularization of morphophonemics, loss of function words, analyticity, loss of morphology, loss of syntactic complexity, agrammatism, phonological and grammatical variability, reduction of vocabulary, and an increase in polysemy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evaluating and creating structures is crucial for the preservation and promotion of endangered languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bad format and sourcing for the above paragraph. Need to clean this up and add the references mentioned above.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Perhaps could include and expand on the definition and application of systems dynamic model and other models here…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;perceptions-of-saint-lucian-kwéyòl&quot;&gt;Perceptions of Saint Lucian Kwéyòl&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Caribbean has had a complicated past of trade, colonization, slavery, indentured labor, and more recently voluntary immigration. This, therefore, leads to a present setting of an actively multilingual environment that is ever-changing due to evolving political and legal policies (such as Citizenship by Investment (CIP) &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#bayat_2020&quot;&gt;(Bayat &amp;amp; El Hachem, 2020; GIS, 2017; CIP, 2020; Capital, 2020; Harvey, 2020; Visa, 2016)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;English is the main language spoken (a prestige language) in Saint Lucia, however, Saint Lucian Kwéyòl (Antillean Creole/ Patios/ Patwa) is the heritage language of the island; there are several other languages officially taught (French and Spanish) and generally spoken in the close-knit Caribbean (such as Dutch, Portuguese, Hindi, Arabic, and even Japanese, Mandarin and increasingly Russian) &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#hillman2009understanding&quot;&gt;(Hillman &amp;amp; D’Agostino, 2009; “Saint Lucia,” n.d.; Kobayashi, 2020; Nesheim, 2020; CBF, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;.
Frank’s 2008 work on “Sources of St. Lucian Creole Vocabulary” suggested that about 83.8 % -95.0 % words he came across had French origins,  about 2.8 % to 3.2 % were English, .6 % to .7 % were Amerindian-based, and about .5 % to .6 % were African-based; .4 %  were Indian language-based (Tamil or Hindi), and .1 % was Spanish/Portuguese-based. A notable 11.8 % of lexical items had etymological sources could not be precisely determined &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#frank2007sources&quot;&gt;(Frank, 2007)&lt;/a&gt;; addressing this etymological mystery might be an apt challenge for natural language processing and machine translation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Douglas Midgett’s work on the anthropological linguistics of Saint Lucia, the island’s inhabitants have struggled in their appreciation of its heritage language &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#midgett1970bilingualism&quot;&gt;(Midgett, 1970)&lt;/a&gt;. Historically there were negative connotations with Saint Lucian Kwéyòl (Antillean Creole/Patios), and upon emancipation, there was intense enmity among English and Creole in the newly free community; the use was negatively equated “with all that is backward, rural, Negro, and unsophisticated” &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#midgett1970bilingualism&quot;&gt;(Midgett, 1970)&lt;/a&gt;. Midgett highlighted that the formal teaching of Patois would be viewed as “unjustifiable and in any case, would never be tolerated by even its most ardent user”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, Midgett did, however, acknowledge that “English is the language of all national institutions… Patois is the language of folk institutions”; therefore, it is not surprising that some are still encouraged to learn and converse in English, rather than in Saint Lucian Kwéyòl, to appear more professional or polished &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#oas_2018&quot;&gt;(OAS, 2018)&lt;/a&gt;. At the time, he noted that most people agreed that increased proficiency in spoken and written English (or French) would be an educational must, however, writers and other academics and actual educators had differing views; the former group believed that the use of creole in schools could aid with recognizing English as a second language, whereas educators adamantly argued against any use of Creoles in the schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He believed that the use of Patois in the schools interchangeably with less formal, more colloquial English would aid in establishing English in the minds of students as a functional Patois equivalent. He suggested that as long as educational institutions reinforce the conventional traditional opinion of separating the two languages, the campaign for English literacy and spoken usage will not have widespread effectiveness. Midgett, however, underestimated how pervasive the English language would be; in fact, it is the creole language that currently lacks proper literacy among the public &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#midgett1970bilingualism&quot;&gt;(Midgett, 1970)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Need to clean this up and add the references mentioned above; might need to include a clear explanation of what is creole and how it differs from a pidgin.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, as of May 1970, Midgett suggested that the vitality of the language was still strong; he stated that “there still exists a situation in which virtually every native-born St. Lucian can speak Patois” &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#midgett1970bilingualism&quot;&gt;(Midgett, 1970)&lt;/a&gt;. This language still appears to be surviving today, albeit under an inconclusive status; despite the recent surge in appeal due to governmental and pop culture support, the lingering lack of definitive vitality data could inadvertently permit an unabated decline &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#marmion2014community&quot;&gt;(Marmion et al., 2014; Midgett, 1970; Kabir, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1998, Frank explored and even expanded the written form of the creole language in Saint Lucia while attempting to effectively translate an English bible into the local language. Upon concluding his tasks he remarked that the bible would indirectly boost creole literacy through the motivational passages of the bible:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘… for all practical purposes Creole remains an unwritten language for the majority of the population, which remains unaware of the books published in Creole. Attempts to teach Creole literacy have not met with much success because of lack of interest. Motivation is the most important factor in the success of any literacy program, and having something people want to read is the most important motivating factor’&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#frank1998lexical&quot;&gt;(Frank &amp;amp; Frank, 1998)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Need to clean this up. Perhaps spend some more time rewording this to use less of the direct quotes, and shorten this paper.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;issues-with-natural-annotation-challenges-and-solutions-for-annotating-saint-lucian-kwéyòl&quot;&gt;Issues with natural annotation (Challenges and Solutions for Annotating Saint Lucian Kwéyòl)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As noted before, Saint Lucian Kwéyòl is highly influenced by ‘imported vocabulary’; the majority of which is French followed by English, however, it should be noted that the third largest portion of the language has definitive etymological sources. These words may constitute out-of-vocabulary (OOV) regarding a standard English or French treebank and could result in difficulties for using English-trained tools on Saint Lucian Kwéyòl &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#Wang2020FromGT&quot;&gt;(Wang et al., 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. Moreover, in terms of topic prominence, this language is regarded as a ‘Subject-Predicate-Object’ ordered language &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#frank1992clause&quot;&gt;(Frank, 1992)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I do want to include a bit of discussion about the creole sentence structure, clauses, and the lingering impact of languages such as French, English, and Spanish.&lt;/em&gt; This may involve the discussion of the common Subject+Verb+Object (SVO) structure, versus the Subject+Object+Verb (SOV), etc. This sentence structure typically notes a noun phrase before a verb phrase (or a Subject+Predicate(+Object) combination at the clause level), however, structures of creoles sentences may not be so simple.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I also might want to mention the possible issues with transliteration when dealing with the etymology of words that non-Latin based characters that still somewhat contribute to the creole vocabulary; this mostly would focus on target languages of Tamil and Hindi&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#frank2007sources&quot;&gt;(Frank, 2007)&lt;/a&gt;. Also, academics have suggested that dispute their obvious connection, there is not always singular and direct relationships between Kwéyòl and French words (missing reference). Frank highlighted that there are many cases where a Kwéyòl noun originates from a French preposition and/or article plus noun; for example, Kwéyòl’s “lavi” is related to French’s ‘la vie’, “nanj” to ‘un ange’, “zòdi”  to ‘les ordures’ and “dlo” to ‘de l’eau’ (missing reference).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also important to note that additional natural language processing issues may arise when manipulating the creole language, or attempting to adapt it to a digital environment such as a comprehensive online-dictionary. Public contributors may understand the language in terms of speaking it, however, they may not be the best teachers; that is to say that contributors may not always be clear in their explanations or contributions. Overall, straying from official spellings of words can contribute to data entry issues. For example, one can observe the accents used with “chofé” - “to heat up”,  and “chofè” - a “driver” (missing reference). These words without context and accents would be very difficult to decipher. Persons inaccurately applying accents, or unable to access the necessary unique characters were required (diacritics) for formal grammar can present problems in documenting the language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As noted by Frank, some dictionary entries can present as variants of keywords, and debates can arise concerning which word should be the dominant standard form, and which should be the variant form (missing reference). For example, the Saint Lucian Kwéyòl dictionary notes &lt;em&gt;jòdi&lt;/em&gt; as the standard form of the adverb ‘today’, and &lt;em&gt;hòdi&lt;/em&gt; as the variant form (missing reference). Frank is said to address the issue of determining the Kwéyòl form of words by noting the ‘commonly-used form that is closest to the French origin (or, in some cases, origin from another source) was chosen for a full entry, and other forms less directly related to the form of the etymological source were said to be the variants’ (missing reference).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;problems-of-polysemy-in-saint-lucian-kwéyòl&quot;&gt;Problems of polysemy in Saint Lucian Kwéyòl&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue with dictionary compilation in this region may deal with the overlap of meanings attributed to certain words. Polysemy is a common occurrence in the low-resource language of Saint Lucian Kwéyòl &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#Mayeux2019RethinkingD&quot;&gt;(Mayeux, 2019; Cope &amp;amp; Schafer, 2017)&lt;/a&gt;. An indication of a polysemous verb in English is one that corresponds to different verbs when translated into other languages. For example, one can review the English word for ‘ask’ (for information) and ‘ask’ (for action). This can be interpreted as one word “vragen” in Dutch, however, the majority of other languages use different words for each English interpretation like “fragen” and “bitten” in German, “preguntar” and “pedir” in Spanish, and “fråg” and “bedja” in Swedish, respectively &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#kreidler1998introducing&quot;&gt;(Kreidler, 1998; Padó &amp;amp; Lapata, 2005)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Saint Lucian Kwéyòl,  this can be seen where the term “mwen” can signify the pronouns for ‘I, me, my, or mine’; the term “asou” is a preposition that can mean ‘on, on top of, atop, upon’, ‘ off, off of, from’, ‘toward’ or ‘about, concerning’ (missing reference). The term “vè” can mean ‘glass’, ‘green’, or ‘worm’; the creole word ‘kay’ can indicate future tense as well as ‘house/, building’, ‘scale’ (appearing on the skin), and ‘reef’. “Lè” can mean ‘room’, ‘space’,  and ‘time/ hour’ (including discussions of ‘when’ and ‘if’). “Tan” can represent nouns of ‘time’, ‘weather’, and an adjective indicating a ‘vague amount of something’. As a noun, “kwi” could represent the act of ‘crying/ screaming/ shouting’, as well as refer to a ‘calabash bowl or plate’; as an adjective, it could indicate the state of being ‘raw’ (missing reference).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that there may need to be considerations for word sense disambiguation issues that arise from the intermingling of an almost identical creole from the neighboring island of Dominica. Both islands appear to sound similar and some words are indeed the same, but the written form appears to vary slightly. This might be due to the liberties taken by the different authors of their dictionaries; Frank highlighted his penchant for leaning on French when considering the spelling of words (missing reference). Overall, it appears that while both countries agree that the Creole writing system is phonemically-based (which can make it easier to learn than English to a certain extent) (missing reference), there are slight differences in diacritic use and placement and spelling between countries; this issue can then permeate and linger in both creole speaking countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is said that the shared creole alphabet writing system arose out of two creole ethnography workshops held in St. Lucia in January 1981 and September in 1982; this was developed through the efforts of researchers at “the University of the West Indies (U.W.I.), The Université Antilles – Guyane groups from St. Lucia (MOKWÉYÓL), Dominica (K.E.K.) and the Groupé d’Etude et de Recherche en Espace, Creolophone (GEREC) from Martinique and Guadeloupe” &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#creoleconference1980s&quot;&gt;(of Dominica, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. Dominicans write ‘goodnight’ as &lt;em&gt;‘bon swé’&lt;/em&gt;, whereas Saint Lucians write &lt;em&gt;‘bonswè’&lt;/em&gt; (missing reference). Additionally, take a look at the days of the week; the words for Sunday, Monday, Tuesday, and Saturday are the same, yet, Wednesday, Thursday, and Friday are different. Dominicans write Wednesday as &lt;em&gt;Mèkwédi&lt;/em&gt; whereas Saint Lucians write it as &lt;em&gt;Mékwédi&lt;/em&gt;, and Dominicans write Thursday as &lt;em&gt;Jèdi&lt;/em&gt; whereas Saint Lucians write it as &lt;em&gt;Jédi&lt;/em&gt;; the accent placement is different (missing reference). Dominicans write Friday as &lt;em&gt;Vanwédi&lt;/em&gt; whereas Saint Lucians write it as &lt;em&gt;Vandwédi&lt;/em&gt;; here, while the accent is the same, the Saint Lucians appear to include an additional ‘d’, reminiscent of the original French [&amp;lt; Fr. &lt;em&gt;vendredi&lt;/em&gt;] (according to Frank (missing reference)).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the word, “Creole” can be viewed as a contested, polysemous term in the English language &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#cope2017creole&quot;&gt;(Cope &amp;amp; Schafer, 2017)&lt;/a&gt;. The term has been employed at varied periods and in several regions to distinguish a wide range of entities; this includes ‘identities, ‘languages, peoples, ethnicities, racial heritages, and cultural artifacts’ &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#cope2017creole&quot;&gt;(Cope &amp;amp; Schafer, 2017)&lt;/a&gt;. As an adjective, Creole was applied as an indicator of higher status bestowed upon Louisiana-born slaves to distinguish them from those born in Africa &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#cope2017creole&quot;&gt;(Cope &amp;amp; Schafer, 2017; Brasseaux, 2005)&lt;/a&gt;. It was also used as a noun to designate local birth in Louisiana, regardless of racial heritage; later Americans used creole when referring to people of Spanish or French descent, yet it has often been conflated with the term “Cajan” (which described French colonists that settled in Canada’s Acadia region, then migrated to Louisiana). In fact, for some time, there was also a misconception that the term only referred to whites born in Louisiana &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#brasseaux2005french&quot;&gt;(Brasseaux, 2005)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, Creole primarily refers to one’s linguistic heritage as the main source of their ethnic identity (‘often French culture and a unique Franco-linguistic dialect’) &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#cope2017creole&quot;&gt;(Cope &amp;amp; Schafer, 2017)&lt;/a&gt;. This is particularly true of those of mixed or ancestry foreign to the location &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#definecreole2020&quot;&gt;(“Creole peoples,” 2020; Cope &amp;amp; Schafer, 2017)&lt;/a&gt;. In the Caribbean, the terms ‘Creole’, ‘Kreyol’, ‘Kweyol’, or Kwéyòl can also indicate the regional creole languages such as Antillean Creole (Dominican and Saint Lucian Kwéyòl), Haitian Creole, and Jamaican Creole &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#definecreole2020&quot;&gt;(“Creole peoples,” 2020; “Antillean Creole,” 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. While most are recognized as french based, there is an increasing academic argument to officially recognize unique variants of English based creoles (instead of simply viewing them as the poor application of English) &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#irvine2020st&quot;&gt;(Irvine, 2020; Irvine, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polysemy may indeed present an issue when attempting to study a language or dialects, however, these complications are in fact, often viewed positively in the cultures where creole is spoken; they are often the premise and appeal of much literature in these creole languages. Calypso, and most other endemic forms of music, may celebrate this ability to utilize words or phrases bearing double meanings to indirectly discuss topics that are often crude &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#stephens2013imagining&quot;&gt;(Stephens, 2013)&lt;/a&gt;. Philips suggested that Calypsos can engage this method via ‘lamina lyrics’. &lt;em&gt;Much like an onion, these Calypsos have a number of different levels of meaning, concealed one underneath the other. Achieving this phenomenon, Calypsonians use frames and masks that manifest in Calypsos as a metaphor, metonym, polysemy, irony, and satire&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#phillips2006recognising&quot;&gt;(Phillips, 2006)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;consideration-of-digital-tools-for-language-analysis-rejuvenation-and-conservation&quot;&gt;Consideration of digital tools for language analysis, rejuvenation, and conservation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Need to discuss treebanks, universal dependencies, dependency parsing performance, POS tagging accuracy, etc.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Need to discuss sentiment analysis, etc.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current LIWC dictionary is composed of 5,690 words and word stems. Therefore, this means that some words are not accounted for, and to a broader extent translation does not always indicate sentiment; concepts such as sarcasm, irony, and slang, polysemy, and captionyms can be problematic if the context is not adequately communicated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Need to discuss online dictionaries as these serve as important resources to low-resource languages (might need to add something more to the details below after noting the pros and cons of their existence).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Online dictionaries allow users and compilers opportunities far beyond those of traditional publishing constructions. For an endangered language, the use of such a resource becoming increasingly essential. However, the use of static online dictionaries may not be sufficient to meet the demands of language that is slowly dying. Static dictionaries with dynamic qualities may better serve the needs of cataloging an endangered language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;(this may be an area that I want to investigate/write a paper on, and possibly create a future tool to address this issue).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Online dictionaries benefit from using technology to update their records regularly. This not only pertains to new sections of the alphabet but “also with words of particular interest to its users at the time”. Words such as ‘LOL’ and ‘YOLO’ were online slang that were added to the Oxford English Dictionary (OED) in 2011, and 2016 respectively. The third edition of the OED appears to no longer suppress widely‑used slang terms, however, it certainly is incapable of documenting the meaning and use of every fleeting term used among small assortments of speakers within the entirety of the English‑speaking world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Urban Dictionary is the free service of an online dictionary of contemporary English slang usage; it is a “collaborative project of over 1 million definitions for over 400,000 unique headwords”. It serves as an online lexicography where public contributors explain the meanings of words and phrases not readily covered by traditional dictionaries; contributors collaborate, cooperate, and compete for meaning-making. Eventually, depending on the proliferation of use in society, official dictionaries, such as OED, may elect to officially adopt a word from such a collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The collaborative compilation of online lexicography, therefore, is known to linguistics. In fact, there is a webpage, similar to Urban Dictionary, that strategically caters to Caribbean consumers. While the region bears various peoples with differing complex histories, they do share similarities; while most of these similarities are the unfortunate result of colonialization from similar superpowers, certain words are ubiquitous due to the ease of traversing and settling in neighboring countries. Persons of these areas experience similar flora and fauna, and environmental and social phenomena that are endemic to their setting and way of life. The website, Wiwords, is a dynamic online dictionary that highlights instances of shared vocabulary, as well as allowing for contributions that are unique to certain countries in the Caribbean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should, however, be noted that the number of items tagged as Saint Lucian Kwéyòl appears to be a bit low in this particular online linguistic community. For example, there are no contributions to the Wiwords section dedicated to local quotes or sayings, when these items are quite abundant in Saint Lucian Kwéyòl. Most participation Saint Lucian tagged items appear to pertain to discussions of food, and animal and plant life. Therefore, to better preserve the creole language within Saint Lucia, utilization of this dynamic online community dictionary would be very useful to gauge the language’s vitality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Need to clean this up and add the references mentioned above.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;investigation&quot;&gt;Investigation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some works have suggested dealing with the lexical deviations inherent to creoles can be accommodated by applying the existing language (like French or English) dependency relation definitions while ensuring consistency with the annotations in other non-French or non-English Universal Dependency (UD) treebanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does appear that it would be helpful to develop a framework to improve the models for linguistics; perhaps an extendable framework that can demonstrate its application to low-resource languages such as creole.
It begs the question, how can one leverage existing tree-banks, focusing on POS and sentiment analysis, for languages that do not have an established digital presence (corpus).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, this ultimately leaves one to wonder if it is logical and possible to merge an official online static dictionary with a dynamic slang dictionary to increase overall fluency in an endangered language? Such a system would require access to an existing dictionary, as well as opportunities for dictionary contributions. The creation of an interactive dictionary may assist with reinvigorating the usage of the language through active use and contributions to this resource, but also offer opportunities to actively discuss and clarify words and concepts associated with creole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Need to clean this up and add the references mentioned above.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;implications-for-the-field-of-study-the-works-significance-and-contribution-to-the-field-of-data-science-and-cross-domain-appeal&quot;&gt;Implications for the Field of Study: The work’s significance and contribution to the field of Data Science and cross-domain appeal.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As noted above, this paper intends to focus on computational linguistic (and machine translation) skills to address societal communication difficulties, particularly when dealing with low-resource languages. Introducing a framework to natural language processing will improve computational linguistics as when as data science, as both tend to use the same or similar models and technologies. However, there are additional related fields that may benefit from introducing frameworks that ultimately improve communications; particularly in low-resource/ endangered languages. Therefore, this work can also be considered to explore the possible cross-domain approach to ethical data science projects through highlighting the similarities of skills and technologies associated with, and the possible merger of, the topics related to digital humanities and biocultural diversity. Overall, the Saint Lucian Kwéyòl/ Antillean creole can benefit from utilizing online language resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the 2020 SARS-CoV-2 pandemic, global citizens began critically assessing existing communication issues and problematic policies, and strove to create and cement beneficial policies for the future. It appeared that genuine value could be generated from studies in the areas of Digital Humanities (DH) and Biocultural Diversity (BCD), as these fields specifically focus on the intrinsic connection between societal structures and its possible harmony with their surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital Humanities can be interpreted as the intersection of computing (or digital technologies and humanities disciplines; it is regarded as the technology space where many digital humanists undertake the process of “translating texts into digital spaces and data or translating digital and quantitative information into new texts and interpretations” &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#levenberg2018research&quot;&gt;(Levenberg et al., 2018)&lt;/a&gt;. The field of digital humanities is quite diverse, and flexible, meaning that skills acquired can be applied to various areas. For example, an understanding and appreciation of linguistics is often helpful when working in this field; a digital humanities task related to linguistic analysis and marketing could entail an analysis of YouTube Play comments to aid in answering a question about targeted audiences  &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#levenberg2018research&quot;&gt;(Levenberg et al., 2018)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ability to reliably collect and manipulate a large set of texts is crucial; one may employ computational techniques from “natural language processing, corpus linguistics, distant reading, or broad
reading”  &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#levenberg2018research&quot;&gt;(Levenberg et al., 2018)&lt;/a&gt;. These techniques assist with data processing; this can encompass data aggregation and analysis of large sets of structured or unstructured texts  &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#levenberg2018research&quot;&gt;(Levenberg et al., 2018)&lt;/a&gt;. Depending on the purposes of
their research, it is said that different disciplinary approaches use distinct sets of algorithmic or programmatic approaches to interpreting the contents of texts  &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#levenberg2018research&quot;&gt;(Levenberg et al., 2018)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital humanities can be the strategic and systematic implementation and utilization of digital resources on the study of the humanities and further analysis of their application. For example, this can take the form of works in archeology. Undertakings can produce an intricate reconstruction of the social and environmental history of various areas of a bygone era (like developing “Patterns of Etruscan Urbanism” &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#stoddart2020patterns&quot;&gt;(Stoddart et al., 2020)&lt;/a&gt;); this area is particularly useful when attempting to process historical documents related to time data &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#ortman2019new&quot;&gt;(Ortman, 2019)&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally, these skills can be useful in recreating documents  &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#ortman2019new&quot;&gt;(Ortman, 2019)&lt;/a&gt;, catalog images &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#DH_Art_label_Delgado&quot;&gt;(Ziegler Delgado, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;, using Computer Vision &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#DH_pattern_recognition_Cornia&quot;&gt;(Cornia et al., 2020)&lt;/a&gt;, and using various forms of machine translation to handle text processing &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#DH_LIWC_2020Ye_Boot&quot;&gt;(Ye &amp;amp; Boot, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Need to expand this area a bit; may need more sources.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Mattmann’s “vision for data science” he suggested that “for the specialism to emerge and grow, data scientists will have to overcome barriers that are common to multidisciplinary research” &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#mattmann2013vision&quot;&gt;(Mattmann, 2013)&lt;/a&gt;. Luisa Maffi was the co-founder and director of Terralingua and a pioneer in the Biocultural Diversity domain of research &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#terralingua_2019&quot;&gt;(Terralingua, 2019; Terralingua, 2020; Terralingua, 2014; Maffi &amp;amp; others, 2007; Maffi, 2005)&lt;/a&gt;. She revealed the interrelated (and possibly coevolved) nature of the diversity of all forms of life within a complex socio-ecological adaptive system. BCD projects tend to have some connection to conservation efforts, and have strong ties to linguistics; according to Maffi, biological, cultural, and scientific complexity add to the various forms of diversity in life &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#terralingua_2019&quot;&gt;(Terralingua, 2019; Bates et al., 2020; Buckley, 2020; Corlett et al., 2020; Maffi &amp;amp; others, 2007; Maffi, 2005)&lt;/a&gt;. BCD has been regarded as an evolving perspective for examining the interconnection of living beings and their environments, particularly regarding conservation efforts &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#myers2000biodiversity&quot;&gt;(Myers et al., 2000)&lt;/a&gt;; one source regards it as highlighting the “interrelatedness between people and their natural environment” &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#buizer2016governing&quot;&gt;(Buizer et al., 2016)&lt;/a&gt;. Maffi has dedicated much of her work to linguistics &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#maffi2005linguistic&quot;&gt;(Maffi, 2005)&lt;/a&gt;, particularly the preserving and reinvigorating endangered languages &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#maffi2002endangered&quot;&gt;(Maffi, 2002; Maffi, 2003)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While BCD adaptable to every environment, it is very apt for positive projects in rural areas or the countryside communities (with limited infrastructure) and even indigenous communities  &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#terralingua_2019&quot;&gt;(Terralingua, 2019; Terralingua, 2020; Terralingua, 2014; Maffi &amp;amp; others, 2007; Maffi, 2005)&lt;/a&gt;. Often these communities highly value their environment as it sustains them. For example, Brazil is a country with vast natural resources, and it is home to various indigenous communities (with many unique languages).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one Brazilian study, the thoughtful application of BCD actions aided in counteracting adverse social outcomes where government interference in local nature governance occurred &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#mooij_conserving2019&quot;&gt;(Mooij et al., 2019)&lt;/a&gt;. This work paired BCD with a Practice-Based Approach (PBA) to reduce miscommunication or inaction in the community–government interactions; this was an effort to ensure that the essence of typical, or daily, issues between local communities and ruling governments was not lost when those officials communicated the community’s financial aid concerns to domestic and international audiences. To create a more complete picture of human-nature interaction, and a better understanding of the efficacy and acceptance of conservation interventions, locals were able to express their basic practices relating to the local environment (such as hunting preferences), and they were able to receive advice and resources for sustainable practices and livelihoods. The PBA approach facilitated subjects mixing “external plans with their own logic and respond to outsiders’ plans according to their own logic”; thus, allowing for increased communication and contemplation of community issues and needs. Prudent reflection of BCD was said to have aided in detecting (non-)compliant behavior “that would have otherwise likely gone unnoticed” &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#mooij_conserving2019&quot;&gt;(Mooij et al., 2019)&lt;/a&gt;. Therefore, BCD broad applications in the community–government interaction, and can aid in the careful development of communities that require extensive development resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the successes noted in Brazil, BCD projects may facilitate helpful developments in other countries, including small island nations &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#simbiak2019current&quot;&gt;(Simbiak et al., 2019)&lt;/a&gt;. Island countries such as Saint Lucia, in the Caribbean, has a local heritage language of Saint Lucian Kwéyòl language that is currently in a precarious state; no language vitality census has been attempted since the late 1940s &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#irvine2020language&quot;&gt;(Irvine, 2020; Hilaire, 2008; St-Hilaire, 2011)&lt;/a&gt;. The vocabulary of this language is intrinsically tied to objects in the natural environment.  Moreover, the country’s national cultural policy outlines even outlined a desire for Saint Lucian Caribbean people to “be aware of the importance of living in harmony with the environment” &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#unesco_2017&quot;&gt;(UNESCO, 2017; CDF, 2019)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another work acknowledged Maffi’s expression of concern for the twofold destruction of local cultures and wilderness in her early writings, yet the work highlighted the possible positive outcomes with diligent proactive efforts. It was believed that acknowledgment of BCD would facilitate a move from a “crisis narrative to a dynamic narrative” &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#elands_biocultural_2019&quot;&gt;(Elands et al., 2019)&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally, the work highlighted that BCD studies do not solely occur in rural areas; observations could be made in cities to assist with improving living standards and encouraging urban green infrastructure projects &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#elands_biocultural_2019&quot;&gt;(Elands et al., 2019)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cities are increasingly considering BCD projects as a means of rapidly ameliorating living conditions. BCD has been recognized for its ability to foster creative solutions to addressing environmental concerns, and aid in a more forceful embedding of ecology into decision-making (beyond standard ecological concepts such as Ecosystems Services (ES)) &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#buizer2016governing&quot;&gt;(Buizer et al., 2016)&lt;/a&gt;; one work insisted that researchers and policy-makers carefully consider including BCD in their “conceptual repertoire” related to environmental projects as a means of addressing the “value-orientations of all stakeholders” &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#buizer2016governing&quot;&gt;(Buizer et al., 2016)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the concept of biocultural diversity is relatively novel, there are increasing bodies of works constantly being developed, even during the 2020 SARS-CoV-2 pandemic. In fact, the pandemic appeared to be creating a unique opportunity to academically assess the interrelatedness of entities existing and enduring through the crisis; as noted earlier, there are unusual increases and decreases of interactions between humans and animals, and between humans and their environments &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#reyes-valdes_information_2020&quot;&gt;(Reyes-Valdés &amp;amp; Kantartzi, 2020; Bates et al., 2020; Buckley, 2020; Corlett et al., 2020)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, one new work during this time acknowledged the concept’s typical associations with transdisciplinary projects and the concept’s involvement with linguistic, cultural, and biological research methods in tandem with numerous statistical and mathematical approaches &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#reyes-valdes_information_2020&quot;&gt;(Reyes-Valdés &amp;amp; Kantartzi, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. However, the work then demonstrated the adaptability of the concept to biological data, by connecting transcriptome analysis bearing a biological interaction structure of a cultural group. Unique relationships were able to be identified through the lens of the cultural group component. The findings were scientifically supported, as it was said that “the specificity and specialization indices have a direct mathematical relationship with the biocultural complexity, which can be interpreted as the effective number of biocultural units equivalent to the observed data” &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#reyes-valdes_information_2020&quot;&gt;(Reyes-Valdés &amp;amp; Kantartzi, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;May need to expand this area a bit; may need more sources&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motivation is essential to change, however, to properly allocate resources, data collection and analysis should occur; based on the details above, it does appear that the areas of digital humanities and biocultural diversity do acknowledge and respect careful scientific observation and accounting of findings. Data science offers a plethora of tools in which to explore our world. However, it is often a difficult task to decipher what tools to use and when. Developing the skill and capacity to achieve this requires quite a bit of study. It also requires a significant degree of concern and compassion to dedicate resources to research that may not have a direct, immediate, or substantial financial reward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;publication-plan&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publication Plan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The publication process can be viewed as an essential part of one’s Ph.D. solidification in the field. While publications before graduation from a program can at times be difficult, it may be advantageous to attempt this as part of one’s ultimate success in the field. A publication plan allows one to market their results to places that are more apt to appreciate one’s works; this allows one to ensure that their contributions are better recognized by industry professionals. Some have viewed such publications as providing a powerful and significant indicator for ‘scientific career advancement’ &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#giebel_2019&quot;&gt;(Giebel, 2019)&lt;/a&gt;; this is particularly important in a highly competitive field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the level of a literature review I intend to complete concerning the creation of a framework and its application, I intend to publish a view papers/chapters before my final dissertation presentation (as soon as possible). My main target is a recently created publication geared towards data science papers - &lt;em&gt;Patterns&lt;/em&gt;. It is said to publish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘…original research in data science, particularly focusing on solutions to the cross-disciplinary problems that all researchers face when dealing with data, and articles about datasets, software code, algorithms, infrastructures, etc., with permanent links to these research outputs’. Patterns also promotes cross-community conversation by publishing opinion pieces and review articles&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#patterns_2020&quot;&gt;(“Patterns,” 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. Since I do intend to discuss matters related to computational linguistics, frameworks, and my dissertation’s societal value to low-resource languages (biocultural diversity topics), I do believe that this is an appropriate target. 
However, this does not mean that other publishers will be ignored; I am also open to suggestions and changes concerning this matter. I will also review the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.taaonline.net/textbook-publishers-author-guidelines&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Please see below for details on publications currently being considered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patterns:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.cell.com/patterns/home&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal of Pidgin and Creole Languages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.jbe-platform.com/content/journals/15699870&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Applied Corpus Linguistics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.journals.elsevier.com/applied-corpus-linguistics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Language &amp;amp; Communication: An Interdisciplinary Journal:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.journals.elsevier.com/language-and-communication&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lingua: An International Review of General Linguistics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.journals.elsevier.com/lingua&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ampersand: An International Journal of General and Applied Linguistics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.journals.elsevier.com/ampersand&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal of Memory and Language:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.journals.elsevier.com/journal-of-memory-and-language&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linguistics and Education: An International Research Journal:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.journals.elsevier.com/linguistics-and-education&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal of Second Language Writing: An international journal on second and foreign language writing and writing instruction:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.journals.elsevier.com/journal-of-second-language-writing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Language Sciences:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.journals.elsevier.com/language-sciences&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modern Journal of Language Teaching Methods (MJLTM):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://mjltm.org/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elsevier Journals in Linguistics and Language:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.elsevier.com/social-sciences-and-humanities/linguistics-and-language/journals&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal of Marine and Island Cultures:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://jmic.online/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability — Open Access Journal:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.mdpi.com/journal/sustainability&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;frank2007sources&quot;&gt;Frank, D. B. (2007). &lt;i&gt;Sources of St. Lucian Creole Vocabulary&lt;/i&gt;. http://www.saintluciancreole.dbfrank.net/workpapers/sources_of_vocabulary.pdf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;frank2001kweyol&quot;&gt;Crosbie, P., Frank, D., Leon, E., &amp;amp; Samuel, P. (2001). Kwéyòl dictionary. &lt;i&gt;Castries, Government of Saint Lucia, Ministry of Education&lt;/i&gt;. http://www.saintluciancreole.dbfrank.net/dictionary/KweyolDictionary.pdf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;soto2020language&quot;&gt;Soto, W. (2020). Language Identification of Guadeloupean Creole. &lt;i&gt;Groupement De Recherche Linguistique Informatique Formelle Et De Terrain (LIFT)&lt;/i&gt;, 53. https://hal.archives-ouvertes.fr/hal-03066031/document#page=59&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;kweyol_works_joseph&quot;&gt;Joseph, J. C. (2020). Kwéyòl Sent Lisi. In &lt;i&gt;Kwéyòl Sent Lisi&lt;/i&gt;. https://kweyolsentlisi.weebly.com/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;kweyol_fb_joseph&quot;&gt;Joseph, J. C. (2020). Kwéyòl Sent Lisi. In &lt;i&gt;Facebook&lt;/i&gt;. https://www.facebook.com/kweyolsentlisi/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;nivre2016universal&quot;&gt;Nivre, J., De Marneffe, M.-C., Ginter, F., Goldberg, Y., Hajic, J., Manning, C. D., McDonald, R., Petrov, S., Pyysalo, S., Silveira, N., &amp;amp; others. (2016). Universal dependencies v1: A multilingual treebank collection. &lt;i&gt;Proceedings of the Tenth International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC’16)&lt;/i&gt;, 1659–1666.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;Wang2020FromGT&quot;&gt;Wang, H., Yang, J., &amp;amp; Zhang, Y. (2020). From genesis to creole language: Transfer learning for singlish universal dependencies parsing and pos tagging. &lt;i&gt;ACM Transactions on Asian and Low-Resource Language Information Processing (TALLIP)&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;19&lt;/i&gt;, 1–29. https://doi.org/10.1145/3321128&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ferreira2019improving&quot;&gt;Ferreira, J., Gonçalo Oliveira, H., &amp;amp; Rodrigues, R. (2019). Improving NLTK for processing Portuguese. &lt;i&gt;8th Symposium on Languages, Applications and Technologies (SLATE 2019)&lt;/i&gt;. https://drops.dagstuhl.de/opus/volltexte/2019/10885/pdf/OASIcs-SLATE-2019-18.pdf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;abeille2012treebanks&quot;&gt;Abeillé, A. (2012). &lt;i&gt;Treebanks: Building and using parsed corpora&lt;/i&gt; (Vol. 20). Springer Science &amp;amp; Business Media.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;abeille2003building&quot;&gt;Abeillé, A., Clément, L., &amp;amp; Toussenel, F. (2003). Building a treebank for French. In &lt;i&gt;Treebanks&lt;/i&gt; (pp. 165–187). Springer. https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-94-010-0201-1_10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;abeille2004enriching&quot;&gt;Abeillé, A., &amp;amp; Barrier, N. (2004). Enriching a French treebank. &lt;i&gt;LREC&lt;/i&gt;. http://www.lrec-conf.org/proceedings/lrec2004/pdf/562.pdf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;maslow_1943_2000&quot;&gt;Maslow, A. H. (1943). Theory of Human Motivation : Psychological Review. In &lt;i&gt;Classics in the History of Psychology: A Theory of Human Motivation&lt;/i&gt;. Christopher D. Green of York University, Toronto, Ontario . https://psychclassics.yorku.ca/Maslow/motivation.htm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;matias2020human&quot;&gt;Matias, T., Dominski, F. H., &amp;amp; Marks, D. F. (2020). &lt;i&gt;Human needs in COVID-19 isolation&lt;/i&gt;. SAGE Publications Sage UK: London, England. https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/1359105320925149&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;wong2020healing&quot;&gt;Wong, A. H., Pacella-LaBarbara, M. L., Ray, J. M., Ranney, M. L., &amp;amp; Chang, B. P. (2020). Healing the Healer: Protecting Emergency Health Care Workers’ Mental Health During COVID-19. &lt;i&gt;Annals of Emergency Medicine&lt;/i&gt;. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7196406/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;casale2020interpersonally&quot;&gt;Casale, S., &amp;amp; Flett, G. L. (2020). Interpersonally-based fears during the COVID-19 pandemic: Reflections on the fear of missing out and the fear of not mattering constructs. &lt;i&gt;Clinical Neuropsychiatry&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;17&lt;/i&gt;(2), 88–93. https://doi.org/10.36131/CN20200211&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;terralingua_2019&quot;&gt;Terralingua. (2019). What Is Biocultural Diversity? In &lt;i&gt;Terralingua&lt;/i&gt;. Terralingua. https://terralingua.org/what-we-do/what-is-biocultural-diversity/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;maffi2007biocultural&quot;&gt;Maffi, L., &amp;amp; others. (2007). Biocultural diversity and sustainability. &lt;i&gt;The SAGE Handbook of Environment and Society. SAGE Publ., London&lt;/i&gt;, 267–277. https://doi.org/10.1002/9781118924396.wbiea1797&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;maffi2005linguistic&quot;&gt;Maffi, L. (2005). Linguistic, cultural, and biological diversity. &lt;i&gt;Annu. Rev. Anthropol.&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;34&lt;/i&gt;, 599–617. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.anthro.34.081804.120437&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;terralingua_edu_2020&quot;&gt;Terralingua. (2020). Biocultural Diversity Education. In &lt;i&gt;Terralingua&lt;/i&gt;. Terralingua. https://terralingua.org/our-projects/biocultural-diversity-education/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;terralingua_overview_2014&quot;&gt;Terralingua. (2014). Our Overview of a New Approach to Education and Curriculum Development . In &lt;i&gt;Terralingua&lt;/i&gt;. Terralingua. https://terralingua.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/BCDEI-Overview.pdf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;BrunoGonccalves2016touristic&quot;&gt;Bassolas, A., Lenormand, M., Tugores, A., Gonçalves, B., &amp;amp; Ramasco, J. J. (2016). Touristic site attractiveness seen through Twitter. &lt;i&gt;EPJ Data Science&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;5&lt;/i&gt;(1), 12.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;BrunoGonccalves2013twitter&quot;&gt;Mocanu, D., Baronchelli, A., Perra, N., Gonçalves, B., Zhang, Q., &amp;amp; Vespignani, A. (2013). The twitter of babel: Mapping world languages through microblogging platforms. &lt;i&gt;PloS One&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;8&lt;/i&gt;(4), e61981.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;BrunoGonccalves2014crowdsourcing&quot;&gt;Gonçalves, B., &amp;amp; Sánchez, D. (2014). Crowdsourcing dialect characterization through Twitter. &lt;i&gt;PloS One&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;9&lt;/i&gt;(11), e112074.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;BrunoGonccalves2014links&quot;&gt;Ronen, S., Gonçalves, B., Hu, K. Z., Vespignani, A., Pinker, S., &amp;amp; Hidalgo, C. A. (2014). Links that speak: The global language network and its association with global fame. &lt;i&gt;Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;111&lt;/i&gt;(52), E5616–E5622.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;BrunoGonccalves2017semantic&quot;&gt;Šćepanović, S., Mishkovski, I., Gonçalves, B., Nguyen, T. H., &amp;amp; Hui, P. (2017). Semantic homophily in online communication: evidence from twitter. &lt;i&gt;Online Social Networks and Media&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;2&lt;/i&gt;, 1–18.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;joseph_songs_2020&quot;&gt;Joseph, J. C. (2020). Mèt Lékòl - Kwéyòl Sent Lisi . In &lt;i&gt;10 St. Lucia La Rose Songs&lt;/i&gt;. Kwéyòl Sent Lisi . https://kweyolsentlisi.weebly.com/megravet-leacutekogravel.html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;SLU_song_yannucci_2020&quot;&gt;Yannucci, L. (2020). Fanm Ki Dou - Saint Lucia. In &lt;i&gt;Mama Lisa’s World of Children and International Culture&lt;/i&gt;. mamalisa. https://www.mamalisa.com/?t=es&amp;amp;p=4060&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;weekes2014bodies&quot;&gt;Weekes, T. (2014). &lt;i&gt;Bodies, Memories and Spirits: A Discourse on Selected Cultural Forms and Practices Of St.Lucia&lt;/i&gt;. Xlibris US. https://books.google.com/books?id=8O_wAgAAQBAJ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;frank_1990&quot;&gt;Frank, D. (1990). Six St Lucian French Creole Narrative Texts. In &lt;i&gt; Work Papers of the Summer Institute of Linguistics in St Lucia&lt;/i&gt;. SIL International. https://www.dbfrank.net/saintluciancreole/workpapers/six_texts.pdf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;sil_readingbook_1989&quot;&gt;SIL. (1989). Sé Kon Sal Fèt - A reading book in Saint Lucian Creole. In &lt;i&gt;Summer Institute of Linguistics&lt;/i&gt;. SIL International. https://tinyurl.com/yeajwe8b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;SLUnewtestament_1999&quot;&gt;Tèstèman nèf-la: Épi an posyòn an liv samz-la. (1999). In &lt;i&gt;Saint Lucian Creole French New Testament&lt;/i&gt;. The Digital Bible Society . http://downloads.dbs.org/scriptures/pdf/ACFWBT/ACFWBT.pdf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;bibleproject_2004&quot;&gt;Saint Lucian Creole French New Testament. (2004). In &lt;i&gt;The Global Bible Project&lt;/i&gt;. Wycliffe Bible Translators. https://acf.global.bible/bible/4e558d011298deae-01/2JN.intro&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;BibleSocieties_2020&quot;&gt;Glory (Saint Lucian Creole French). (2020). In &lt;i&gt;The Translation Insights and Perspectives (TIPs)&lt;/i&gt;. United Bible Societies. https://tips.translation.bible/story/glory-saint-lucian-creole-french/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;anthem_2016&quot;&gt;Kwéyòl National Anthem approved. (2016). In &lt;i&gt;Saint Lucia - Access Government&lt;/i&gt;. Office of the Prime Minister. http://www.govt.lc/news/kw-y-l-national-anthem-approved&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;louisy_govt_2004&quot;&gt;Louisy, D. C. P. L. (2004). &quot;Facing Opportunity and Taking Responsibility for Our Country’s Development&quot;. In &lt;i&gt;Throne Speech&lt;/i&gt;. Governor General Dame Calliopa Pearlette Louisy. http://caribbeanelections.com/eDocs/articles/lc/lc_Throne_Speech_2004.pdf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;sluFRC_FB_2020&quot;&gt;SLU. (2020). Folk Research Centre. In &lt;i&gt;Facebook&lt;/i&gt;. https://www.facebook.com/saintluciafolk/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;islandsongs_1993&quot;&gt;Musical Traditions of St. Lucia, West Indies. (1993). In &lt;i&gt;Dances and Songs from a Caribbean Island&lt;/i&gt;. Smithsonian/Folkways Recording. https://media.smithsonianfolkways.org/liner_notes/smithsonian_folkways/SFW40416.pdf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;creolelitlist1996&quot;&gt;Carnegie, J. R. (1996). Select Bibliography of the Literature of the English-speaking West Indies, 1989-1991. &lt;i&gt;Journal of West Indian Literature&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;7&lt;/i&gt;(1), 1–53. http://www.jstor.org/stable/23019891&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;wijffels_2020&quot;&gt;Wijffels, J. (2020). UDPipe Natural Language Processing - Text Annotation. In &lt;i&gt;UDPipe&lt;/i&gt;. https://cran.r-project.org. https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/udpipe/vignettes/udpipe-annotation.html)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;bayat_2020&quot;&gt;Bayat, S. M., &amp;amp; El Hachem, H. (2020). Saint Lucia - The Corporate Immigration Review - Edition 10 - TLR. In &lt;i&gt;The Law Reviews&lt;/i&gt;. The Law Reviews. https://thelawreviews.co.uk/edition/the-corporate-immigration-review-edition-10/1227321/st-lucia&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;gis_CIP_2017&quot;&gt;GIS. (2017). Chamber discusses CIP changes. In &lt;i&gt;Saint Lucia - Access Government&lt;/i&gt;. GIS. http://www.govt.lc/news/chamber-discusses-cip-changes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;slu_cip_2020&quot;&gt;CIP, S. L. (2020). CIP FAQs. In &lt;i&gt;Citizenship By Investment&lt;/i&gt;. cipsaintlucia.com. https://www.cipsaintlucia.com/faqs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;capital_CIP_2020&quot;&gt;Capital, A. (2020). Saint Lucia Citizenship by Investment - Your 2nd Passport. In &lt;i&gt;Arton Capital&lt;/i&gt;. Arton Capital. https://www.artoncapital.com/global-citizen-programs/saint-lucia/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;harvey_2020&quot;&gt;Harvey, L. G. (2020). Saint Lucia Citizenship By Investment Program (CIP): HLG. In &lt;i&gt;Harvey Law Group - World’s Leading Law Firm in Business Law, Investment Immigration, Citizenship-By-Investment, Residency-By-Investment&lt;/i&gt;. Harvey Law Group. https://www.harveylawcorporation.com/saint-lucia/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;investvisa_2016&quot;&gt;Visa, I. (2016). CIP Restructuring In Progress for Saint Lucia. In &lt;i&gt;Qicms- Saint Lucia CIP Restructuring | Citizenship by Investment&lt;/i&gt;. invest-visa. https://www.invest-visa.com/Post/240231/Immigration-News/CIP-Restructuring-InProgress-for-Saint-Lucia&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;hillman2009understanding&quot;&gt;Hillman, R. S., &amp;amp; D’Agostino, T. J. (2009). &lt;i&gt;Understanding the contemporary Caribbean&lt;/i&gt;. Lynne Rienner Publishers BoulderLondon. https://www.rienner.com/uploads/4a48e971d622c.pdf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;everyculture_2020&quot;&gt;Saint Lucia. In &lt;i&gt;Countries and Their Cultures&lt;/i&gt;. https://www.everyculture.com/No-Sa/Saint-Lucia.html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;kobayashi_2020&quot;&gt;Kobayashi, T. (2020). Message from the Chief Representative. In &lt;i&gt;JICA&lt;/i&gt;. https://www.jica.go.jp/stlucia/english/office/about/message.html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;nesheim_CIP_2020&quot;&gt;Nesheim, C. H. (2020). The Saint Lucia Citizenship by Investment Programme. In &lt;i&gt;Investment Migration Insider&lt;/i&gt;. Investment Migration Insider. https://www.imidaily.com/the-saint-lucia-citizenship-by-investment-programme/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;CBF_2020&quot;&gt;CBF. (2020). Saint Lucia Presents a New CIP-Project. In &lt;i&gt;Cross Border Freedom&lt;/i&gt;. CBF. https://www.crossborderfreedom.com/saint-lucia-presents-a-new-cip-project/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;midgett1970bilingualism&quot;&gt;Midgett, D. (1970). Bilingualism and linguistic change in St. Lucia. &lt;i&gt;Anthropological Linguistics&lt;/i&gt;, 158–170. https://www.jstor.org/stable/30029245?seq=1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;oas_2018&quot;&gt;OAS. (2018). Organization of American States: Democracy for peace, security, and development. In &lt;i&gt;OAS&lt;/i&gt;. Organization of Eastern Caribbean States Commission represented by St. Lucia and the Innoved Uniq, Quisqueya University, Haiti. https://www.oas.org/cotep/LibraryDetails.aspx?lang=en&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;marmion2014community&quot;&gt;Marmion, D., Obata, K., &amp;amp; Troy, J. (2014). &lt;i&gt;Community, identity, wellbeing: the report of the Second National Indigenous Languages Survey&lt;/i&gt;. Australian Institute of Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Studies Canberra.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;kabir_dennerysegment2020creolization&quot;&gt;Kabir, A. J. (2020). Creolization as balancing act in the transoceanic quadrille: Choreogenesis, incorporation, memory, market. &lt;i&gt;Atlantic Studies&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;17&lt;/i&gt;(1), 135–157.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;frank1998lexical&quot;&gt;Frank, D., &amp;amp; Frank, D. (1998). Lexical challenges in the St. Lucian Creole Bible translation project. &lt;i&gt;Twelfth Biennial Conference of the Society for Caribbean Linguistics, Castries, St. Lucia&lt;/i&gt;, 1–16. https://www.saintluciancreole.org/workpapers/lexical_challenges.pdf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;frank1992clause&quot;&gt;Frank, D. (1992). &lt;i&gt;Clause versus Sentence in St. Lucian French Creole&lt;/i&gt;. https://www.saintluciancreole.org/workpapers/clause_versus_sentence.pdf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;Mayeux2019RethinkingD&quot;&gt;Mayeux, O. (2019). &lt;i&gt;Rethinking decreolization : language contact and change in Louisiana Creole&lt;/i&gt;. https://www.repository.cam.ac.uk/handle/1810/294526&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;cope2017creole&quot;&gt;Cope, M. R., &amp;amp; Schafer, M. J. (2017). Creole: a contested, polysemous term. &lt;i&gt;Ethnic and Racial Studies&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;40&lt;/i&gt;(15), 2653–2671. https://doi.org/10.1080/01419870.2016.1267375&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;kreidler1998introducing&quot;&gt;Kreidler, C. W. (1998). &lt;i&gt;Introducing English Semantics&lt;/i&gt;. Routledge. https://books.google.com/books?id=QFiv5tDnI_sC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;pado2005cross&quot;&gt;Padó, S., &amp;amp; Lapata, M. (2005). Cross-lingual bootstrapping of semantic lexicons: The case of framenet. &lt;i&gt;AAAI&lt;/i&gt;, 1087–1092. https://www.aaai.org/Papers/AAAI/2005/AAAI05-172.pdf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;creoleconference1980s&quot;&gt;of Dominica, G. (2020). A Brief History of Kwéyòl (Patwa). In &lt;i&gt;The Division of Culture&lt;/i&gt;. gov.dm. http://divisionofculture.gov.dm/creole-languages/5-kweyol&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;brasseaux2005french&quot;&gt;Brasseaux, C. A. (2005). &lt;i&gt;French, Cajun, Creole, Houma: A Primer on Francophone Louisiana&lt;/i&gt;. LSU Press. https://books.google.com/books?id=XCBfDwAAQBAJ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;definecreole2020&quot;&gt;Creole peoples. (2020). In &lt;i&gt;Academic Dictionaries and Encyclopedias&lt;/i&gt;. Enacademic. https://enacademic.com/dic.nsf/enwiki/53856&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;defineacreole2020&quot;&gt;Antillean Creole. (2020). In &lt;i&gt;Academic Dictionaries and Encyclopedias&lt;/i&gt;. Enacademic. https://enacademic.com/dic.nsf/enwiki/614299&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;irvine2020st&quot;&gt;Irvine, M. (2020). St. Lucia Creole English and Dominica Creole English. &lt;i&gt;World Englishes&lt;/i&gt;. https://doi.org/0.1111/weng.12519&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;irvine2020language&quot;&gt;Irvine, M. (2020). &lt;i&gt;Language contact in St. Lucia: The features and origins of St. Lucia Creole English&lt;/i&gt; [PhD thesis]. ResearchSpace@ Auckland.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;stephens2013imagining&quot;&gt;Stephens, M. R. (2013). &lt;i&gt;Imagining Resistance and Solidarity in the Neoliberal Age of US Imperialism, Black Feminism, and Caribbean Diaspora&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;phillips2006recognising&quot;&gt;Phillips, E. M. (2006). Recognising the Language of Calypso as “Symbolic Action” in Resolving Conflict in the Republic of Trinidad and Tobago. &lt;i&gt;Caribbean Quarterly&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;52&lt;/i&gt;(1), 53–73.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;levenberg2018research&quot;&gt;Levenberg, L., Neilson, T., &amp;amp; Rheams, D. (2018). &lt;i&gt;Research methods for the digital humanities&lt;/i&gt;. Springer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;stoddart2020patterns&quot;&gt;Stoddart, S., Palmisano, A., Redhouse, D., Barker, G., Di Paola, G., Motta, L., Rasmussen, T., Samuels, T., &amp;amp; Witcher, R. E. (2020). Patterns of Etruscan urbanism. &lt;i&gt;Frontiers in Digital Humanities.&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;7&lt;/i&gt;, 1.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ortman2019new&quot;&gt;Ortman, S. G. (2019). A New Kind of Relevance for Archaeology. &lt;i&gt;Frontiers in Digital Humanities&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;6&lt;/i&gt;, 16. https://doi.org/10.3389/fdigh.2019.00016&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;DH_Art_label_Delgado&quot;&gt;Ziegler Delgado, M. M. (2020). THE TIME OF DIGITAL HUMANITIES: BETWEEN ART HISTORY, CULTURAL HERITAGE, GLOBAL CITIZENSHIP AND EDUCATION IN DIGITAL SKILLS. &lt;i&gt;Revista De Comunicación De La SEECI&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;52&lt;/i&gt;, 29. http://proxy-harrisburg.klnpa.org/login?url=http://search.ebscohost.com/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;amp;db=edb&amp;amp;AN=145102698&amp;amp;site=eds-live&amp;amp;scope=site&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;DH_pattern_recognition_Cornia&quot;&gt;Cornia, M., Stefanini, M., Baraldi, L., Corsini, M., &amp;amp; Cucchiara, R. (2020). Explaining digital humanities by aligning images and textual descriptions. &lt;i&gt;Pattern Recognition Letters&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;129&lt;/i&gt;, 166–172. http://proxy-harrisburg.klnpa.org/login?url=http://search.ebscohost.com/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;amp;db=edselp&amp;amp;AN=S0167865519303381&amp;amp;site=eds-live&amp;amp;scope=site&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;DH_LIWC_2020Ye_Boot&quot;&gt;Ye, Y., &amp;amp; Boot, P. (2020). &lt;i&gt;Machine Translation as an Alternative to Language-Specific Dictionaries for LIWC.&lt;/i&gt; http://proxy-harrisburg.klnpa.org/login?url=http://search.ebscohost.com/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;amp;db=edsbas&amp;amp;AN=edsbas.EE8D7521&amp;amp;site=eds-live&amp;amp;scope=site&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;mattmann2013vision&quot;&gt;Mattmann, C. A. (2013). A vision for data science. &lt;i&gt;Nature&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;493&lt;/i&gt;(7433), 473–475.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;bates_2020&quot;&gt;Bates, A. E., Primack, R. B., Moraga, P., &amp;amp; Duarte, C. M. (2020). COVID-19 pandemic and associated lockdown as a &quot;Global Human Confinement Experiment&quot; to investigate biodiversity conservation. In &lt;i&gt;Biological conservation&lt;/i&gt;. Elsevier Ltd. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7284281/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;buckley2020conservation&quot;&gt;Buckley, R. (2020). Conservation implications of COVID19: Effects via tourism and extractive industries. &lt;i&gt;Biological Conservation&lt;/i&gt;. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7247974/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;corlett2020impacts&quot;&gt;Corlett, R. T., Primack, R. B., Devictor, V., Maas, B., Goswami, V. R., Bates, A. E., Koh, L. P., Regan, T. J., Loyola, R., Pakeman, R. J., &amp;amp; others. (2020). Impacts of the coronavirus pandemic on biodiversity conservation. &lt;i&gt;Biological Conservation&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;246&lt;/i&gt;, 108571. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7139249&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;myers2000biodiversity&quot;&gt;Myers, N., Mittermeier, R. A., Mittermeier, C. G., Da Fonseca, G. A. B., &amp;amp; Kent, J. (2000). Biodiversity hotspots for conservation priorities. &lt;i&gt;Nature&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;403&lt;/i&gt;(6772), 853–858. https://www.nature.com/articles/35002501?report=reader&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;buizer2016governing&quot;&gt;Buizer, M., Elands, B., &amp;amp; Vierikko, K. (2016). Governing cities reflexively—The biocultural diversity concept as an alternative to ecosystem services. &lt;i&gt;Environmental Science &amp;amp; Policy&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;62&lt;/i&gt;, 7–13. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envsci.2016.03.003&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;maffi2002endangered&quot;&gt;Maffi, L. (2002). Endangered languages, endangered knowledge. &lt;i&gt;International Social Science Journal&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;54&lt;/i&gt;(173), 385–393. https://doi.org/abs/10.1111/1468-2451.00390&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;maffi2003business&quot;&gt;Maffi, L. (2003). The “business” of language endangerment. &lt;i&gt;Language in the Twenty-First Century&lt;/i&gt;, 67–86. https://www.google.com/books/edition/Language_in_the_21st_Century/Ca57m42RkMAC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;mooij_conserving2019&quot;&gt;Mooij, M. L. J., Dessartre Mendonça, S., &amp;amp; Arts, K. (2019). Conserving Biocultural Diversity through Community–Government Interaction: A Practice-Based Approach in a Brazilian Extractive Reserve. &lt;i&gt;Sustainability&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;11&lt;/i&gt;(1), 32. https://doi.org/10.3390/su11010032&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;simbiak2019current&quot;&gt;Simbiak, M., Supriatna, J., Walujo, E. B., &amp;amp; others. (2019). Current status of ethnobiological studies in Merauke, Papua, Indonesia: A perspective of biological-cultural diversity conservation. &lt;i&gt;Biodiversitas Journal of Biological Diversity&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;20&lt;/i&gt;(12). https://doi.org/10.1007/978-94-017-8941-7_14&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;hilaire2008postcolonialism&quot;&gt;Hilaire, A. S. (2008). Postcolonialism, identity, and the French language in St. Lucia. &lt;i&gt;New West Indian Guide/Nieuwe West-Indische Gids&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;81&lt;/i&gt;(1-2), 55–77.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;hilaire2011kweyol&quot;&gt;St-Hilaire, A. (2011). &lt;i&gt;Kwéyòl in postcolonial Saint Lucia: Globalization, language planning, and national development&lt;/i&gt; (Vol. 40). John Benjamins Publishing. https://www.jbe-platform.com/content/books/9789027284648&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;unesco_2017&quot;&gt;UNESCO. (2017). Technical and Vocational Education and Training (TVET) Policy Review: Saint Lucia. In &lt;i&gt;unesdoc.unesco.org&lt;/i&gt;. United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization. https://unesdoc.unesco.org/ark:/48223/pf0000247494&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;cdf_2019&quot;&gt;CDF. (2019). National Cultural Policy. In &lt;i&gt;Cultural Development Foundation (CDF) St. Lucia&lt;/i&gt;. Ministry of Social Transformation, Culture &amp;amp; Local Government. http://www.cdfstlucia.org/who-we-are/national-cultural-policy/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;elands_biocultural_2019&quot;&gt;Elands, B. H. M., Vierikko, K., Andersson, E., Fischer, L. K., Gonçalves, P., Haase, D., Kowarik, I., Luz, A. C., Niemelä, J., Santos-Reis, M., &amp;amp; Wiersum, K. F. (2019). Biocultural diversity: A novel concept to assess human-nature interrelations, nature conservation and stewardship in cities. &lt;i&gt;Urban Forestry &amp;amp; Urban Greening&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;40&lt;/i&gt;, 29–34. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ufug.2018.04.006&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;reyes-valdes_information_2020&quot;&gt;Reyes-Valdés, M. H., &amp;amp; Kantartzi, S. K. (2020). An information theory approach to biocultural complexity. &lt;i&gt;Scientific Reports&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;10&lt;/i&gt;(1), 7203. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-64260-5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;giebel_2019&quot;&gt;Giebel, M. (2019). Is it a good idea to publish during your PhD? Yes, but ... In &lt;i&gt;Nature News&lt;/i&gt;. Nature Publishing Group. https://socialsciences.nature.com/posts/53143-is-it-publish-or-perish-for-phd-students-it-depends&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;patterns_2020&quot;&gt;Patterns. (2020). In &lt;i&gt;journals.elsevier.com/patterns&lt;/i&gt;. Elsevier.com. https://www.journals.elsevier.com/patterns/#: :text=Patterns is a premium open,scope, regardless of original domain.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Data Sci. Discussions: Natural annotation of crowdsourced online dictionaries</title>
   <link href="http://llord1.github.io/papers/2020/11/27/wiwords"/>
   <updated>2020-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://llord1.github.io/papers/2020/11/27/wiwords</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h4 id=&quot;general-discussion-of-the-natural-annotation-of-crowdsourced-online-dictionaries&quot;&gt;General discussion of the natural annotation of crowdsourced online dictionaries&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am interested in leveraging the natural annotation provided by a crowdsourced online dictionary &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiwords.com/&quot;&gt;Wiwords&lt;/a&gt;, to actively/continuously address word sense disambiguation issues that arise from the analysis of a low-resource language (Saint Lucian Creole)’s social media (Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, etc.) text data. By improving word sense disambiguation issues with the creole language, one may be better able to assess the language’s vitality via assessing the frequency of its usage in social media posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, avocado translates to zabòka&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webonary.org/kweyol/gfdb5d87c-f3e9-49f6-a80e-f9dddeb2e358/&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; in the official Saint Lucian creole dictionary. However, on Instagram&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/explore/tags/zaboca/?hl=en&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;, Facebook&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/embracedominica/posts/known-locally-as-pear-or-zaboca-the-avocado-is-a-flowering-plant-native-to-mexic/1796956037194101/&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;, and Twitter&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/itzbuellzfool/status/1312498381860659200&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt; (and even a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Under-Zaboca-Tree-Glynis-Guevara/dp/1771333294&quot;&gt;book on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, refers to the same item using the spelling ‘zaboca’, ‘zabocca’ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/BarbadosCulinaryJourney/photos/avocado-or-zabocca-originally-found-in-the-deep-forests-of-south-america-and-tak/1037910523023415/g&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/5204/05cfd523532ee8a3d9470bbeb200c17af9cc.pdf&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;, and ‘zaboka’&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lylythervil/status/998975906738733058&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;. Yet, the crowdsourced online dictionary Wiwords notes the same item with the spelling ‘zaboca’&lt;a href=&quot;http://wiwords.com/word/zaboca&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt; and includes pictures for clarification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cursory search of Twitter revealed that the ‘zaboca’ spelling was just about as common as ‘zaboka’,  yet the accented spelling, ‘zabòka’, was not present. One could say that Wiwords did indeed reflect the term’s typical informal (social media) form. While Wiwords does not list the official spelling or all other alternative spellings, it does assist with understanding instances of the presence or absence of diacritical marks and providing needed context to improving the word sense disambiguation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;brief-literature-review&quot;&gt;Brief literature review&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Online dictionaries allow users and compilers opportunities far beyond those of traditional publishing constructions. For an endangered language, the use of such a resource becoming increasingly essential. However, the use of static online dictionaries may not be sufficient to meet the demands of language that is slowly dying. Static dictionaries with dynamic qualities may better serve the needs of cataloging an endangered language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Online dictionaries can benefit from using technology to update their records regularly. This not only pertains to new sections of the alphabet but “also with words of particular interest to its users at the time”. Words such as LOL and YOLO were online slang that were added to the Oxford English Dictionary (OED) in 2011, and 2016 respectively. The third edition of the OED appears to no longer suppress widely‑used slang terms, however, it certainly is incapable of documenting the meaning and use of every fleeting term used among small assortments of speakers within the entirety of the English‑speaking world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Urban Dictionary is the free service of an online dictionary of contemporary English slang usage; it is a “collaborative project of over 1 million definitions for over 400,000 unique headwords”. It serves as an online lexicography where public contributors explain the meanings of words and phrases not readily covered by traditional dictionaries; contributors collaborate, cooperate, and compete for meaning-making. Eventually, depending on the proliferation of use in society, official dictionaries, such as OED, may elect to officially adopt a word from such a collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The collaborative compilation of online lexicography, therefore, is known to linguistics. In fact, there is a webpage, similar to Urban Dictionary, that strategically caters to Caribbean consumers. While the region bears various peoples with differing complex histories, they do share similarities; while most of these similarities are the unfortunate result of colonialization from similar superpowers, certain words are ubiquitous due to the ease of traversing and settling in neighboring countries. Persons of these areas experience similar flora and fauna, and environmental and social phenomena that are endemic to their setting and way of life. The website, Wiwords, is a dynamic online dictionary that highlights instances of shared vocabulary, as well as allowing for contributions that are unique to certain countries in the Caribbean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the Antillean creole spoken in Saint Lucia can benefit from utilizing online language resources. A pidgin is a language variety developed by speakers in contact who share no common language; it would have limited functions of use, is linguistically simplified, and has developed its own rules and norms of usage. Creole languages are developed from pidgins, and severe as the first language of some members of a speech community, where it is used for a wide range of functions. Since creole languages seldomly achieve official status, the speakers of a fully formed creole may eventually feel compelled to conform their speech to one of the parent languages. This decreolization process typically brings about a post-creole speech continuum characterized by large scale variation and hypercorrection in the language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should, however, be noted that Saint Lucians do not appear to be highly active in this online linguistic community. For example, there are no contributions to the section outlined for local “quotes” or sayings, when these are quite abundant in the local language. Most participation from Saint Lucia pertains to discussions of food, and animal and plant life. Therefore, to better preserve the creole language within Saint Lucia,  a dynamic online community dictionary would be very useful in keeping certain words active.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also important to note that natural language processing issues may arise when manipulating the creole language, or attempting to adapt it to a digital environment such as a comprehensive online-dictionary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;issues-with-natural-annotation&quot;&gt;Issues with natural annotation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Public contributors may understand the language in terms of speaking it, however, they may not be the best teachers; that is to say that contributors may not always be clear in their explanations or contributions. Overall, straying from official spellings of words can contribute to data entry issues. For example, one can observe the accents used with “chofé” - “to heat up”,  and “chofè” - a “driver”. These words without context and accents would be very difficult to decipher. Persons inaccurately applying accents, or unable to access the necessary unique characters were required (diacritics) for formal grammar can present problems in documenting the language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;problems-of-polysemy&quot;&gt;Problems of polysemy&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue with dictionary compilation in this region may deal with the overlap of meanings attributed to certain words. Many-to one-relations between words and their meanings (e.g. homonymy and polysemy) are often not included in lists when studying this grammatical phenomenon for a unique language like creole. In addition to synonyms, frequent polysemy, the presence of homonyms and homophones and the phenomena sometimes referred to as the “false friends” of the translator.
Dictionaries recognize the distinction between polysemy and
homonymy by making a polysemous item a single dictionary entry
and making homophonous lexemes two or more separate entries; polysemous terms can though different can be derived from one basic idea, and the related terms reflect that image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polysemy is a common occurrence in the endangered language of Saint Lucian Antillean creole. An indication of a polysemous verb in English is one that corresponds to different verbs when translated into other languages. For example, one can review the English word for “ask” (for information) and “ask” (for action); this can be interpreted as one word “vragen” in Dutch, however, the majority of other languages use different words for each interpretation in English, like “fragen” and “bitten” in German, and “preguntar” and “pedir” in Spanish. In Saint Lucian creole,  this can be seen where the term “mwen” can mean “me” or “my”, or the term “asou” can mean “on” or “lean against”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that there may need to be considerations for word sense disambiguation issues that arise from the intermingling of an almost identical creole from the neighboring island of Dominica. Both islands appear to sound similar and some words are indeed the same, but the written form appears to vary slightly. This might be due to the liberties taken by the different authors of their dictionaries; Frank (missing reference) highlighted his penchant for leaning on French when considering the spelling of words. Overall, it appears that while both countries considered phonetic spelling, there are slight differences in diacritic use and placement, and spelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take for example the days of the week; the words for Sunday, Monday, Tuesday, and Saturday are the same, however, Wednesday, Thursday, and Friday are different. Dominicans write Wednesday as &lt;em&gt;Mèkwédi&lt;/em&gt; whereas Saint Lucians write it as &lt;em&gt;Mékwédi&lt;/em&gt;, and Dominicans write Thursday as &lt;em&gt;Jèdi&lt;/em&gt; whereas Saint Lucians write it as &lt;em&gt;Jédi&lt;/em&gt;; the accent placement is different &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#dominica_dic2018&quot;&gt;(of Dominica, 2018)&lt;/a&gt;. Dominicans write Friday as &lt;em&gt;Vanwédi&lt;/em&gt; whereas Saint Lucians write it as &lt;em&gt;Vandwédi&lt;/em&gt;; here, while the accent is the same, the Saint Lucians appear to include an additional ‘d’, reminiscent of the original French [&amp;lt; Fr. &lt;em&gt;vendredi&lt;/em&gt;] (according to Frank (missing reference)).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is said that the shared creole alphabet writing system arose out of two creole ethnography workshops held in St. Lucia in January 1981 and September in 1982; this was developed through the efforts of researchers at “the University of the West Indies (U.W.I.), The Université Antilles – Guyane groups from St. Lucia (MOKWÉYÓL), Dominica (K.E.K.) and the Groupé d’Etude et de Recherche en Espace, Creolophone (GEREC) from Martinique and Guadeloupe” &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#creoleconference1980s&quot;&gt;(of Dominica, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the word, “Creole” can be viewed as a contested, polysemous term in the English language. The term has been used at different times and in various geographical regions to describe distinct identities, languages, peoples, ethnicities, racial heritages, and cultural artefacts. As an adjective, Creole was applied as an indicator of higher status bestowed upon Louisiana-born slaves to distinguish them from those born in African. It was also used as a noun to designate local birth in Louisiana, regardless of racial heritage; later Creole was used by Americans when referring to people of Spanish or French descent, yet it has often been conflated with the term “Cajan” (which described French colonists that settled in Canada’s Acadia region, then migrated to Louisiana). In fact, for some time, there was also a misconception that the term only referred to whites born in Louisiana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, Creole primarily refers to one’s linguistic heritage (French culture and a unique Franco-linguistic dialect) as the main source of their ethnic identity (particularly those of mixed or foreign ancestry). Creole, ‘Kreyol’ or ‘Kweyol’ also refers to the creole languages in the Caribbean, including Antillean Creole, Haitian Creole, and Jamaican Creole, among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polysemy may indeed present an issue when attempting to study a language or dialects, however, it is in fact, the premise of much of the active literature in this language. Calypso, and most other endemic forms of music, may celebrate this ability to utilize words or phrases bearing double meanings to indirectly discuss topics that are often crude. Philips suggested that Calypsos can engage this method via ‘lamina lyrics’. &lt;em&gt;Much like an onion, these Calypsos have a number of different levels of meaning, concealed one underneath the other. Achieving this phenomenon, Calypsonians use frames and masks that manifest in Calypsos as a metaphor, metonym, polysemy, irony, and satire&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1863, August Schleicher, the German linguist, discussed languages as &lt;em&gt;natural organisms that come into being, develop, age, and die according to laws that are quite independent of man’s will&lt;/em&gt; (cited by Arens 1969:259). This perception of language is contrary to recent the modern view that it is one’s set of communication habits that have principally been defined by their social experience, led by an innate sense to decipher and learn the language practices of others. However, despite having a few members of the “native speaking generation” left, often communities lack the implementation of structures dedicated to the retention of language. Therefore, successive generations may require resources that express the necessity of the language as well as its desirability to ensure its continuance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mohan is of the view that living languages can die before “the last trace of memory has vanished”; that these languages may be experiencing a feigned guise of life through its observation of “sympathetic post-users from outside its system” (1979:42). To further quote Mohan, an obsolescent language:
&lt;em&gt;is actually dead before its forms have totally disappeared, in two different senses. A small part of the non-native speaking generation has preserved dead tokens of the language. Also, the time gap between the age of the youngest native speaker and the latest possible age of language acquisition, in infancy, shows the language dead at its source, but with a now finite community of native speakers continuing, like the earlier light of a dead star, to travel its original course and give an illusion picture of vitality (313).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover,  Sasse (2001) lists ten changes occurring during language obsolescence;  several of which bear similarities to those described by Campbell &amp;amp; Muntzel (1989) and Palosaari &amp;amp; Campbell (2011), namely: &lt;em&gt;loss of phonological distinctions, regularization of morphophonemics, loss of function words, analyticity, loss of morphology, loss of syntactic complexity, agrammatism, phonological and grammatical variability, reduction of vocabulary, and an increase in polysemy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evaluating and creating structures is crucial for the preservation and promotion of endangered languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Need to expand on the definition of systems dynamic model and other models here…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;perceptions-of-creole&quot;&gt;Perceptions of creole&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perceptions of the locals’ attitudes towards the creole language are often complicated. Language change in Saint Lucia has been a pressing concern for academics for many years. As recent as 1970,  Douglas Midgett highlighted that the formal teaching of Patois would be viewed as “unjustifiable and in any case, would never be tolerated by even its most ardent user”. At the time, he noted that most people agreed that increased proficiency in spoken and written English (or French) would be an educational must, however, writers and other academics and actual educators had differing views; the former group believed that use of creole in schools could aid with recognizing English as a second language, whereas educators adamantly argued against any use of Creoles in the schools. He believed that the use of Patois in the schools interchangeably with less formal, more colloquial English would aid in establishing English in the minds of students as a functional Patois equivalent. He suggested that as long as educational institutions reinforce the conventional traditional opinion of separating the two languages, the campaign for English literacy and spoken usage will not have widespread effectiveness. Midgett, however, underestimated how pervasive the English language would be; in fact, it is the creole language that currently lacks proper literacy among the public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1998, Frank explored and even expanded the written form of the creole language in Saint Lucia while attempting to effectively translate an English bible into the local language. Upon concluding his tasks he remarked that the bible would indirectly boost creole literacy through the motivational passages of the bible:
 &lt;em&gt;“… for all practical purposes Creole remains an unwritten language for the majority of the population, which remains unaware of the books published in Creole. Attempts to teach Creole literacy have not met with much success because of lack of interest. Motivation is the most important factor in the success of any literacy program, and having something people want to read is the most important motivating factor”&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;investigation&quot;&gt;Investigation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ultimately leaves one to wonder if it is logical and possible to merge an official online static dictionary with a dynamic slang dictionary to increase overall fluency in an endangered language? Such a system would require access to an existing dictionary, as well as opportunities for dictionary contributions. The creation of an interactive dictionary may assist with reinvigorating the usage of the language through active use and contributions to this resource, but also offer opportunities to actively discuss and clarify words and concepts associated with creole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Need to clean this up and add the references mentioned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;dominica_dic2018&quot;&gt;of Dominica, G. (2018). Kweyol Language. In &lt;i&gt;A virtual Dominica&lt;/i&gt;. gov.dm. https://www.avirtualdominica.com/project/creole-kweyol-language/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;creoleconference1980s&quot;&gt;of Dominica, G. (2020). A Brief History of Kwéyòl (Patwa). In &lt;i&gt;The Division of Culture&lt;/i&gt;. gov.dm. http://divisionofculture.gov.dm/creole-languages/5-kweyol&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Current Tasks</title>
   <link href="http://llord1.github.io/papers/2020/11/14/CurrentTasks"/>
   <updated>2020-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://llord1.github.io/papers/2020/11/14/CurrentTasks</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h4 id=&quot;current-tasks&quot;&gt;Current tasks:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;NLP video by Alice Zhao&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;Look into recommended NLP textbooks&lt;/del&gt;: can still look into more&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;Review some dissertations on NLP:&lt;/del&gt; can still look into more&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Review Sentiment Analysis videos by Pennebaker&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Explore well-known and recent NLP articles, and read the articles recommended by John&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Summarize NLP articles for core concepts and models&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;Review some publications related to NLP:&lt;/del&gt; can still look into more&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Update conference/publication plan (data science and linguistics conferences).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Write out the differences between linguistics, computational linguistics, digital humanities, and data science for literature review.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Compare to other existing sentiment analysis software/ tools&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Read up on graph theory and sentiment analysis&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Find additional committee members related to linguistics/NLP&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Speak to these potential members to at least get feedback on progress&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.acm.org/doi/pdf/10.1145/3321128&quot;&gt;From Genesis to Creole Language: Transfer Learning for Singlish Universal Dependencies Parsing and POS Tagging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Have at least a basic model and some committee members by end of the semester.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Current Outline</title>
   <link href="http://llord1.github.io/papers/2020/11/14/CurrentOutline"/>
   <updated>2020-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://llord1.github.io/papers/2020/11/14/CurrentOutline</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Current tasks and paper outline:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maslow’s need for belonging: Addressing the “lost in translation” issues with sentiment analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;establishing-conceptsthemes&quot;&gt;Establishing concepts/themes:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Includes a critique of data science pedagogy (revamped creative and ethical data science research topic-generation); differentiating between linguistics and computational linguistics, digital humanities, and biocultural diversity, and NLP discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;goal-improved-cross-lingual-sentiment-analysis-models&quot;&gt;Goal: Improved Cross-Lingual Sentiment Analysis Models&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Describe the basics of sentiment analysis along with a brief summary of related work.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Introduce possible scenarios for cross-lingual sentiment analysis, argues the use of machine translation, and introduces an example target language - Saint Lucian creole&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;model-design-and-application&quot;&gt;Model design and application:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cross-Lingual Sentiment Analysis (using not bi-grams, but phrase-grams with LIWC in Machine Translation); NLP model proposal for Creole to English, English to Creole Rule-Based Machine Translation System.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;assessing-accuracy-via-datasets&quot;&gt;Assessing accuracy via datasets:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Provide details of data sets and tools used in experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Using established datasets (sources of Creole literature, and sentences from Creole dictionary (labeled)).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Consider an experiment using corpus-based cross-lingual projections.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Study cross-lingual polarity detection where (labeled or unlabeled) data in the target language is available.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Compare the methods for translation of sentiment lexicons.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Use POS tags from the Creole dictionary&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Attempt Cross-Lingual Sentiment labeling with LIWC&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Evaluate special rules of creole for a Rule-Based Machine Translation; is there anything unique to creole&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Provide a summary of all experiment results, remarks, contributions and directions for further research.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;related-prediction-models&quot;&gt;Related prediction models:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Language and law (predict the likelihood of success in creole cases, the typical legal language/phrases in creole cases).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;additional-models-and-discussions&quot;&gt;Additional models and discussions:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Kmeans clustering for Creole language origins; French, African, Spanish, Portuguese, English, and Tamil. Many-to-one relationship?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Consideration of Cross-Lingual Sentiment Analysis Models using graph theory.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Test text generation: Machine Learning using transformers (not LSTM); GPT2 (using TensorFlow and Google Collab)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Attempt to leverage the natural annotation provided by a crowdsourced online dictionary &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiwords.com/&quot;&gt;Wiwords&lt;/a&gt;, to actively/continuously address word sense disambiguation issues that arise from the analysis of a low-resource language (Saint Lucian Creole)’s social media (Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, etc.) text data. By improving word sense disambiguation issues with the creole language, one may be better able to assess the language’s vitality via assessing the frequency of its usage in social media posts. &lt;a href=&quot;https://llord1.github.io/papers/2020/11/27/wiwords&quot;&gt;See a draft of expanded discussion.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Attempt to use the phrase-grams to aid with creating additional Creole literature on various topics; attempting to translate an English legal document into Creole (check if accuracy is present; if the text remains neutral (as the law is believed to be so, or if there are additional emotions detected)and see how successful additional legal document generation could be.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Additional paper on standard creative literature (stories and fables).  Thinking and creating in English first, then translating to Creole; or thinking and creating directly in Creole, then translating to English.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Some calypso songs have parts that are purely creole, however, these are designed to have hidden meaning using plain phrases. It will be interesting to see if the AI can detect the subtlety.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Current questions: Is this Ph.D. level work yet? How can I improve what I have/ check what is missing? Are these the only areas I need to be aware of when addressing a lost in translation issue?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Data Sci. Discussions: Capitonyms</title>
   <link href="http://llord1.github.io/papers/2020/09/29/capitonyms"/>
   <updated>2020-09-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://llord1.github.io/papers/2020/09/29/capitonyms</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h3 id=&quot;general-discussion-of-capitonyms&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General discussion of Capitonyms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of this Ph.D. program, I believe I have become a bit more capable of noticing applications of NLP concepts in my surroundings. I now look at Grammarly.com and wonder about the underlying tools and infrastructure. I think about Noam Chomsky’s ideas on the “autonomy of syntax”, where syntax and grammar depict information that is independent of the meaning and semantics of words,  and how that may impact autocorrection here. It seems to have some sort of an interactive spelling correction, with an interesting combination of background lemmatization, tokenization, and PoS tagging; Grammarly.com probably has some “named entity recognition”, with “sentence boundary detection”, and a “Word Sense Disambiguation” feature using some kind of Lesk algorithm and snowball stemmer and (like those present in Python’s NLTK). Concepts like the editing of stopwords are not applied here, and it is not yet capable of properly handling corrections for various languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;te-quiero-yo-te-quiero&quot;&gt;Te quiero/ Yo te quiero:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also noticed that some phrases do not trigger error alerts in Grammarly.com. It appears that it does allow for Spanish phrases to be addressed as correct or incorrect, on an assumingly English platform. Sometimes it flags a Spanish word as incorrect simply because the word is not capitalized. For example, one can look at the Spanish phrase ‘te quiero’;  this is the informal way of saying ‘I love you’, and has a lighter connotation of love and care when compared to the more romantic phrase ‘te amo’. Grammarly.com currently suggests that one capitalizes only the word quiero, to make the phrase acceptable/ remove the grammar alert (‘te Quiero’).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Quiero’ appears to have Latin roots from the word &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wordsense.eu/quaero/&quot;&gt;‘quaero’&lt;/a&gt; - meaning to ‘seek’ or ‘look for’. The word ‘quiero’ is indeed a tricky one as it can be arrived at through conjugation, based on different scenarios. It can be derived from the reciprocal verb ‘Quererse’, where it can mean ‘to feel affection for’ (to love each other). It can also be derived from the transitive verb ‘Querer’; however, in a transitive form (where it demands things), it also has several slightly different meanings; it can mean ‘to feel affection’ which includes ‘to love’, ‘to like’, and ‘to be fond of’; it can also indicate intention (‘to mean’ and ‘to try’), or to wish (‘to want’). I will, however, state that the fact that quiero can be applied to so many different scenarios, can serve to support an argument for it being a demonstration of polysemy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps, this issue with Grammarly.com is indeed due to quiero’s typical usage; it typically indicates a want. For example, one can want an item, like ice-cream; ‘Quiero helado’ translates to ‘I want ice-cream’. Here Quiero’s use is viewed as correct, yet instead, helado is marked here as non-English. I suppose the Spanish phrase for “want ice-cream” may not be as popular/common, and one could say that this may have been a flaw with the original training data; however, I am uninformed of the underlying structure, so I am unable to state if is completely based on machine learning models (or combined with a supporting language-translation tool) where quiero would have been typically encountered at the beginning of a sentence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, GoogleTranslate and Python’s Textblob library may also be a bit faulty as it seems that they offer varied capitalizations or meanings when a word or phrase is hyphenated, separate, or concatenated &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#sarkar2019text&quot;&gt;(Sarkar, 2019; Sarkar, 2019)&lt;/a&gt;. When using GoogleTranslate from English to Spanish, to indicate that I want ice cream (with the words ice and cream separated) there are no capitalizations. However, if I hyphenate or concatenate, it capitalizes the word “Quiero”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This translation issue might also be due to the distinction between direct and indirect objects is not quite the same in Spanish, as it is in English; and thus the pronouns that represent them are sometimes called accusative and dative pronouns, respectively. Or it could be that the verb, Querer,  is considered to be a transitive verb (one that needs to have a direct object) and, therefore its usage is a bit more complex, thus difficult to program? Anyway, since the language is so temperamental does that mean that larger training datasets are needed to detect the nuance of the appropriate use or translation, or is this something a language package update/ new package could address?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;current-example-of-machine-translation-issues-in-action&quot;&gt;Current example of machine translation issues in action:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, in the last week, the singer Jennifer Lopez had a controversial Spanish line in her latest song that caused an interesting look into the NLP capitonym challenges. She called herself “Tu negrita del Bronx”. Negrita as you can probably guess can imply that something is dark, and “ita” is usually added to the end of something to indicate a term of endearment, infantilizing, or insulting to a dark-skinned person. People were unsure of what she meant by its use since she is clearly not dark in skin tone, but she tried to explain that in some parts of the Spanish world, calling someone dark-skinned is universal- basically, saying anyone who is not white is dark, and they do uplift each other for this quality. So confused fans went to Google for a literal translation, only to encounter further confusion; if you capitalized Bronx, it would display the negative version (your n-word from the Bronx), and if you did not capitalize it would have translated to the milder version ( “Your black girl from the bronx”).  Textblob also has the same translation result for both scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, that capitonym also appears to be used in Textblob to a certain extent; it appeared to be a means to address the differentiation between formal forms and informal forms of conversations.
The formal form of ‘yo te quiero’ and the informal from ‘te quiero’ result in ‘I love you’ and  ‘i love u’,  respectively. Note that regardless of capitalization in the formal phrase, the result is capitalized.  Yet only when the first character is capitalized in the informal (‘Te quiero’), will it be reciprocated in the result (‘I love u’); yet, the other words remain in their informal forms (‘you’ remains as ‘u’). An additional consideration is that when the word ‘mucho’ accompanies the phrase ‘te quiero’ to form ‘te quiero mucho’ (‘I love you very much’)  it seems to be regarded as formal, as all the necessary formatting is present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be interesting to see if translation changes over time to directly address this concern as the scandal would have generated additional internet chatter. It does not appear that Google is addressing this matter based on a live training dataset but perhaps based on a package like Textblob. Using keywords like “capitonym” “te quiero” “textblob”, I was unable to find any current literature on this occurrence via any Google or present in any scholarly archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I guess would love to do some sort of commentary paper on this phenomenon; to perhaps discuss the possible inner workings of the underlying algorithm that furthered the scandal, and discuss the possible future implications. Since world leaders are increasing their use of informal text and speech through the use of social media platforms, yet these same governments rely on this technology for translation, there could be potential future conflicts due to literal misinterpretation. Perhaps data science studies can raise the alarm for a need for improvement in the underlying flawed structure that lacks live updating to formal and informal dictionaries or demonstrates overfit models. That paper would have gone under my Maslow’s needs sections on belonging or security, since miscommunication can facture one’s sense of belonging, and subsequently lead to a lack of sense of security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently reading a work called &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyurl.com/yyu3fxl2&quot;&gt;‘The definite article in Spanish as a polysemous category’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; since it was published in the Journal of Cognitive Science as if 2017; however, I acknowledge this is just for personal edification since this is more along the realms of Cognitive Linguistics and not pure Data Science. I am also reading &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://upcommons.upc.edu/handle/2117/7492&quot;&gt;‘Linguistic-based evaluation criteria to identify statistical machine translation errors’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; since I am interested in statistical machine translation errors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;sarkar2019text&quot;&gt;Sarkar, D. (2019). &lt;i&gt;Text analytics with Python: a practitioner’s guide to natural language processing&lt;/i&gt;. Apress.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;sarkar_2019&quot;&gt;Sarkar, D. (2019). &lt;i&gt;Text Analytics with Python&lt;/i&gt;. Apress. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4842-4354-1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Survey Consent:Lawyers</title>
   <link href="http://llord1.github.io/2020/08/26/LawConsent"/>
   <updated>2020-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://llord1.github.io/2020/08/26/LawConsent</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Institutional Review Board&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harrisburg University of Science and Technology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participation Consent Agreement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This linguistic research study has been approved by the Institutional Review Board (IRB) of Harrisburg University of Science and Technology (HU). This research study is led by …, a Ph. D. candidate in Data Science Department at HU. The Faculty Advisor for this study is …, Professor of Analytics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This study is being conducted in compliance with the standards and guidelines given by the HU IRB. The Collaborative Institution Training Initiative (CITI) Program has certified the researcher, Laurel Lord, for human-subject research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose of the Study:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this research is to gather general demographic data of lawyers and identify patterns of linguistic legal representation on the multilingual island of Saint Lucia. There will be a specific focus on the second most prevalent language - “Saint Lucian Kwéyòl”. The responses of participants will be run through textual analytical tools to provide insight into the legal environment that Saint Lucians, particularly Kwéyòl speakers, experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participant Tasks:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each participant is asked to fill out an online survey to provide their basic demographic details, statements on their multilingual capacities, and statements on the current linguistic legal environment. The form contains eleven questions that each participant may be able to complete in less than thirty minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participant Risks and Discomforts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no anticipated risk for the participant in this research. All information will be protected, and the confidentiality of the data will be maintained throughout this research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Survey Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The collection of profession-specific labor statistical data is uncommon in Saint Lucia. Additionally, there appears to be low societal consideration of the increasing multilingual environment; therefore, data collection and analysis of this specific profession could serve as a template for job-specific data collection and improve the legal representation offered to the inhabitants of Saint Lucia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participation is Voluntary:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Survey paSurvey participation is voluntary, and individuals may choose not to participate if uncomfortable with answering any of the questions after signing the consent form by withdrawing from the survey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participant Compensation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no compensation for participation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy/Confidentiality/Data Security:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The The data collected will be saved in a standard hard drive for three years; non-identifiable data, and a report, will be submitted to the Bar Association of Saint Lucia and The Central Statistical Office of Saint Lucia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inquires/Questions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any Any questions may be directed to … at …@my.harrisburgu.edu. Questions or concerns regarding your rights as a subject in this study may be directed to HU IRB via 717-901-5100 or their website at harrisburgu.edu.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Just a quick link to the draft form</title>
   <link href="http://llord1.github.io/2020/08/26/DraftForm"/>
   <updated>2020-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://llord1.github.io/2020/08/26/DraftForm</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://form.jotform.com/203134599286160&quot;&gt;See draft survey with consent form here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Assets: Assessing the link between crime and language</title>
   <link href="http://llord1.github.io/2020/08/26/AssetsSLUlawsurvey"/>
   <updated>2020-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://llord1.github.io/2020/08/26/AssetsSLUlawsurvey</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h3 id=&quot;safety-and-security-needs-can-be-explored-as-topics-related-to-assets&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Safety and security needs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; can be explored as topics related to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Assets&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;linguistics-and-maslows-safety-and-security-needs&quot;&gt;Linguistics and Maslow’s safety and security needs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the extended period of social disruption caused by the 2020 SARS-CoV-2 pandemic, many gained a newfound appreciation for Maslow’s theory on a hierarchy of needs &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#maslow_1943_2000&quot;&gt;(Maslow, 1943; Matias et al., 2020; Wong et al., 2020; Casale &amp;amp; Flett, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. Global citizens reflected on the loss of lives, the loss of a sense of justice, the loss of financial stability, the subsequent loss of housing stability, and an overall sense of the loss of social normalcy. Many are also concerned about the severity and frequency of natural disasters that were increasingly impacting all forms of life within our complex global socio-ecological environment. In a time of crisis, Maslow’s theory can aid in visualizing and prioritizing scarce resources according to one’s needs, and data science can be used to explore, assess, and address those needs; data science can serve as a tool of establishing a degree of certainty, in uncertain times. Often, obtaining our needs is intrinsically linked to the ease with which we are able to communicate - our ability to understand and to be understood. To effectively facilitate the communication of various societal needs, data science can be employed as a means of monitoring and maintaining the standards of numerous fields through the careful study of an environment’s linguistics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several careers in society can contribute to providing the general sense of safety and security that Maslow often discussed &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#diener2011happiness&quot;&gt;(Diener &amp;amp; Biswas-Diener, 2011)&lt;/a&gt;. Notably, obvious, yet often overlooked are issues concerning human communication. Miscommunication can mean the difference between life and death in some fields, particularly those of medical practitioners and members of the justice system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data science is the backbone for most research and is often the key that unlocks paradigm research. In Mattmann’s “vision for data science” he suggested that “for the specialism to emerge and grow, data scientists will have to overcome barriers that are common to multidisciplinary research” &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#mattmann2013vision&quot;&gt;(Mattmann, 2013)&lt;/a&gt;. Therefore, thoughtful data collection and monitoring of these crucial services can improve the services provided to the public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;linguistic-research-trends-in-safety-and-security-needs-fields&quot;&gt;Linguistic research trends in “safety and security needs” fields&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thoughtful deliberation of linguistics, particularly the consideration of language barriers, is increasing in many fields; this is most noticeable in the medical field as the effectiveness of communication can have a direct impact on the safety and security, in terms of the patient’s life. As recently as 2019, Sweden conducted a national study on health care professionals’ communications through interpreters; this study was conducted after noting that many parents utilizing neonatal care were foreign-born and unable to effectively communicate with the healthcare professionals in the local language &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#patriksson2019health&quot;&gt;(Patriksson et al., 2019)&lt;/a&gt;. In 2013, linguistic work had been done to highlight communications issues between physicians and Spanish-speaking Latin American women with pelvic floor disorders &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#sevilla2013communication&quot;&gt;(Sevilla et al., 2013)&lt;/a&gt;; this study highlighted that apart from patients’ lack of disease understanding, there was a lack of Spanish proficiency among the participating physicians. Another 2013 research project centered on the perceptions of patient-provider communication in breast and cervical cancer-related care when dealing with low-income English and Spanish-speaking women &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#simon2013perceptions&quot;&gt;(Simon et al., 2013)&lt;/a&gt;. Even in 2009, there was a study done on competent peer support intervention for Spanish-speaking Latinas with breast cancer &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#napoles2009developing&quot;&gt;(Nápoles-Springer et al., 2009)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the aforementioned cases mostly shifted the majority of the responsibility of effective communication to additional parties, such as regulated translators, rather than assessing a multilingual professional’s inherent communication skills. Studies are increasingly being attempted on professionals that can speak more than one language; investigations can include assessments of the sufficiency of their training materials when their primary language is not the dominant language of the country in which they practice. One study did investigate Spanish–English bilingual psychotherapists and their personal and professional language development and use &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#verdinelli2009spanish&quot;&gt;(Verdinelli &amp;amp; Biever, 2009)&lt;/a&gt;. Another study was conducted on instances where nurses double as interpreters (a study of Spanish-speaking patients in a US primary care setting) &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#elderkin2001nurses&quot;&gt;(Elderkin-Thompson et al., 2001)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the support from studies that demonstrated the importance of foreign language assistance programs, mistakes still occurred during the 2020 SARS-CoV-2 pandemic. Failed communication systems of a government department denied detainees informed consent, and therefore facilitated blatant medical malpractice on unwitting immigrant patients; there were notable instances of the performance of unnecessary services on captive multilingual immigrant patients &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#olivares_washington_ICE2020&quot;&gt;(Olivares &amp;amp; Washington, 2020; Treisman, 2020; BBC, 2020; Cassady, 2020; Lambe, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. Despite the presence of foreign language assistance resources, the utilization of these resources was not carefully monitored or enforced. In these situations, communication failures serve to highlight that failures to communicate and enforce the legal rights of these patients can also lead to life and death situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;benefits-to-multilingual-law-practitioners&quot;&gt;Benefits to multilingual law practitioners&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investigations concerning linguistics and “safety and security needs” can also involve members of the justice system. Furthermore, there are also are benefits to be reaped by law practitioners. As of 2015, Brian Porro, the principal translator at the Directorate-General for Translation at the European Commission, eagerly sought to hire lawyer-linguists at the European Court of Justice; instead, he noted that there was “a dearth of suitably qualified prospective English candidates in law with an additional language” &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#ahmed_2015&quot;&gt;(Ahmed, 2015)&lt;/a&gt;. Therefore, this scarcity of capable multilingual lawyers may allow for international law firms to extend higher salaries to bilingual employees. Further, Porro suggested that speaking additional languages facilitated better communication. He added that the very presence of a sub-discipline could highlight one’s ability to concentrate and deploy your language skills in legal practice &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#ahmed_2015&quot;&gt;(Ahmed, 2015)&lt;/a&gt;. He also notes that one’s language skills could also provide opportunities to work abroad &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#ahmed_2015&quot;&gt;(Ahmed, 2015)&lt;/a&gt;. Moreover, it does appear that inhabitants of multilingual societies would benefit from having figures of law enforcement, and practice, being able to effectively communicate in these languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;law-and-linguistics-in-a-multilingual-setting&quot;&gt;Law and linguistics in a multilingual setting&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address the public’s “safety and security needs” lawyers can take on multiple roles, where they can enforce laws and maintain peace. Notably, they can also serve as change agents when addressing flaws in existing laws or proposing laws to meet new public “safety and security needs”. Andras Sajo’s 1993 work on the &lt;em&gt;“Role of Lawyers in Social Change”&lt;/em&gt; highlighted instances, in the country of Hungary, where lawyers exuded direct and indirect political and social influences &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#sajo1993role&quot;&gt;(Sajo, 1993)&lt;/a&gt;. Overall his work supports the idea that the power wielded by elite figures, such as lawyers, can have an intense impact on society &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#sajo1993role&quot;&gt;(Sajo, 1993; UMassAmherst, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. He suggested that lawyers as a profession, &lt;em&gt;“function in society as keepers of the law, through courts and/or through avoiding and channeling contracts with law-enforcing mechanisms”&lt;/em&gt;. Sajo noted that Hungary was a &lt;em&gt;“lawyer-dominated society, both in terms of the percentage of lawyers among the intellectual elite and the importance of legal dispute handling”&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#sajo1993role&quot;&gt;(Sajo, 1993)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also spoke of these lawyers as being part of the &lt;em&gt;“intellighentzia”&lt;/em&gt; as being &lt;em&gt;“elite professionals independent from employment relations or at least appearing independent”&lt;/em&gt;, and highlighted their vital part in Eastern European social changes, especially as those changes were &lt;em&gt;traditionally related to national independence movements in the last 150-200 years&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#sajo1993role&quot;&gt;(Sajo, 1993)&lt;/a&gt;. He praised these humanities professionals as ideal wordsmiths (based on their work in expressing the inherently emotional message of Hungary’s social movements); and also as stewards of social mobility for upcoming classes (as they utilized their traditional law school training, as members of the ruling classes, and directed it towards the public service sector and local self-government works) &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#sajo1993role&quot;&gt;(Sajo, 1993)&lt;/a&gt;. Stability in society seemed to rise with the number of lawyers from various social backgrounds; &lt;em&gt;“judges were administratively replaced by semi-skilled new “loyal” judges of worker and peasant origin”&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#sajo1993role&quot;&gt;(Sajo, 1993)&lt;/a&gt;. Ultimately, Sajo highlighted positive societal progress made possible through “elites”; one could infer that those lawyers satisfied a degree of their own need for self-actualization, as they truly internalized their roles of protecting the public’s “safety and security needs”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent history, one particularly notable work by Celia Brown-Blake, highlighted the interconnected nature of linguistics and law &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#brown_legal_change2014expanding&quot;&gt;(Brown-Blake, 2014)&lt;/a&gt;. Brown-Blake reviewed details of a Charter on Language Rights and Language Policy in the
Creole-speaking Caribbean stating that it may be a positive step, in a language-planning process that strived to “use the law as a tool to effect change in the language order of Caribbean Creole-speaking countries”, but also warned that it may only provide limited success without the proper recognition and enforcement of proposed changes &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#brown_legal_change2014expanding&quot;&gt;(Brown-Blake, 2014)&lt;/a&gt;. Brown-Blake’s work can serve as inspiration for creative problem-solving associated with linguistic barriers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Caribbean can serve as a rich multilingual setting in which one can explore the relationship between law and linguistics. The 2006 case for Gerald Joseph’s criminal appeal, served to highlight the importance of proper linguistic consideration for clients that speak heritage languages (missing reference). The complexity of this environment allows for multiple law specialties for a local Saint Lucian and overseas markets; thus, increasing the possibility of encountering non-English speakers as clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Caribbean has had a complicated past of trade, colonization, slavery, indentured labor, and more recently voluntary immigration. This, therefore, leads to a present setting of an actively multilingual environment that is ever-changing due to evolving political and legal policies (such as Citizenship by Investment (CIP) &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#bayat_2020&quot;&gt;(Bayat &amp;amp; El Hachem, 2020; GIS, 2017; CIP, 2020; Capital, 2020; Harvey, 2020; Visa, 2016)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;English is the main language spoken (a prestige language) in Saint Lucia, however, Saint Lucian Kwéyòl (Antillean Creole/Patios) is the heritage language of the island; there are several other languages officially taught (French and Spanish) and generally spoken in the close-knit Caribbean (such as Dutch, Portuguese, Hindi, Arabic, and even Japanese, Mandarin and increasingly Russian) &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#hillman2009understanding&quot;&gt;(Hillman &amp;amp; D’Agostino, 2009; “Saint Lucia,” n.d.; Kobayashi, 2020; Nesheim, 2020; CBF, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that the Saint Lucian constitution does outline the nature of trials in the native language of the accused. As of 1979 constitution officially began enforcing the following linguistic provisions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Any person who is arrested or detained shall with reasonable promptitude and in any case no later than twenty-four hours after such arrest or detention be informed in a language that he understands of the reasons for his arrest or detention and be afforded reasonable facilities for private communication and consultation with a legal practitioner of his own choice and, in the case of a minor, with his parents or guardian.”&lt;/em&gt; It also specifically stated that &lt;em&gt;“every person who is charged with a criminal offence… shall be informed as soon as reasonably practicable, in a language that he understands and in detail, of the nature of the offence charged…” and “shall be permitted to have without payment the assistance of an interpreter if he cannot understand the language used at the trial…”&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#slu_1978&quot;&gt;(SLU, 1978)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that the constitution is clear on what provisions to be made concerning the native language of the accused, however, it does not state how this standard is to be monitored or maintained or the level of fluency of the speakers. It appears that the accused is the one solely responsible for indicating if there are issues of miscommunication, rather than the courts maintaining such a standard. This lack of a formal monitoring system of the linguistic capabilities of lawyers on the island may lead to, at the very least, delays in justice when clients are seeking suitable legal representation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While legal aid, has become a reality for Saint Lucians within the last two decades, and court-appointed interpreter can be sought &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#SLU_legalaid_2015&quot;&gt;(Digital, 2015; Emmanuel, 2001; Satney, 2007)&lt;/a&gt;, the legal environment does have several areas for improvement &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#gaillard_SLULAW_2020&quot;&gt;(Gaillard, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. The legal environment (and the general public) does not appear to prioritize effective language assistance services. To that, a 2002 “crime trends in the Caribbean and responses report”, suggested that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Broadly, crime control and prevention strategies may be designed to (a) systematically treat the root causes of crime (b) make populations more resilient to criminality (c) strengthen the ability of the responsible institutions to respond to crime in all of its various expressions. In the language of the public health officials, the first would represent a kind of primary prevention.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This perspective highlights issues within the law enforcement and practitioners, as they do not emphasize the exploration of language barriers as part of progress; the focus is often on “modernizing police-citizen relations” via updated techniques and technologies, rather than improving direct communication skills with civilians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Douglas Midgett’s work on the anthropological linguistics of Saint Lucia, the island’s inhabitants have struggled in their appreciation of its heritage language &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#midgett1970bilingualism&quot;&gt;(Midgett, 1970)&lt;/a&gt;. Historically there were negative connotations with Saint Lucian Kwéyòl (Antillean Creole/Patios), upon emancipation there was extreme enmity between English and Creole in the newly free society; the use was negatively equated “with all that is backward, rural, Negro, and unsophisticated” &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#midgett1970bilingualism&quot;&gt;(Midgett, 1970)&lt;/a&gt;. Nonetheless, as of May 1970, Midgett suggested that the vitality of the language was still strong; he stated that “there still exists a situation in which virtually every native-born St. Lucian can speak Patois” &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#midgett1970bilingualism&quot;&gt;(Midgett, 1970)&lt;/a&gt;. This language still appears to be surviving today, albeit under an inconclusive status; despite the recent surge in appeal due to governmental and pop culture support, the lingering lack of definitive vitality data could inadvertently permit an unabated decline &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#marmion2014community&quot;&gt;(Marmion et al., 2014; Midgett, 1970; Kabir, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. Ultimately, Midgett did, however, acknowledge that “English is the language of all national institutions… Patois is the language of folk institutions”; therefore, it is not surprising that some are still encouraged to learn and converse in English, rather than in Saint Lucian Kwéyòl, to appear more professional or polished &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#oas_2018&quot;&gt;(OAS, 2018)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, both Sajo and Brown-Blake investigated areas beyond simply practicing the law and drafting policies to foster necessary changes in society. One can therefore infer that while policies may boost linguistic equality and harmony in a multilingual society, proper enforcement of these policies and standards is crucial. It does, however, raise the question of the effectiveness of current monitoring practices, if there is no quantifiable tether to these ideals in the form of active data collection. Based on the aforementioned works of Sajo and Midgett, one can infer that to effectively raise the prestige of minority heritage or minority languages, their prevalence among the “elite” members of society, those that hold a great influence on society’s sense of safety and security, should be monitored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;monitoring-and-maintaining-linguistic-standards-in-lawyering&quot;&gt;Monitoring and maintaining linguistic standards in lawyering:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-noted-gap-in-demographic-data&quot;&gt;A noted gap in demographic data&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although data collection on the various professions can be conducted by private companies, it is typically undertaken by government-backed labor agencies to ensure that the data is freely available to the public. While not all developing nations have been able to dedicate resources to the close monitoring of this data, its value is increasingly recognized. In America, the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS) collects such data and hosts it on a public website &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#BLS2020&quot;&gt;(BLS, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The U.S. BLS provides general information on the demographics of the lawyers in the country, however, the American Bar Association (ABA) gathers more detailed information on Legal Profession Statistics &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#BLS2020&quot;&gt;(BLS, 2020; ABA, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. Their current statistical data is used to assist with research on lawyers and the legal profession. Their website notes data on the topics of lawyer demographics (including matters of disability, women, and minority/people of color) &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#aba_2020&quot;&gt;(ABA, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. It also encompasses justice system statistics (including topics on public perception of justice system/lawyers and the justice system), court statistics (including cases filed, and criminal justice statistics) &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#aba_2020&quot;&gt;(ABA, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. This association also notes the topics of law students and education and legal salaries (and related attrition/retention data) &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#aba_2020&quot;&gt;(ABA, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saint Lucia’s National Environmental Information System (NEIS) has been one of the latest governmental attempts at collecting and organizing national data &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#govtSLU_NEIS_2019&quot;&gt;(govt.lc, 2019)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#govtSLU_NEIS&quot;&gt;(neis.govt.lc, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#govtSLUdata&quot;&gt;(govt.lc, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. This “Project Reporting System for Multilateral Environmental Agreement (MEA) Implementation and Environmental Information Management” is regarded as a “legal instrument with binding effects on countries that have agreed to become parties” &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#govtSLU_NEIS&quot;&gt;(neis.govt.lc, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. Saint Lucia’s participation in this international agreement, enhances global agreements and sustainable development projects moving forward. However, one current category that highlights the “employed labor force by industry”, is classified as having a low priority level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, lawyer demographics in Saint Lucia (SLU) do not appear to be centrally gathered. The 2016 Labour Force Survey, made publicly available by The Central Statistical Office of SLU; while it inquired into one’s occupation status, job title, industry, business name, and type of work, the resulting response data appeared to be difficult to utilize (missing reference). The form was very complex and detailed to the point where it was a bit detrimental; the form allowed for so many generalizations and customizations of categories such as job titles so that the resulting information seemed to be challenging to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the dataset ultimately appears to have been simplified to the point where details on individual professions were rendered indiscernible. The response most related to lawyers would be one that highlighted occupations that involved “professional, scientific and technical activities”; this made up 1.0% (51 participants) of the survey. A representative of The Central Statistical Office of SLU stated that the data in the country’s 2016 Labour Force Survey was “not disaggregated in such a way to get a count of all lawyers” (missing reference). It was also stated that since the 2016 Labour Force Survey “utilizes a sample if it were to give a figure it would not be representative” (missing reference). Ultimately, even the president of the Bar Association of SLU (Renee St. Rose), also confirmed that she was unaware of the departments of government bearing statistical data specific to lawyers &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#st.rose_information_2020&quot;&gt;(St.Rose, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-noted-gap-in-linguistic-legal-data&quot;&gt;A noted gap in linguistic legal data&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The consideration of a country’s legal system’s ties to linguistics is not new, however, the topic has not been thoroughly explored (particularly in extensively multilingual and multicultural settings such as the Caribbean). Lawyering in a fairly multilingual setting can inherently be more challenging than lawyering in environments with very little linguistic diversity. However, operating in a country with a set prestige and active heritage language introduce additional challenges. One Caribbean academic did express the lack of study on crime and language in the region. In a 2020 interview, the aforementioned academic, Trinidadian linguist Jo-Anne Ferreira, stated &lt;em&gt;“crime was linked to lack of jobs, [which] is linked to lack of education, [which] is linked to lack of language access” thus, linking “crime and language”&lt;/em&gt;. She had no issues with English as the national official language of a country, however, she had strong concerns with the &lt;em&gt;“minoritizing of the majority and their language”&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#mendes-franco_2020&quot;&gt;(Mendes-Franco, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. She went on to state that &lt;em&gt;“bilingualism and multilingualism are normal around the world. The problem is we like to think of bilingualism as good only if it includes a language with status”&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#mendes-franco_2020&quot;&gt;(Mendes-Franco, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite her passion for the topic, Ferreira’s focus appeared to be on the cumulative circumstances that led to criminals to the life of crime &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#mendes-franco_2020&quot;&gt;(Mendes-Franco, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;, and not necessarily at the justice system that may be failing to effectively intercede on the behalf of heritage language speakers. Surveying the details of the languages spoken by current prisoners would be a comprehensive study; however, surveying those current prisoners may be highly time-consuming and a wrapped up in ethical bureaucracy. Such a study would also focus on first addressing the needs of current prisoners, rather than actively addressing language needs before individuals become entangled in the complexities of the local legal system. It is fair to have concerns about possible disparities in the applications of laws based on one’s practice of a heritage language (Saint Lucian Kwéyòl), rather than the prestige language (English). However, examining the linguistic skills of lawyers practicing in a multilingual environment may provide some useful and timely information, from a less complex participant pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;studys-purpose&quot;&gt;Study’s Purpose:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Assessing the link between crime and language.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reflection on Maslow’s need for safety and security during the 2020 SARS-CoV-2 pandemic has highlighted gaps in data collection and monitoring various fields and industries in Saint Lucia. Unlike its North American counterpart, the Bar Association of Saint Lucia (and the local government) did not closely monitor the data of lawyers on the island. A need was, therefore, identified for obtaining detailed demographic data on lawyers. With many languages being spoken on the island, one does ponder the ease of communication between prestige and heritage language speakers, and whether it can impact one’s sense of safety and security; concerns about the effectiveness of legal defenses are warranted after the 2020 revelation of increasingly questionable behaviors among local lawyers &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#gaillard_SLULAW_2020&quot;&gt;(Gaillard, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;methodology&quot;&gt;Methodology:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;survey-environment-participants-and-instruments&quot;&gt;Survey environment: Participants and instruments&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project aims to conduct a non-experimental quantitative survey of lawyer demographic and linguistic data. The goal is to have as many lawyers participate as possible; therefore, determining the base total population of lawyers on the island is important to one gauging if the end participation levels meet sufficient statistical standards for the study to be considered viable. According to a 2020 public statement of the President of the Saint Lucia Bar Association (SLBA), there are just over 200 lawyers that practice in Saint Lucia &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#george_2020&quot;&gt;(George, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. Direct communications with the president of the SLBA, revealed that while membership is not mandatory, all lawyers are considered members of the association (unless they expressly declare this is not to be the case) &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#st.rose_followup_2020&quot;&gt;(St.Rose, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. It should be noted that a voluntary membership list on the SLBA website indicates that at least 64 members can be directly contacted via email by members of the public; however, the president of the SLBA has agreed to assist with the distribution of the survey by utilizing a private internal contact list of all members &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#st.rose_followup_2020&quot;&gt;(St.Rose, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An online survey was selected as the tool/instrument of data collection, to best adhere to social distancing protocols of the pandemic. A draft survey has been completed utilizing Google forms since there is no financial backing required for its launch; SurveyMonkey is a well-known online survey system, however, with a Basic (free) plan one can &lt;em&gt;“collect unlimited responses for free, but view either 40 or 100 responses per survey (depending on when you created an account and your billing location). Any responses over your account’s response limit are hidden, and will be deleted 60 days after they’re received”&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#surveymonkey_2020&quot;&gt;(SurveyMonkey, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. Since responses are estimated to be between 64 and 500, SurveyMonkey may not be the most financially efficient tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This survey does not currently offer any financial compensation to participants. Most censuses do not compensate respondents, as respondents may view participation as a basic civic duty. Furthermore, it noted that there is an additional extrinsic motivation to comply if the survey is administered by or on behalf of a government body, an industry, an association, or an educational institution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the need for compensation of participants for surveys and questionnaires is still a highly disputed matter in research fields. It can be argued that despite increasing the rate of participation, compensating participants does not guarantee their attention to detail and honesty. On the other hand, some may argue that non-compensation decreases participation numbers, and may not guarantee attention to detail; however, there is a higher likelihood of honest answers as motivation is fueled by sheer interest, and not clouded by monetary gain, but sheer interest. Overall, arguing for or against compensation is further complicated when administered in a setting that lacks detailed data/ has conducted limited data analysis of the people and the culture. The US is highly data-driven and has records going back centuries, whereas records in places such as the Caribbean, maybe non-existent, under-resourced, or even deliberately destroyed. One would be able to argue that compensation is necessary for inhabitants of the US, yet, it seems highly questionable to arrive at the same conclusion for a different (and understudied) culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding data or studies to support compensation in countries or regions that are under-researched has proven challenging. However, Goldstein pointed to a work that seemed apt for this situation; that being Stecklov and co.’s work on “can incentives improve survey data quality in developing countries?” &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#stecklov2018can&quot;&gt;(Stecklov et al., 2018)&lt;/a&gt;. The difference between compensation and non-compensation was about 96 to 99.9 percent, respectively. Notably, the work observed that bias arose in compensated participants when questioned about assets, monthly income, and consumption of luxury expenditures (all being reported lower); thus, it appeared that the incentive group attempted appearing poorer than their actual situation to somehow justify the compensation they were receiving. Providing compensation also bears consideration of the possible negative impact of an overjustification effect in the context of a project on social good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, one’s culture may also impact survey participation and the need for compensation. Despite being a small island with a commensurate population, and newly independent (as of 1979), the inhabitants of Saint Lucia appear to have a heightened sense of community and social progress; Caribbean islands can be viewed as collectivist societies (albeit a forced outcome of colonialization). One can, therefore, infer that perhaps digital surveys that aim to improve their societies, through census type surveys of industries and professions, are even more likely to be favorably received in a collectivist setting (thus requiring no compensation) than in an individualistic setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, as noted before, the Central Statistical Office of SLU, acknowledges that their collection of data is highly limited and rarely done; the department is still developing resources and acquiring personnel, and, therefore, limitations to research are likely to be linked to data gatherers limited resources, rather than lack of responses from data givers. Moreover, since the survey stands to benefit their field, lawyers may be more inclined to answer honestly and paid attention to detail. Therefore, while compensation may become a necessary consideration for future surveys, voluntary participation in this socially beneficial project does not appear to necessitate compensation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the analysis will encompass initial exploratory factor analysis (EFA) and then evaluated with confirmatory factor analysis (CFA), with visualizations, and will include Chi-square tests of independence &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#luk2013bilingualism&quot;&gt;(Luk &amp;amp; Bialystok, 2013; Suhr, 2006)&lt;/a&gt;. Results will be run through both Python and R Studio; the best representations of the data will be selected. Additional analysis and tools may be applied where necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;survey-design-questions&quot;&gt;Survey Design: Questions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://form.jotform.com/203134599286160&quot;&gt;See draft survey (with consent form) here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be basic demographic data collection on Saint Lucian lawyers (questions 1- 8 below), and linguistic data collection on Saint Lucian lawyers (questions 9-17 below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;1. Please indicate your age from the following ranges.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Options: Less than 18; 18-24; 25-29 ;30-34; 35-39; 40-44; 45-49; 50-54; 55-59; 60-64; 65-69; 70-74; 75 or older; Choose not to respond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The age range (multiple choice) was based on the ABA data that indicates lawyers typically obtain higher education levels beyond high-school and remain in practice past the age of 65 &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#ABA2020Profile&quot;&gt;(Association, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;; the median age of all U.S. workers was 42.3 years old, yet very few lawyers are younger than 25 and the median age for U.S. lawyers in 2019 was 47.5 years old. This question was posed as a standard demographic question, yet it was also important as it highlighted the current and future state of the legal linguistic environment. Noting age may highlight multilingualism trends among age groups. For example, if multilingualism is more prominent in the younger lawyers, then the projection of multilingual representation would be positive positive. However, if multilingual tendencies are clustered among older lawyers, then this study may serve to highlight needed points of improvement in the legal system in an increasingly multilingual society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;2. Please indicate which of the following classifications best describe (s) you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Options: Man; Woman; Choose not to respond; Other (please specify)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gender identification is another standard (multiple choice) demographic question, however, it is useful to gather this data check whether the August 2020 American trend of men outnumbering women (especially in leadership), is replicated in and persistent in the Caribbean country of Saint Lucia &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#ABA2020Profile&quot;&gt;(Association, 2020; Clio, 2020; Ernde, 2019)&lt;/a&gt;. There may also be a need to highlight if there are any differences in linguistics interests among the lawyers. Females are often believed to be more capable of and interested in linguistic acquisition and practice. Data gathered could confirm or dispute this assumption &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#van2015gender&quot;&gt;(Van Der Slik et al., 2015)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;3. Please indicate which of the following best describe (s) your ethnicity/race.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Options: Amerindian (Native Caribbean People)/American Indian/Alaska Native; Black/African/Afro-Caribbean; White/North European; Mediterranean (Greek, Italian, Turkish, Syrian, etc.); Hispanic/ Latino (Mexican, Central or South American, or other Spanish or Portuguese, etc.); Indian subcontinent; SE Asian/Chinese/Native Hawaiian/ Other Pacific Islander; Mixed parentage; Not known; Choose not to respond; Other:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the ABA noted that “most state bars and state licensing agencies do not track race and ethnicity in the profession”, in 2020 there was an increase in this type of data collection &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#ABA2020Profile&quot;&gt;(Association, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#clio_2020&quot;&gt;(Clio, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#AttorneyAtWork_2019&quot;&gt;(Ernde, 2019)&lt;/a&gt;. As of 2010, only 11.4% of all American lawyers were men and women of color, and this only rose to 14.1% in 2020 &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#ABA2020Profile&quot;&gt;(Association, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#clio_2020&quot;&gt;(Clio, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#AttorneyAtWork_2019&quot;&gt;(Ernde, 2019)&lt;/a&gt;. In developed countries, like America, it is said that minorities remain underrepresented in the legal profession; however, there is limited information on the legal environment of the Caribbean-an environment where the majority of the population would historically be non-white. As of the 2010 Saint Lucian census, the “ethnic group” of 
“African Descents” represented about 85.28 percent of the population (the highest); this was distantly followed by the “Mixed” category with 10.85 percent, and the “East Indian” at 2.16 percent &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#CSO_SLU2010&quot;&gt;(CSO, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, one’s household and upbringing may shape or influence one’s interests. Multiculturalism is quite prevalent in the Caribbean, however, one’s multilingualism might be impacted by one’s upbringing. While formal education may be a primary factor in one’s language acquisition, various states of immigration over generations, or other forms of diversity in one’s household, might influence their linguistic capacities.
Identifying participant ethnicity/race is another standard demographic inquiry, nevertheless, its inclusion is to highlight any differences in linguistics interests among the lawyers based on their backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;4. Please indicate the base of citizenship that best applies to you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Options: Jus sanguinis (right of blood); Jus soli (right of birthplace); Naturalization; Non-citizen; Choose not to respond&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This question may be useful in establishing whether naturalized citizens are more likely to be multilingual than locally born persons (or persons with familial ties to the country. Legal terms were used to add a bit more clarification. This question is indeed problematic as it may be considered an identifiable trait in the survey, based on the limited number of lawyers on the island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;5. Please indicate the number of years you have been in practice (number of years since your first call to the bar in the Common-Wealth etc.).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Options: Less than 1; 1-5; 6-10; 11-15; 16-20; 21-25; 26-30; 31 or more; Choose not to respond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not a typical demographic question, however, it is one that can reveal data on the vibrancy or stagnancy of the field in terms of linguistics. It was an attempt to pinpoint how long one can thrive in an industry without the need for multilingual skills. It will be interesting to explore if career longevity is strongly or weakly associated with one’s linguistic acquisitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;6. Please indicate the option (s) that best describes your current working environment.&lt;/em&gt;
Options: In private practice, in a firm with less than 5 lawyers; In private practice, in a firm with 5-15 lawyers; In private practice, in a firm with 16-25 lawyers; In private practice, in a firm with 26-50 lawyers; In private practice, in a firm with 51 or more lawyers; Public service (work with government agencies and officials, etc.); Public interest (legal aid, legal services, public defender, etc.); In a not for profit organization; In an academic institution; Choose not to respond; Other (please specify).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lawyers may choose to focus on different areas of the law, and the clients they encounter are due to this specialization &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#umassamherst_general2020&quot;&gt;(Amherst, 2020; UMassAmherst, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. Inquiring into one’s area of specialization will highlight which areas of the law may be associated with a need to speak multiple languages; more specifically, which areas of the law in Saint Lucia, are more likely to require an understanding of Saint Lucian Kwéyòl language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;7. Please indicate your areas of practice; please check all that apply.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specialty Options: Alternative dispute resolution (ADR), Banking and Finance law, Citizenship by investment, Commercial law, Constitutional law, Construction law, Contract law, Corporate law, Criminal law, Employment law, Environmental law, Equity and trusts, EU law*, Family law, Human rights law, Insurance law, Intellectual property (IP) law, Land law, Litigation, Media law, Private client law, Property law, Public law, Shipping law, Sports law, Tax law, Tort law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An additional means of narrowing down underlying multilinguistic tendencies in this field is to inquire into one’s areas of practice. St. Lucia is a sovereign island nation in the Commonwealth of Nations, but because Saint Lucia was both a French and English colony before it gained independence on February 22nd, 1979, the legal system has been a mix of civil and English common law &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#specialitysmith_2020&quot;&gt;(FSU, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. This complexity allows for multiple law specialties for a local Saint Lucian market, as well as abroad; thusly, increasing the possibility of encountering non-English speakers as clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;8. Please indicate your average annual income.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Options: Below 36,000 XCD; 36,001 XCD - 46,000 XCD; 46,001 XCD - 56,000 XCD; 56,001 XCD - 66,000 XCD; 66,001 XCD - 76,000 XCD; 76,001 XCD - 86, 000 XCD; 86,001 XCD - 96, 000 XCD; 96,001 XCD - 106, 000 XCD; Above 106,001 XCD; Choose not to respond&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on one’s average salary per case, there could be an argument for the economic reinforcement of certain linguistic standards. It may be interesting to note if multilingual able to request and acquire more money due to their linguistic abilities. The Average Attorney Salary of a lawyer located in the sister island country of Dominica is around 2,950 XCD per month &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#DOMsalary&quot;&gt;(salaryexplorer.com, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. It has been said that salaries range from 1,360 XCD (lowest) to 4,680 XCD (highest). Yet, according to salaryexplorer.com, a Saint Lucian Attorney typically earns around 5,500 XCD per month; this is with salaries ranging from 2,530 XCD (lowest) to 8,750 XCD (highest). It should be noted that Saint Lucia’s minimum wage rate was last changed at the beginning of 2013, yet it stands at XCD 300 a month for office clerks, XCD 200 for shop assistants, and XCD 160 for messengers according to minimum-wage.org &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#SLU2020wages&quot;&gt;(minimum-wage.org, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;9. Please indicate your current student debt level.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Options: None; Below 36,000 XCD; 36,001 XCD - 46,000 XCD; 46,001 XCD - 56,000 XCD; 56,001 XCD - 66,000 XCD; 66,001 XCD - 76,000 XCD; 76,001 XCD - 86, 000 XCD; 86,001 XCD - 96, 000 XCD; 96,001 XCD - 106, 000 XCD; Above 106,001 XCD; Choose not to respond&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consideration was given to the fact that student debt may be a confounding variable to multilingualism. For example, some individuals may be deterred from pursuing optional formal language courses as this may incur additional debt. To account for this variable a question concerning student debt was included. The inclusion is supported by the ABA, as it too gathers such data &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#aba_2020&quot;&gt;(ABA, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;; moreover, this data can also be utilized to better monitor the legal field like simply observing educational cost trends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;10. Please indicate if a perceived language barrier has ever limited any of your attorney-client interactions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Options: Yes; No; Choose not to respond&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This question seeks to explore the personal linguistic limitations of lawyers in a multilingual environment, and if multilingual clients are having their needs met by the current environment. It may reveal if there have been any issues with legal representation on the island. If there are, the findings may reinforce the negative impact of a lack of multilingual lawyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;11. Please indicate if a perceived language barrier has ever limited any of your attorney-client interactions with Saint Lucian Kwéyòl speakers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Options: Yes; No; Choose not to respond&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This question seeks to garner specific details on language barriers; it attempts to explore the boundaries of fluency that a lawyer may encounter specifically when attempting to represent local Saint Lucian Kwéyòl (Antillean Creole/Patios) speaking clients. It is a heritage language and is said to be the second most spoken language on the island. Reduced language barriers would allow lawyers to better relay facts, arguments, and sentiments of clients with the distinct Kwéyòl (Antillean Creole/Patios) speaking background. This may establish if there is or is not a need for lawyers to acquire that particular language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;12. Please indicate if your workplace offers any formal foreign language assistance programs to support linguistic diversity in clients.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Options: Yes, an internal service available to clients.; No, an external service would be recommended (for example, a court-appointed interpreter).; Choose not to respond&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This question is to simply assess the resources available to lawyers provided by their workplaces. If there is a substantial foreign language assistance support system already in existence, this could also suggest that the industry has considered the connection of linguistics to the legal field and effectively addressed it. This question may be flawed since it could be one large firm that provides such language assistance services, rather than the entire industry; however, one could argue that based on a favorable overall total percentage of participation, this could still have a positive reflection on the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;13. If you do speak more than one language, please indicate if your multilingual skill was ever crucial to representing a client.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Options: I do not speak more than one language; Yes; No; Choose not to respond&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This question seeks to investigate the demand for multilingualism in lawyering, based on experienced demand. These details may reveal sufficiencies as well as insufficiencies concerning the adequate legal representation of Saint Lucian clients. Saint Lucia is a multilingual country, and so a lawyer capable of speaking multiple languages would be better able to relay facts, arguments, and sentiments of clients with diverse backgrounds. Such lawyers, with reduced language barriers, would benefit from attracting a broader and more diverse client base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;14. Where applicable, please rank the languages you use most often to communicate within your household. This question only requires one response per row (ties in rankings can be indicated).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Column Titles: 1st language (most often used); 2nd language (second most often used); 3rd language (third most often used); N/A; Choose not to respond&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Row Titles: English; Saint Lucian Kwéyòl (Antillean Creole/Patios); Haitian Creole; French; Spanish; Papiamento; Portuguese; Dutch; Hindi (or any Indian subcontinental language not listed); Arabic (or any Mediterranean language not listed); Swahili (or any African language not listed); Russian (or any Eurasian language not listed); Japanese; Mandarin; Any form of sign language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This question is one of the most crucial to this study as this may signify a Saint Lucian lawyer’s mother tongue, or L1 &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#posel2016language&quot;&gt;(Posel &amp;amp; Zeller, 2016)&lt;/a&gt;. The ranking is necessary to note each language’s dominance  &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#uscb_2020&quot;&gt;(USCB, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. To limit participant fatigue and simplify data analysis, the rank is limited to three main language options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While English is a prestige language in Saint Lucia &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#hilaire2008postcolonialism&quot;&gt;(Hilaire, 2008; Irvine, 2020; Midgett, 1970; St-Hilaire, 2011)&lt;/a&gt;, it is indeed a multilingual country. Therefore, assumptions cannot be made as to one’s full competencies of English; indeed one may have been hired based on being a native speaker of another language, or a variety of other scenarios. Yet, the form will only be presented in English; this is because a certain degree of its competency is required of professionals that practice in Saint Lucia (and most legal documents are indeed written in English).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notably, apart from modern English, legal (and medical) professionals can claim to be multilingual, based on their foundational studies of Latin. Latin has been declared a dead language, and its inclusion would indeed seem redundant, as the field already recognizes this knowledge. Questioning one’s fluency in Latin may also spark negative feelings from participants, as the language is intrinsically linked to the mastery of their profession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saint Lucian Kwéyòl (Antillean Creole/Patios) is inquired about, as it is the heritage language of the island &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#midgett1970bilingualism&quot;&gt;(Midgett, 1970)&lt;/a&gt;. While a language vitality survey has not been conducted since 1946 &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#irvine2020language&quot;&gt;(Irvine, 2020; Hilaire, 2008; St-Hilaire, 2011)&lt;/a&gt;, most leading language authorities, including “Ethnologue”, assume that the language is not in a threatened or endangered state &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#irvine2020language&quot;&gt;(Irvine, 2020; Ethnologue, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;; the last records indicate that the majority of the Saint Lucian population are “bilingual in English and  &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#mitchell2009st&quot;&gt;(Mitchell, 2009)&lt;/a&gt;. It stands to reason that law practitioners on the island may have encountered or have had to represent speakers of this language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haitian Creole is another heritage language of the Caribbean, that has been recognized as the official language of Haiti via a constitutional change, and is currently being formally regulated by &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#macedo2019decolonizing&quot;&gt;(Macedo, 2019)&lt;/a&gt;. There has been a long legal struggle to have it fully recognized as part of the island’s standard education; especially on the island of Haiti &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#kuhn2019haiti&quot;&gt;(Kuhn, 2019; DeGraff, 2016; Brown-Blake, 2014)&lt;/a&gt;. There is evidence to support the fact that several legal professionals, from the Caribbean and abroad, have interacted with Haitian Creole speakers, particularly to assist with disaster relief services &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#lacet_haiti2012trauma&quot;&gt;(Lacet, 2012; O’Brien &amp;amp; Federici, 2019)&lt;/a&gt;. Haitian Creole was, therefore, added to reduce any possible confusion with the classification of Haitian Creole as Saint Lucian Kwéyòl. To further reduce confusion surrounding the creole languages of the Caribbean, Papiamento was acknowledged with a designated option &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#brown_legal_change2014expanding&quot;&gt;(Brown-Blake, 2014)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The French and Spanish languages were included on this list as these are typical education offerings of all high schools on the island of Saint Lucia &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#irvine2020language&quot;&gt;(Irvine, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. These languages reflect the general Caribbean environment, as several countries recognize and teach French and Spanish as their prestige languages; this includes countries such as Martinique and Guadeloupe, and Cuba, respectively. Dutch, Portuguese, and to a lesser extent Hindi (or any other Indian subcontinental language), are other common languages to the rest of the Caribbean due to colonialization and indentured labor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;African, Arabic, and other immigrants from the Mediterranean region do have a strong presence in the Saint Lucian business environment, and therefore, may have needed for legal representation on the island &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#hillman2009understanding&quot;&gt;(Hillman &amp;amp; D’Agostino, 2009; “Saint Lucia,” n.d.; Posel &amp;amp; Zeller, 2016)&lt;/a&gt;. Japanese is taught in Saint Lucia by humanitarian volunteers as part of their Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA) work &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#kobayashi_2020&quot;&gt;(Kobayashi, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. Due to an increased presence of Chinese investors and tourists in the Caribbean, and general funding of local projects by China, one’s ability to understand Mandarin is becoming increasingly valuable &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#rstc_Pearl2019&quot;&gt;(RSTC, 2019; Reynolds, n.d.)&lt;/a&gt;. Once again these immigrants may have had needed legal representation on the island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that Saint Lucia has established a system for CIP &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#bayat_2020&quot;&gt;(Bayat &amp;amp; El Hachem, 2020; GIS, 2017; CIP, 2020; Capital, 2020; Harvey, 2020; Visa, 2016)&lt;/a&gt;. Local lawyers that practice in this area have a greater probability of interacting with persons from various parts of the world; particularly interacting with persons from areas that had no prior historic (colonial) immigration or language ties to the country. Persons from Russia, Asia, and the Middle East have been noted as having increasingly high rates of interest in the CIP programs of the Caribbean &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#nesheim_CIP_2020&quot;&gt;(Nesheim, 2020; CBF, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. The creation of the additional categories, including any form of sign language, was developed to best encapsulate as many interaction scenarios as possible &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#parks_williams_Signlang2011&quot;&gt;(Parks &amp;amp; Williams, 2011; Posel &amp;amp; Zeller, 2016)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;15. Please indicate your proficiency in speaking, reading, writing, and or listening (understanding) the following languages. This question requires at least one response per row. Note: Selecting only “listening (understanding)” encompasses scenarios where one can comprehend but not converse in a language.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Column Titles: Speak; Write; Read; Listen (Understand); N/A; Choose not to respond&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Row Titles: English; Saint Lucian Kwéyòl (Antillean Creole/Patios); Haitian Creole; French; Spanish; Papiamento; Portuguese; Dutch; Hindi (or any Indian subcontinental language not listed); Arabic (or any Mediterranean language not listed); Swahili (or any African language not listed); Russian (or any Eurasian language not listed); Japanese; Mandarin; Any form of sign language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This question is related to determining linguistic proficiency. Row titles will remain the same based on the aforementioned logic on the participant pool. The column category “Listen (Understand)” was added to account for the possible occurrence of asymmetrical bilingualism, receptive bilingualism, non-accommodating bilingualism, among lawyers in the Caribbean &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#thomas2018degree&quot;&gt;(Thomas-Sunesson et al., 2018; Luk &amp;amp; Bialystok, 2013; Woolard, 2004; Bilaniuk, 2010)&lt;/a&gt;. This consideration is valid as multilingualism is prevalent in this region; persons here may encounter various languages, yet have been unable to effectively respond. The presence of a prestige language, such as English, may draw speakers away from heritage languages; these heritage languages can suffer from dropping numbers of speakers when the identification of receptive bilingualism is not followed up with focused efforts. However, I am also currently considering proficiency column items of  “don’t speak or understand; understand some and speak none; understand some and speak some; understand well and speak some; understand well and speak fluently; N/A” &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#marmion2014community&quot;&gt;(Marmion et al., 2014)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;16. Please indicate your level of fluency in the languages listed below. This question requires only one response per row.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Column Titles: Highly fluent; Fluent; Some mastery; A little mastery; Not at all; Choose not to respond&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Row Titles: English; Saint Lucian Kwéyòl (Antillean Creole/Patios); Haitian Creole; French; Spanish; Papiamento; Portuguese; Dutch; Any form of sign language; Hindi (or any Indian subcontinental language not listed); Any form of sign language; Arabic (or any Mediterranean language not listed); Swahili (or any African language not listed); Russian (or any Eurasian language not listed); Japanese; Mandarin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This question is related to determining linguistic fluency. Row titles will remain the same based on the aforementioned logic on the participant pool. Rankings of “Highly fluent; Fluent; Some mastery; A little mastery; Not” at all were selected as a simple means of classifying fluency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;17. Please indicate which technique best describes how you came to learn each of the following languages. This question requires at least one response per row.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Column Titles: Formal education (requirement); Formal education (elective); Informal education (hobby); Informal education (from family &amp;amp; friends); N/A (I do not use this language); Choose not to respond&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Row Titles: English; Saint Lucian Kwéyòl (Antillean Creole/Patios); Haitian Creole; French; Spanish; Papiamento; Portuguese; Dutch; Any form of sign language; Hindi (or any Indian subcontinental language not listed); Any form of sign language; Arabic (or any Mediterranean language not listed); Swahili (or any African language not listed); Russian (or any Eurasian language not listed); Japanese; Mandarin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding where and how one engages in language learning might highlight environments that foster multilingualism in lawyers. The learning of certain languages may take place in formal and informal settings. In Saint Lucia, it is highly likely that most language education would be done in a formal school setting. Overall, the national heritage language of this island would typically be learned informally &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#carrington1988creole&quot;&gt;(Carrington, 1988; Charlemange, 2017; UNESCO, 2017)&lt;/a&gt;. Saint Lucian Kwéyòl only recently began being formally taught to young children (between the ages of 6-12) in less than a handful of schools or during the observation of cultural celebrations &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#oas_2018&quot;&gt;(OAS, 2018; Anthony, 2017)&lt;/a&gt; and paid private sessions for adult learners. However, since the major fire at the National Folk Resource Center, most classes, if offered at all, have reverted to more private sessions &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#slu_news_online_2019&quot;&gt;(Online, 2019; DBS, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. Formal Kwéyòl course offerings from a Saint Lucian higher education institution during 2020, failed to materialize &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#salcc_2020&quot;&gt;(SALCC, 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. Row titles will remain the same based on the aforementioned logic on the participant pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;18. Please indicate which language frequency category best reflects your typical client interactions. This question only requires one response per row.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Column Titles: Very Frequently; Frequently; Occasionally; Rarely; Very Rarely; Never; Choose not to respond&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Row Titles: English; Saint Lucian Kwéyòl (Antillean Creole/Patios); Haitian Creole; French; Spanish; Papiamento; Portuguese; Dutch; Any form of sign language; Hindi (or any Indian subcontinental language not listed); Any form of sign language; Arabic (or any Mediterranean language not listed); Swahili (or any African language not listed); Russian (or any Eurasian language not listed); Japanese; Mandarin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since this survey is unable to acquire data from past clients, this question serves to address the languages that lawyers commonly encounter. The language one typically speaks is not guaranteed to be a client’s mother tongue. It will be interesting to note where the client and lawyer languages overlap, and where they do not; this question may detect possible deficiencies in language assistance resources within this field. Row titles will remain the same based on the aforementioned logic on the participant pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;future-studies&quot;&gt;Future studies:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, such a survey can be applied to various underdeveloped legal environments; potential survey pools can include the legal associations of other developing countries or regional associations (such as the Caribbean Bar Association ) &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#cba_2012&quot;&gt;(CBA, 2012)&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally, other occupations around Saint Lucia can be targeted as potential survey pools; they could produce a better understanding of language assistance services island-wide. Health care workers, fire departments, and even law enforcement services such as police officers and security services may benefit from the data provided by such a study; any profession that requires direct extended interaction with citizens, when providing a sense of safety and security, may benefit from such studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional (possibly future) studies may include an investigation into the existence of inmate metrics; particularly linguistic data. This would encompass an investigation of the rates of incarceration of predominantly Saint Lucian Kwéyòl language speakers. Further investigation could be conducted on linguistics, crime, and domicile data; criminal household location data (per district), paired with linguistic data could dispel or reinforce one popular belief that most Saint Lucian Kwéyòl language speakers are located in the Southern part of the country (and therefore are more unruly and prone to crime) &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#carrington1988creole&quot;&gt;(Carrington, 1988)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;maslow_1943_2000&quot;&gt;Maslow, A. H. (1943). Theory of Human Motivation : Psychological Review. In &lt;i&gt;Classics in the History of Psychology: A Theory of Human Motivation&lt;/i&gt;. Christopher D. Green of York University, Toronto, Ontario . https://psychclassics.yorku.ca/Maslow/motivation.htm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;matias2020human&quot;&gt;Matias, T., Dominski, F. H., &amp;amp; Marks, D. F. (2020). &lt;i&gt;Human needs in COVID-19 isolation&lt;/i&gt;. SAGE Publications Sage UK: London, England. https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/1359105320925149&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;wong2020healing&quot;&gt;Wong, A. H., Pacella-LaBarbara, M. L., Ray, J. M., Ranney, M. L., &amp;amp; Chang, B. P. (2020). Healing the Healer: Protecting Emergency Health Care Workers’ Mental Health During COVID-19. &lt;i&gt;Annals of Emergency Medicine&lt;/i&gt;. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7196406/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;casale2020interpersonally&quot;&gt;Casale, S., &amp;amp; Flett, G. L. (2020). Interpersonally-based fears during the COVID-19 pandemic: Reflections on the fear of missing out and the fear of not mattering constructs. &lt;i&gt;Clinical Neuropsychiatry&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;17&lt;/i&gt;(2), 88–93. https://doi.org/10.36131/CN20200211&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;diener2011happiness&quot;&gt;Diener, E., &amp;amp; Biswas-Diener, R. (2011). &lt;i&gt;Happiness: Unlocking the mysteries of psychological wealth&lt;/i&gt;. John Wiley &amp;amp; Sons.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;mattmann2013vision&quot;&gt;Mattmann, C. A. (2013). A vision for data science. &lt;i&gt;Nature&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;493&lt;/i&gt;(7433), 473–475.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;patriksson2019health&quot;&gt;Patriksson, K., Wigert, H., Berg, M., &amp;amp; Nilsson, S. (2019). Health care professional’s communication through an interpreter where language barriers exist in neonatal care: a national study. &lt;i&gt;BMC Health Services Research&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;19&lt;/i&gt;(1), 586. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12913-019-4428-z&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;sevilla2013communication&quot;&gt;Sevilla, C., Wieslander, C. K., Alas, A. N., Dunivan, G. C., Khan, A. A., Maliski, S. L., Rogers, R. G., &amp;amp; Anger, J. T. (2013). Communication between physicians and Spanish-speaking Latin American women with pelvic floor disorders: a cycle of misunderstanding? &lt;i&gt;Female Pelvic Medicine &amp;amp; Reconstructive Surgery&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;19&lt;/i&gt;(2), 90.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;simon2013perceptions&quot;&gt;Simon, M. A., Ragas, D. M., Nonzee, N. J., Phisuthikul, A. M., Luu, T. H., &amp;amp; Dong, X. Q. (2013). Perceptions of patient-provider communication in breast and cervical cancer-related care: a qualitative study of low-income English-and Spanish-speaking women. &lt;i&gt;Journal of Community Health&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;38&lt;/i&gt;(4), 707–715. https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1007/s10900-013-9668-y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;napoles2009developing&quot;&gt;Nápoles-Springer, A. M., Ortı́z Carmen, O’Brien, H., &amp;amp; Dı́az-Méndez Marynieves. (2009). Developing a culturally competent peer support intervention for Spanish-speaking Latinas with breast cancer. &lt;i&gt;Journal of Immigrant and Minority Health&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;11&lt;/i&gt;(4), 268. https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1007/s10903-008-9128-4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;verdinelli2009spanish&quot;&gt;Verdinelli, S., &amp;amp; Biever, J. L. (2009). Spanish–English bilingual psychotherapists: Personal and professional language development and use. &lt;i&gt;Cultural Diversity and Ethnic Minority Psychology&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;15&lt;/i&gt;(3), 230.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;elderkin2001nurses&quot;&gt;Elderkin-Thompson, V., Silver, R. C., &amp;amp; Waitzkin, H. (2001). When nurses double as interpreters: a study of Spanish-speaking patients in a US primary care setting. &lt;i&gt;Social Science &amp;amp; Medicine&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;52&lt;/i&gt;(9), 1343–1358. https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1016/S0277-9536(00)00234-3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;olivares_washington_ICE2020&quot;&gt;Olivares, J., &amp;amp; Washington, J. (2020). &quot;He Just Empties You All Out&quot;: Whistleblower Reports High Number of Hysterectomies at ICE Detention Facility. In &lt;i&gt;The Intercept&lt;/i&gt;. https://theintercept.com/2020/09/15/hysterectomies-ice-irwin-whistleblower/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;treisman_ICE2020&quot;&gt;Treisman, R. (2020). Whistleblower Alleges ’Medical Neglect,’ Questionable Hysterectomies Of ICE Detainees. In &lt;i&gt;NPR&lt;/i&gt;. NPR. https://www.npr.org/2020/09/16/913398383/whistleblower-alleges-medical-neglect-questionable-hysterectomies-of-ice-detaine?t=1600292028800&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;bbc_ICE2020&quot;&gt;BBC. (2020). ICE whistleblower: Nurse alleges ’hysterectomies on immigrant women in US.’ In &lt;i&gt;BBC News&lt;/i&gt;. BBC. https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-54160638&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;cassady_ICE2020&quot;&gt;Cassady, D. (2020). Whistleblower Alleges Medical Negligence, Unnecessary Hysterectomies At Georgia ICE Facility. In &lt;i&gt;Forbes&lt;/i&gt;. Forbes Magazine. https://www.forbes.com/sites/danielcassady/2020/09/15/whistleblower-alleges-medical-negligence-unnecessary-hysterectomies-at-georgia-ice-facility/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;lambe_ICE2020&quot;&gt;Lambe, J. (2020). ’Like an Experimental Concentration Camp’: Whistleblower Complaint Alleges Mass Hysterectomies at ICE Detention Center. In &lt;i&gt;Whistleblower: There Were Mass Hysterectomies at ICE Facility | Law &amp;amp; Crime&lt;/i&gt;. Law &amp;amp; Crime. https://lawandcrime.com/high-profile/like-an-experimental-concentration-camp-whistleblower-complaint-alleges-mass-hysterectomies-at-ice-detention-center/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ahmed_2015&quot;&gt;Ahmed, Y. (2015). The case for foreign languages as an aspiring lawyer. In &lt;i&gt;The Guardian&lt;/i&gt;. Guardian News and Media. https://www.theguardian.com/law/2015/jul/07/the-case-for-foreign-languages-as-an-aspiring-lawyer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;sajo1993role&quot;&gt;Sajo, A. (1993). The role of lawyers in social change: Hungary. &lt;i&gt;Case W. Res. J. Int’l L.&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;25&lt;/i&gt;, 137.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;umassamherst_politics_2020&quot;&gt;UMassAmherst. (2020). UMass Amherst Pre-Law Advising Office. In &lt;i&gt;Politics : What legal careers are available? : UMass Amherst Pre-Law Advising Office&lt;/i&gt;. University of Massachusetts Amherst. http://prelaw.umass.edu/topics/politics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;brown_legal_change2014expanding&quot;&gt;Brown-Blake, C. (2014). Expanding the use of non-dominant Caribbean languages: Can the law help? &lt;i&gt;International Journal of Speech, Language &amp;amp; the Law&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;21&lt;/i&gt;(1).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;bayat_2020&quot;&gt;Bayat, S. M., &amp;amp; El Hachem, H. (2020). Saint Lucia - The Corporate Immigration Review - Edition 10 - TLR. In &lt;i&gt;The Law Reviews&lt;/i&gt;. The Law Reviews. https://thelawreviews.co.uk/edition/the-corporate-immigration-review-edition-10/1227321/st-lucia&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;gis_CIP_2017&quot;&gt;GIS. (2017). Chamber discusses CIP changes. In &lt;i&gt;Saint Lucia - Access Government&lt;/i&gt;. GIS. http://www.govt.lc/news/chamber-discusses-cip-changes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;slu_cip_2020&quot;&gt;CIP, S. L. (2020). CIP FAQs. In &lt;i&gt;Citizenship By Investment&lt;/i&gt;. cipsaintlucia.com. https://www.cipsaintlucia.com/faqs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;capital_CIP_2020&quot;&gt;Capital, A. (2020). Saint Lucia Citizenship by Investment - Your 2nd Passport. In &lt;i&gt;Arton Capital&lt;/i&gt;. Arton Capital. https://www.artoncapital.com/global-citizen-programs/saint-lucia/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;harvey_2020&quot;&gt;Harvey, L. G. (2020). Saint Lucia Citizenship By Investment Program (CIP): HLG. In &lt;i&gt;Harvey Law Group - World’s Leading Law Firm in Business Law, Investment Immigration, Citizenship-By-Investment, Residency-By-Investment&lt;/i&gt;. Harvey Law Group. https://www.harveylawcorporation.com/saint-lucia/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;investvisa_2016&quot;&gt;Visa, I. (2016). CIP Restructuring In Progress for Saint Lucia. In &lt;i&gt;Qicms- Saint Lucia CIP Restructuring | Citizenship by Investment&lt;/i&gt;. invest-visa. https://www.invest-visa.com/Post/240231/Immigration-News/CIP-Restructuring-InProgress-for-Saint-Lucia&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;hillman2009understanding&quot;&gt;Hillman, R. S., &amp;amp; D’Agostino, T. J. (2009). &lt;i&gt;Understanding the contemporary Caribbean&lt;/i&gt;. Lynne Rienner Publishers BoulderLondon. https://www.rienner.com/uploads/4a48e971d622c.pdf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;everyculture_2020&quot;&gt;Saint Lucia. In &lt;i&gt;Countries and Their Cultures&lt;/i&gt;. https://www.everyculture.com/No-Sa/Saint-Lucia.html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;kobayashi_2020&quot;&gt;Kobayashi, T. (2020). Message from the Chief Representative. In &lt;i&gt;JICA&lt;/i&gt;. https://www.jica.go.jp/stlucia/english/office/about/message.html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;nesheim_CIP_2020&quot;&gt;Nesheim, C. H. (2020). The Saint Lucia Citizenship by Investment Programme. In &lt;i&gt;Investment Migration Insider&lt;/i&gt;. Investment Migration Insider. https://www.imidaily.com/the-saint-lucia-citizenship-by-investment-programme/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;CBF_2020&quot;&gt;CBF. (2020). Saint Lucia Presents a New CIP-Project. In &lt;i&gt;Cross Border Freedom&lt;/i&gt;. CBF. https://www.crossborderfreedom.com/saint-lucia-presents-a-new-cip-project/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;slu_1978&quot;&gt;SLU. (1978). Our Government - Constitution of Saint Lucia. In &lt;i&gt;Saint Lucia - Access Government&lt;/i&gt;. govt.lc. http://www.govt.lc/constitution1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;SLU_legalaid_2015&quot;&gt;Digital, V. P. (2015). Legal Aid In St. Lucia. In &lt;i&gt;St. Lucia News From The Voice St. Lucia&lt;/i&gt;. thevoiceslu.com. https://www.thevoiceslu.com/2015/01/legal-aid-st-lucia/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;emmanuel_legalaid2001&quot;&gt;Emmanuel, J. (2001). OECS Supreme Court Supports Set-up of Legal Aid Services. In &lt;i&gt;Saint Lucia - Access Government&lt;/i&gt;. govt.lc/news. http://www.govt.lc/news/oecs-supreme-court-supports-set-up-of-legal-aid-services&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;satney_legalaid2007&quot;&gt;Satney, C. (2007). Legal Aid Becoming a Reality in Saint Lucia. In &lt;i&gt;Saint Lucia - Access Government&lt;/i&gt;. govt.lc/news. http://www.govt.lc/news/legal-aid-becoming-a-reality-in-saint-lucia&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;gaillard_SLULAW_2020&quot;&gt;Gaillard, S. (2020). Disciplinary action to be taken against several St Lucian lawyers. In &lt;i&gt;loopslu.com&lt;/i&gt;. loopslu.com. http://www.loopslu.com/content/disciplinary-action-be-taken-against-several-saint-lucian-lawyers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;midgett1970bilingualism&quot;&gt;Midgett, D. (1970). Bilingualism and linguistic change in St. Lucia. &lt;i&gt;Anthropological Linguistics&lt;/i&gt;, 158–170. https://www.jstor.org/stable/30029245?seq=1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;marmion2014community&quot;&gt;Marmion, D., Obata, K., &amp;amp; Troy, J. (2014). &lt;i&gt;Community, identity, wellbeing: the report of the Second National Indigenous Languages Survey&lt;/i&gt;. Australian Institute of Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Studies Canberra.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;kabir_dennerysegment2020creolization&quot;&gt;Kabir, A. J. (2020). Creolization as balancing act in the transoceanic quadrille: Choreogenesis, incorporation, memory, market. &lt;i&gt;Atlantic Studies&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;17&lt;/i&gt;(1), 135–157.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;oas_2018&quot;&gt;OAS. (2018). Organization of American States: Democracy for peace, security, and development. In &lt;i&gt;OAS&lt;/i&gt;. Organization of Eastern Caribbean States Commission represented by St. Lucia and the Innoved Uniq, Quisqueya University, Haiti. https://www.oas.org/cotep/LibraryDetails.aspx?lang=en&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;BLS2020&quot;&gt;BLS. (2020). Lawyers : Occupational Outlook Handbook. In &lt;i&gt;U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics&lt;/i&gt;. U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics. https://www.bls.gov/ooh/legal/lawyers.htm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;aba_2020&quot;&gt;ABA. (2020). In &lt;i&gt;About the American Bar Association&lt;/i&gt;. americanbar.org. https://www.americanbar.org/about_the_aba/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;govtSLU_NEIS_2019&quot;&gt;govt.lc. (2019). National Environmental Information System (NEIS): Saint Lucia Open Data. In &lt;i&gt;National Environmental Information System (NEIS) | Saint Lucia Open Data&lt;/i&gt;. https://data.govt.lc/dataset/national-environmental-information-system-neis&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;govtSLU_NEIS&quot;&gt;neis.govt.lc. (2020). In &lt;i&gt;Saint Lucia NEIS&lt;/i&gt;. https://www.neis.govt.lc/#/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;govtSLUdata&quot;&gt;govt.lc. (2020). Search: Saint Lucia Open Data. In &lt;i&gt;Search | Saint Lucia Open Data&lt;/i&gt;. https://data.govt.lc/search/type/dataset&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;st.rose_information_2020&quot;&gt;St.Rose, R. (2020). In &lt;i&gt;Student request for information&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;mendes-franco_2020&quot;&gt;Mendes-Franco, J. (2020). ’Linguistics is in everything’ from astronomy to everyday life, says this linguist from Trinidad &amp;amp; Tobago · Global Voices. In &lt;i&gt;Global Voices&lt;/i&gt;. https://globalvoices.org/2020/03/13/linguistics-is-in-everything-from-astronomy-to-everyday-life-says-this-linguist-from-trinidad-tobago/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;george_2020&quot;&gt;George, M. (2020). Musical Chairs in the Senate. In &lt;i&gt;St. Lucia News From The Voice St. Lucia&lt;/i&gt;. thevoiceslu.com. https://www.thevoiceslu.com/2020/10/musical-chairs-in-the-senate/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;st.rose_followup_2020&quot;&gt;St.Rose, R. (2020). In &lt;i&gt;Student request for information- followup&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;surveymonkey_2020&quot;&gt;SurveyMonkey. (2020). Account Response Limits. In &lt;i&gt;SurveyMonkey Help Center&lt;/i&gt;. SurveyMonkey . https://help.surveymonkey.com/articles/en_US/kb/Billable-Responses&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;stecklov2018can&quot;&gt;Stecklov, G., Weinreb, A., &amp;amp; Carletto, C. (2018). Can incentives improve survey data quality in developing countries?: results from a field experiment in India. &lt;i&gt;Journal of the Royal Statistical Society: Series A (Statistics in Society)&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;181&lt;/i&gt;(4), 1033–1056. https://doi.org/10.1111/rssa.12333&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;luk2013bilingualism&quot;&gt;Luk, G., &amp;amp; Bialystok, E. (2013). Bilingualism is not a categorical variable: Interaction between language proficiency and usage. &lt;i&gt;Journal of Cognitive Psychology&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;25&lt;/i&gt;(5), 605–621.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;suhr2006exploratory&quot;&gt;Suhr, D. D. (2006). &lt;i&gt;Exploratory or confirmatory factor analysis?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ABA2020Profile&quot;&gt;Association, A. B. (2020). ABA Profile of the Legal Profession. In &lt;i&gt;American Bar Association&lt;/i&gt;. https://www.americanbar.org/news/reporter_resources/profile-of-profession/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;clio_2020&quot;&gt;Clio. (2020). The 2018 Legal Trends Report. In &lt;i&gt;Clio&lt;/i&gt;. https://www.clio.com/resources/legal-trends/2018-report/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;AttorneyAtWork_2019&quot;&gt;Ernde, L. (2019). Five Ways the Legal Profession Is Changing, But Slowly. In &lt;i&gt;Attorney at Work&lt;/i&gt;. https://www.attorneyatwork.com/five-ways-the-legal-profession-is-changing-but-slowly/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;van2015gender&quot;&gt;Van Der Slik, F. W. P., Van Hout, R. W. N. M., &amp;amp; Schepens, J. J. (2015). The gender gap in second language acquisition: Gender differences in the acquisition of Dutch among immigrants from 88 countries with 49 mother tongues. &lt;i&gt;PloS One&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;10&lt;/i&gt;(11), e0142056.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;CSO_SLU2010&quot;&gt;CSO. (2020). UNECLAC-CELADE::Redatam Webserver: Statistical Process and Dissemination Tool. In &lt;i&gt;UNECLAC-CELADE::Redatam Webserver | Statistical Process and Dissemination Tool&lt;/i&gt;. CSO St.Lucia - The Central Statistics Office, Government of St.Lucia. https://redatam.org/binlca/RpWebEngine.exe/Portal?BASE=PHC2010C&amp;amp;lang=ENG&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;umassamherst_general2020&quot;&gt;Amherst, U. M. (2020). UMass Amherst Pre-Law Advising Office. In &lt;i&gt;What legal careers are available? : UMass Amherst Pre-Law Advising Office&lt;/i&gt;. University of Massachusetts Amherst. http://prelaw.umass.edu/topics/category/what_legal_careers_are_available&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;umassamherst_special_2020&quot;&gt;UMassAmherst. (2020). UMass Amherst Pre-Law Advising Office. In &lt;i&gt;Private practice vs. public service/public interest : What legal careers are available? : UMass Amherst Pre-Law Advising Office&lt;/i&gt;. University of Massachusetts Amherst . http://prelaw.umass.edu/topics/private_vs_public&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;specialitysmith_2020&quot;&gt;FSU. (2020). Commonwealth Caribbean Law Research Guide: St. Lucia. In &lt;i&gt;Research Guides&lt;/i&gt;. Florida State University. https://guides.law.fsu.edu/caribbean/stlucia&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;DOMsalary&quot;&gt;salaryexplorer.com. (2020). Attorney Average Salary in Dominica 2020. In &lt;i&gt;The Complete Guide&lt;/i&gt;. http://www.salaryexplorer.com/salary-survey.php?loc=60&amp;amp;loctype=1&amp;amp;job=513&amp;amp;jobtype=3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;SLU2020wages&quot;&gt;minimum-wage.org. (2020). Saint Lucia Minimum Wage Rate 2020. In &lt;i&gt;Federal and State Minimum Wage Rates for 2020&lt;/i&gt;. https://www.minimum-wage.org/international/saint-lucia&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;posel2016language&quot;&gt;Posel, D., &amp;amp; Zeller, J. (2016). Language shift or increased bilingualism in South Africa: evidence from census data. &lt;i&gt;Journal of Multilingual and Multicultural Development&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;37&lt;/i&gt;(4), 357–370. https://doi.org/10.1080/01434632.2015.1072206&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;uscb_2020&quot;&gt;USCB. (2020). Why We Ask About...Language Spokent at Home. In &lt;i&gt;Why We Ask About...Language Spokent at Home | American Community Survey | US Census Bureau&lt;/i&gt;. US Census Bureau. https://www.census.gov/acs/www/about/why-we-ask-each-question/language/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;hilaire2008postcolonialism&quot;&gt;Hilaire, A. S. (2008). Postcolonialism, identity, and the French language in St. Lucia. &lt;i&gt;New West Indian Guide/Nieuwe West-Indische Gids&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;81&lt;/i&gt;(1-2), 55–77.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;irvine2020language&quot;&gt;Irvine, M. (2020). &lt;i&gt;Language contact in St. Lucia: The features and origins of St. Lucia Creole English&lt;/i&gt; [PhD thesis]. ResearchSpace@ Auckland.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;hilaire2011kweyol&quot;&gt;St-Hilaire, A. (2011). &lt;i&gt;Kwéyòl in postcolonial Saint Lucia: Globalization, language planning, and national development&lt;/i&gt; (Vol. 40). John Benjamins Publishing. https://www.jbe-platform.com/content/books/9789027284648&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ethnologue_2020&quot;&gt;Ethnologue. (2020). Size and vitality of Saint Lucian Creole French. In &lt;i&gt;Ethnologue&lt;/i&gt;. Ethnologue. https://www.ethnologue.com/size-and-vitality/acf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;mitchell2009st&quot;&gt;Mitchell, E. S. (2009). &lt;i&gt;St. Lucian Kwéyòl in St. Croix: A study of language choice and attitudes&lt;/i&gt;. University of Puerto Rico, Rio Piedras (Puerto Rico).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;macedo2019decolonizing&quot;&gt;Macedo, D. (2019). &lt;i&gt;Decolonizing foreign language education: The misteaching of English and other colonial languages&lt;/i&gt;. Routledge.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;kuhn2019haiti&quot;&gt;Kuhn, A. (2019). Haiti and Creole: The Violation of Human Rights in Education. &lt;i&gt;Columbia Journal of Transnational Law&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;58&lt;/i&gt;. https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3394894&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;degraff2016mother&quot;&gt;DeGraff, M. (2016). Mother-tongue books in Haiti: The power of Kreyòl in learning to read and in reading to learn. &lt;i&gt;Prospects&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;46&lt;/i&gt;(3-4), 435–464. https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11125-017-9389-6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;lacet_haiti2012trauma&quot;&gt;Lacet, C. E. (2012). &lt;i&gt;Trauma and resilience: The relocation experiences of Haitian women earthquake survivors&lt;/i&gt; [PhD thesis]. Boston College.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;o_haiti2019crisis&quot;&gt;O’Brien, S., &amp;amp; Federici, F. M. (2019). Crisis translation: considering language needs in multilingual disaster settings. &lt;i&gt;Disaster Prevention and Management: An International Journal&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;rstc_Pearl2019&quot;&gt;RSTC. (2019). Eyes Of The World On Saint Lucia As Horse Racing Launches : Press Release -Royal Saint Lucia Turf Club . In &lt;i&gt;St. Lucia Times News&lt;/i&gt;. St. Lucia Times News &amp;amp; Royal Saint Lucia Turf Club (RSTC). https://stluciatimes.com/eyes-of-the-world-on-saint-lucia-as-horse-racing-launches/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;reynolds2017&quot;&gt;Reynolds, A. The Pearl of the Caribbean - jakoproductions.com. In &lt;i&gt;The Pearl of the Caribbean&lt;/i&gt;. Jako Productions. http://www.jakoproductions.com/society/ThePearlofTheCaribbean.pdf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;parks_williams_Signlang2011&quot;&gt;Parks, E., &amp;amp; Williams, H. (2011). Sociolinguistic Profiles of Twenty-four Deaf Communities in the Americas. In &lt;i&gt;SIL International :SIL Electronic Survey Reports&lt;/i&gt;. SIL International Publications . https://www.sil.org/resources/publications/entry/41653&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;thomas2018degree&quot;&gt;Thomas-Sunesson, D., Hakuta, K., &amp;amp; Bialystok, E. (2018). Degree of bilingualism modifies executive control in Hispanic children in the USA. &lt;i&gt;International Journal of Bilingual Education and Bilingualism&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;21&lt;/i&gt;(2), 197–206. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5942592/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;woolard2004codeswitching&quot;&gt;Woolard, K. A. (2004). Codeswitching. &lt;i&gt;A Companion to Linguistic Anthropology&lt;/i&gt;, 73–94.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;bilaniuk2010language&quot;&gt;Bilaniuk, L. (2010). Language in the balance: The politics of non-accommodation on bilingual Ukrainian–Russian television shows. &lt;i&gt;International Journal of the Sociology of Language&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;2010&lt;/i&gt;(201), 105–133.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;carrington1988creole&quot;&gt;Carrington, L. D. (1988). Creole discourse and social development. &lt;i&gt;Manuscript Report/IDRC; 212e&lt;/i&gt;. https://idl-bnc-idrc.dspacedirect.org/bitstream/handle/10625/35009/IDL-35009.pdf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;charlemange_2017&quot;&gt;Charlemange, K. P. (2017). Kwéyòl In Schools. In &lt;i&gt;St. Lucia News From The Voice St. Lucia&lt;/i&gt;. The Voice St. Lucia. https://www.thevoiceslu.com/2017/10/kweyol-in-schools/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;unesco_2017&quot;&gt;UNESCO. (2017). Technical and Vocational Education and Training (TVET) Policy Review: Saint Lucia. In &lt;i&gt;unesdoc.unesco.org&lt;/i&gt;. United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization. https://unesdoc.unesco.org/ark:/48223/pf0000247494&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;anthony_2017&quot;&gt;Anthony, P. (2017). FRC Targets Youth to Promote Creole Culture in October. In &lt;i&gt;HTS News 4orce &lt;/i&gt;. HTS News 4orce &amp;amp; Folk Research Centre’s Press release. https://www.htsstlucia.org/frc-targets-youth-to-promote-creole-culture-in-october/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;slu_news_online_2019&quot;&gt;Online, S. L. U. N. (2019). Folk Research Centre yet to receive report on cause of its ’disastrous fire.’ In &lt;i&gt;St. Lucia News Online&lt;/i&gt;. stlucianewsonline.com. https://www.stlucianewsonline.com/folk-research-centre-yet-to-receive-report-on-cause-of-its-disastrous-fire/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;dbs_SALCC_2020&quot;&gt;DBS. (2020). SALCC Offers Kweyol Language Classes. In &lt;i&gt;dbstvstlucia&lt;/i&gt;. Daher Broadcasting Service (DBS). http://dbstvstlucia.com/2020/07/14/salcc-offers-kweyol-language-classes/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;salcc_2020&quot;&gt;SALCC. (2020). Modern Language Learning. In &lt;i&gt;SALCC&lt;/i&gt;. SALCC. https://salcc.edu.lc/Modern Language.html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;cba_2012&quot;&gt;CBA. (2012). In &lt;i&gt;The Caribbean Bar Association&lt;/i&gt;. caribbeanbar.org. https://www.caribbeanbar.org/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://llord1.github.io/2020/07/08/Assets&quot;&gt;Back to: Safety and security needs: Assets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Assets: Assessing the link between law and linguistics - Analysis</title>
   <link href="http://llord1.github.io/2020/08/26/AssetsSLUlaw"/>
   <updated>2020-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://llord1.github.io/2020/08/26/AssetsSLUlaw</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h3 id=&quot;safety-and-security-needs-can-be-explored-as-topics-related-to-assets&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Safety and security needs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; can be explored as topics related to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Assets&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a time of crisis, such as the 2020 SARS-CoV-2 pandemic, Maslow’s theory of needs aids in visualizing and prioritizing scarce resources based on an individual’s needs &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#maslow_1943_2000&quot;&gt;(Maslow, 1943; Mcleod, 2020; Matias et al., 2020; Casale &amp;amp; Flett, 2020; Wong et al., 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. Often, obtaining our needs is intrinsically linked to the ease with which we are able to communicate - our ability to understand and to be understood. To effectively facilitate the communication of various societal needs, data science can be employed as a means of monitoring and maintaining the standards of numerous fields through the careful study of an environment’s linguistics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, our sense of safety and security can be linked to the ease with which we can understand the medical advice being relayed to us by medical professionals or their ability to understand the symptoms we describe. As recently as 2019, Sweden conducted a national study on health care professionals’ communications through interpreters; an investigation occurred after noting that many parents utilizing neonatal care were foreign-born and unable to effectively communicate with the healthcare professionals in the local language, &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#patriksson2019health&quot;&gt;(Patriksson et al., 2019)&lt;/a&gt;.  In 2013, linguistic one work highlighted communications issues between physicians and Spanish-speaking Latin American women with pelvic floor disorders &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#sevilla2013communication&quot;&gt;(Sevilla et al., 2013)&lt;/a&gt;. This study highlighted that apart from patients’ lack of understanding concerning the disease, there was a lack of Spanish proficiency among the participating physicians. Even in 2009, there was a study done on competent peer support intervention for Spanish-speaking Latinas with breast cancer &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#napoles2009developing&quot;&gt;(Nápoles-Springer et al., 2009)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notably, one of the areas most closely associated with ensuring societal safety and security would be a country’s legal system. This system encompasses police officers and high courts, however, the position of utmost importance in navigating the legal system on an individual’s behalf - one’s voice in the court - would be their lawyer. Therefore, the effectiveness of communication between lawyers and the client can be fundamentally linked to that client’s freedom. Data science can therefore be used as a means of monitoring and maintaining justice through the exploration of legal data; trends may be uncovered on the probability of innocent or guilty verdicts, given the lawyer’s capacity to communicate in the client’s dominant language (mother tongue).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, the Caribbean can serve as a rich multilingual setting in which one can explore the relationship between law and linguistics. The 2006 case for Gerald Joseph’s criminal appeal, served to highlight the importance of proper linguistic consideration for clients that speak heritage languages (missing reference), do these cases occur most often require Family law, Land law, Property law, Environmental law, or perhaps Employment law, Human rights law, and even Criminal law. Based on the verdict of cases, it may also be possible to predict the likelihood of one winning a case where one’s language limitations are part of their legal defense. Where possible, additional demographic data may be highlighted to provide additional parameters for the calculation of the likelihood of success or failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considerations may need to be made as to the setting of the cases. Should the case be considered a success or a failure if the defendant is the creole speaker? What happens if the plaintiff is the speaker and wins? What happens if the plaintiff is the speaker and loses? What happens when both are creole speakers? Were court-appointed interpreters used?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional complications may include the fact that there are various types of creole in the Caribbean. Some are French-based like Haitian Creole and Antillean Kwéyòl (Saint Lucian and Dominican). Others may be English-based; this may include Jamaican and Barbadian (but may also include a Saint Lucian variant &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#irvine2020st&quot;&gt;(Irvine, 2020; Hilaire, 2008; St-Hilaire, 2011)&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally, Papiamento or Papiamentu, a Portuguese-based creole language, is also present in the Caribbean; however, it is mostly restricted to the Dutch Caribbean/ ABC islands, having official status in Aruba and Curaçao, and is a recognized language in the Dutch public bodies of Bonaire, Sint-Eustatius and Saba).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This analysis will begin with cases in the Caribbean region (as this is a highly multilingual setting) from the database of www.eccourts.org; if the data is insufficient parameters will be widened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will need to settle on a model once sufficient data has been identified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After testing the necessary preliminary analysis is conducted, documents will be developed, finalized, and shopped around to the various related journals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This document may be paired with the industry multilinguistic competency survey of Saint Lucian lawyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://llord1.github.io/2020/08/26/AssetsSLUlawsurvey&quot;&gt;Survey discussion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;maslow_1943_2000&quot;&gt;Maslow, A. H. (1943). Theory of Human Motivation : Psychological Review. In &lt;i&gt;Classics in the History of Psychology: A Theory of Human Motivation&lt;/i&gt;. Christopher D. Green of York University, Toronto, Ontario . https://psychclassics.yorku.ca/Maslow/motivation.htm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;mcleod_2020&quot;&gt;Mcleod, S. (2020). Maslow’s Hierarchy of Needs. In &lt;i&gt;Simply Psychology&lt;/i&gt;. Simply Psychology. https://www.simplypsychology.org/maslow.html#needs7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;matias2020human&quot;&gt;Matias, T., Dominski, F. H., &amp;amp; Marks, D. F. (2020). &lt;i&gt;Human needs in COVID-19 isolation&lt;/i&gt;. SAGE Publications Sage UK: London, England. https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/1359105320925149&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;casale2020interpersonally&quot;&gt;Casale, S., &amp;amp; Flett, G. L. (2020). Interpersonally-based fears during the COVID-19 pandemic: Reflections on the fear of missing out and the fear of not mattering constructs. &lt;i&gt;Clinical Neuropsychiatry&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;17&lt;/i&gt;(2), 88–93. https://doi.org/10.36131/CN20200211&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;wong2020healing&quot;&gt;Wong, A. H., Pacella-LaBarbara, M. L., Ray, J. M., Ranney, M. L., &amp;amp; Chang, B. P. (2020). Healing the Healer: Protecting Emergency Health Care Workers’ Mental Health During COVID-19. &lt;i&gt;Annals of Emergency Medicine&lt;/i&gt;. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7196406/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;patriksson2019health&quot;&gt;Patriksson, K., Wigert, H., Berg, M., &amp;amp; Nilsson, S. (2019). Health care professional’s communication through an interpreter where language barriers exist in neonatal care: a national study. &lt;i&gt;BMC Health Services Research&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;19&lt;/i&gt;(1), 586. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12913-019-4428-z&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;sevilla2013communication&quot;&gt;Sevilla, C., Wieslander, C. K., Alas, A. N., Dunivan, G. C., Khan, A. A., Maliski, S. L., Rogers, R. G., &amp;amp; Anger, J. T. (2013). Communication between physicians and Spanish-speaking Latin American women with pelvic floor disorders: a cycle of misunderstanding? &lt;i&gt;Female Pelvic Medicine &amp;amp; Reconstructive Surgery&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;19&lt;/i&gt;(2), 90.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;napoles2009developing&quot;&gt;Nápoles-Springer, A. M., Ortı́z Carmen, O’Brien, H., &amp;amp; Dı́az-Méndez Marynieves. (2009). Developing a culturally competent peer support intervention for Spanish-speaking Latinas with breast cancer. &lt;i&gt;Journal of Immigrant and Minority Health&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;11&lt;/i&gt;(4), 268. https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1007/s10903-008-9128-4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;irvine2020st&quot;&gt;Irvine, M. (2020). St. Lucia Creole English and Dominica Creole English. &lt;i&gt;World Englishes&lt;/i&gt;. https://doi.org/0.1111/weng.12519&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;hilaire2008postcolonialism&quot;&gt;Hilaire, A. S. (2008). Postcolonialism, identity, and the French language in St. Lucia. &lt;i&gt;New West Indian Guide/Nieuwe West-Indische Gids&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;81&lt;/i&gt;(1-2), 55–77.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;hilaire2011kweyol&quot;&gt;St-Hilaire, A. (2011). &lt;i&gt;Kwéyòl in postcolonial Saint Lucia: Globalization, language planning, and national development&lt;/i&gt; (Vol. 40). John Benjamins Publishing. https://www.jbe-platform.com/content/books/9789027284648&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://llord1.github.io/2020/07/08/Assets&quot;&gt;Back to: Safety and security needs: Assets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What can an LIWC Sentiment analysis on Maslow's works reveal?</title>
   <link href="http://llord1.github.io/2020/07/08/Sentiment"/>
   <updated>2020-07-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://llord1.github.io/2020/07/08/Sentiment</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h2 id=&quot;brief-introduction&quot;&gt;Brief introduction:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his 1943 paper for Psychological Review, &lt;em&gt;A Theory of Human Motivation&lt;/em&gt;, Abraham Maslow promoted a visual representation of his psychological theory. The model, dubbed as Maslow’s Hierarchy of Needs, was a tiered hierarchy of human needs; it was a motivational theory in psychology. The five-tiered version of this hierarchy has been widely used in various fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This framework, however, is mostly utilized in business settings. Some leaders might consider this theory when planning project productivity goals, while most leaders turn to this theory to investigate and explain why productivity goals were not met. Here, negative connections can be drawn to the framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exploring Maslow’s existing works with the Linguistic Inquiry and Word Count (LIWC) tool, might provide more insight into how his framework is applied. If his works are more negative than positive, this may assist in surmising why leaders employ his structure as a tool that categorizes employee problems, rather than individuals utilizing it as an inspirational and aspirational structure. Despite Maslow’s hierarchy being well-known in business environments, leaders may seldom employ this model to assess themselves and their personal goals. Moreover, businesses are more likely to create employee surveys based on this framework than directly educate employees on the framework’s possible application to their individual lives, and how their productivity in the workplace is impacted by it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hypothesis&quot;&gt;Hypothesis:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maslow’s works are more negative than positive in tone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;topics-to-be-discussed&quot;&gt;Topics to be discussed:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What can an LIWC Sentiment analysis on Maslow’s works reveal about the overall tone of his contributions?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Is the tone of his work being misinterpreted as innately negative?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Which psychological processes best illustrate his works?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Should it be assumed that the “affective processes” of negative and positive be the only areas for exploration, or should other areas be explored?&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Can his work be best assessed as focusing on “personal concerns” like work, leisure, home, money, and religion; or by “drives” of affliction achievement, power, reward, and risk? Perhaps the sexual and ingestion “biological processes” are his true focus, or the “social processes” topics of family, friends, female references, and male references.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Can the LIWC’s psychological processes be categorized into the structure of Maslow’s psychological needs, or would there be areas of overlap?&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Can a visual mapping be created to display this interaction?&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;additional-liwc-capabilities&quot;&gt;Additional LIWC capabilities:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Are all the psychological needs quantifiably equal when paired with their relative psychological processes?  For example, does the score of “belonging and love”  within the lens of the “biological process” match “social processes”’s?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Are all levels of the hierarchy equally discussed, or are do they vary based on their position in the structure and their topic matter? For example, is the topic of “physiological needs” going share the same word count as “self-actualization”? Do they have the same “analytical thinking” score?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Or do these “psychological needs” demonstrate a score reflective of their position in the structure.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;More reading is required on the LIWC. Since both the LIWC and Maslow’s hierarchy utilize similar terminology associated with psychological needs/ processes, was its creation influenced by Maslow? If so, what was the extent?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sources-for-maslows-works&quot;&gt;Sources for Maslow’s works:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This includes a comprehensive list of interviews, articles, audio and video material, and books in and out of print: http://www.maslow.com/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Self-actualization needs: topics related to Awareness</title>
   <link href="http://llord1.github.io/2020/07/08/Awareness"/>
   <updated>2020-07-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://llord1.github.io/2020/07/08/Awareness</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h2 id=&quot;self-actualization-needs-can-be-explored-as-topics-related-to-awareness&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Self-actualization needs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; can be explored as topics related to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Awareness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Self-esteem needs: topics related to Attitudes</title>
   <link href="http://llord1.github.io/2020/07/08/Attitudes"/>
   <updated>2020-07-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://llord1.github.io/2020/07/08/Attitudes</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h2 id=&quot;self-esteem-needs-can-be-explored-as-topics-related-to-attitudes&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Self-esteem needs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; can be explored as topics related to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Attitudes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Assets: Impact of tourism on Saint Lucian Kwéyòl language vitality</title>
   <link href="http://llord1.github.io/2020/07/08/AssetsTourism"/>
   <updated>2020-07-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://llord1.github.io/2020/07/08/AssetsTourism</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h3 id=&quot;safety-and-security-needs-can-be-explored-as-topics-related-to-assets&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Safety and security needs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; can be explored as topics related to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Assets&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What impact, if any, does tourism have on the vitality of the Saint Lucian Kwéyòl language? What factors elevated the prestige language on over the heritage language? For example, are tourists likely to move freely throughout all communities, or just certain ones based on the number of tourist attractions or ease of transportation (based on infrastructure)? Consequently, vendors of those communities may frequently defer to the prestige language when engaging in tourists due to the positive reinforcement associated with a successful sale. Also, are educational facilities of impressionable youths located near tourist hubs?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This study would entail observing data on various areas of interest related to tourism in Saint Lucia. For example, examining data on the number of tourist attractions per district, number of hotels per district,  the ports of entry per district, number of jobs related to tourism per district, number of educational facilities per district, and the number of main government offices per district. The final details may lead to a discussion of language hotspots; and a possible explanation of their existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;current-data-sources&quot;&gt;Current data sources:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://data.govt.lc/dataset/hotel-listings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://data.govt.lc/dataset/st-lucia-hotel-locations (coordinates)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://data.govt.lc/dataset/tourism-indicators&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://data.govt.lc/dataset/st-lucia-communities&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://data.govt.lc/dataset/st-lucia-districts (includes coordinates and basic population demographics)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://data.govt.lc/dataset/labour-force-statistics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(List of tabulations and indicators 2014 - 2017)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://data.govt.lc/dataset/location-data-st-lucia-schools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://data.govt.lc/dataset/locations-highways&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://data.govt.lc/dataset/st-lucia-police-stations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://llord1.github.io/2020/07/08/Assets&quot;&gt;Back to: Safety and security needs: Assets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Safety and security needs: topics related to Assets</title>
   <link href="http://llord1.github.io/2020/07/08/Assets"/>
   <updated>2020-07-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://llord1.github.io/2020/07/08/Assets</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h2 id=&quot;safety-and-security-needs-can-be-explored-as-topics-related-to-assets&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Safety and security needs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; can be explored as topics related to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Assets&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assessing the link between crime and language. Could miscommunication between prestige and heritage language speakers hinder legal defenses? Are there any metrics on lawyers’ multilingual lawyers on the island? Are there any laws related to representation requirements (do lawyers assess the language needs of clients to decide how best to assist them)? What are the rates of incarceration of predominantly Saint Lucian Kwéyòl language speakers? What are the inmate metrics per district of origin (there is a popular belief that most Saint Lucian Kwéyòl language speakers are located in the Southern part of the country)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://llord1.github.io/2020/08/26/AssetsSLUlaw&quot;&gt;Lawyer demographics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What impact, if any, does tourism have on the vitality of the Saint Lucian Kwéyòl language? What factors elevated the prestige language on over the heritage language? This entails observing the number of ports of entry per district, number of tourist attractions per district, number of hotels per district, number of jobs related to tourism per district, number of educational facilities per district, number of main government offices per district. The final details may lead to a discussion of language hotspots; and a possible explanation of their existence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://llord1.github.io/2020/07/08/AssetsTourism&quot;&gt;Tourism’s impact on Saint Lucian languages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Analysis: Spanish Mnemonic Tools </title>
   <link href="http://llord1.github.io/2020/06/08/AnalysisMnemonic"/>
   <updated>2020-06-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://llord1.github.io/2020/06/08/AnalysisMnemonic</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h2 id=&quot;cognitive-needs-can-be-explored-as-topics-related-to-analysis&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cognitive needs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; can be explored as topics related to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Analysis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What language learning tools are most effective with acquiring Saint Lucian Kwéyòl language? A comparison of specially curated language learning tools: discussion of the value of puzzles for language acquisition and familiarity (word search puzzles), discussion of curated mnemonic tools, and language learning mobile applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pursuit of language learning is one done with the hopes of improving communication; to understand and to be understood. It should be acknowledged that languages consist of text data, albeit well-established corpora. Often language teachers are challenged with the task of exploring such corpora and finding creating ways to simplify inherently complex language concepts. This undertaking is often done with the aid of some visual aids; however, the standards of visualizations vary as teachers are often expected to create unique learning tools to explain standard course material to each new class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Language teachers are encouraged to keep their visualization of the age-old corpora fresh. Moreover, they are increasingly expected to incorporate technology into their works where possible. However, the application of the latest forms of technology is not always suitable; at times, simplicity is indeed the best option. Therefore, the goal here is to investigate the established forms of data visualization when teaching languages and attempt to rank them. Ranking can assist with forming future recommendations for the teaching of specific topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spanish is one of the most popular languages spoken in the world and taught in schools; it is also listed as one of the more simple languages to acquire as a second language. In fact, while the Kwéyòl, the heritage language of Saint Lucia, is taught in only a handful of schools on the island, Spanish is one of the main languages commonly taught in most high schools. Since the learning of Spanish is so common, investigations seeking the simplification of complex linguistic concepts could ease language acquisition, and indirectly enhance communications in society. Data visualization could improve how individuals can absorb this language information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the teaching and learning of Spanish verbs can be difficult. In Spanish, most verbs can be classified based on their endings of AR, ER, and AR. Conjugating the verbs requires an understanding of concepts such as regular and irregular endings. Verbs may also be classified based on the “stem change” involved in conjugation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, verbs are typically taught using simple tables. Even if one were to focus on stem-changing verbs, tables are indeed the most common form of displaying the information. While not very visually interesting, this is the standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/llord1/llord1.github.io/master/resources/pictures/plaintable.png&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&amp;lt;/div

-&amp;gt;![Table2](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/llord1/llord1.github.io/master/resources/pictures/plain.png)&amp;lt;-

Other teachers may attempt to make this information more visually appealing by highlighting their related labels.

-&amp;gt;![Table3](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/llord1/llord1.github.io/master/resources/pictures/tablee.png)&amp;lt;-

Some teachers have unofficially adopted the &quot;shoe/boot verbs method&quot; to emphasize the visualization of the verb conjugation. 

-&amp;gt;![Boot1](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/llord1/llord1.github.io/master/resources/pictures/boot.png)&amp;lt;-

-&amp;gt;![Boot2](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/llord1/llord1.github.io/master/resources/pictures/boot2.png)&amp;lt;-

-&amp;gt;![Boot3](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/llord1/llord1.github.io/master/resources/pictures/boot3.png)&amp;lt;-

-&amp;gt;![Boot4](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/llord1/llord1.github.io/master/resources/pictures/boot-verbs.png)&amp;lt;-


Another less popular method in the US is the &quot;hand method&quot;. This form assigns persons to fingers on one's hand. 

-&amp;gt;![Traditional hand](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/llord1/llord1.github.io/master/resources/pictures/traditionalhand.png)&amp;lt;-

This method is reminiscent of the Guidonian hand mnemonic device used to aid singers in studying to sight-sing. 
-&amp;gt;![Guidonian](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/llord1/llord1.github.io/master/resources/pictures/ghand.png)&amp;lt;-


This form, however, excludes the second-person-plural version of verbs - the vosotros form. This form is not necessarily difficult to learn, only novel to many persons that learned Spanish in the Americas; when looking at Spanish being acquired in Latin America versus Spain, the use of vosotros can mean the difference between being formally correct or informally fluent, respectively.



Recently, it had been suggested this hand mnemonic device could be adapted to include all the verb conjugation details. The vosotros form can be acknowledged as special rather than being ignored; this uniqueness can be highlighted through its association with the ring finger.

-&amp;gt;![My version](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/llord1/llord1.github.io/master/resources/pictures/myhands.PNG)&amp;lt;-


[Back to: Cognitive needs: Analysis](https://llord1.github.io/2020/06/08/Analysis)
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Cognitive needs: topics related to Analysis</title>
   <link href="http://llord1.github.io/2020/06/08/Analysis"/>
   <updated>2020-06-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://llord1.github.io/2020/06/08/Analysis</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h2 id=&quot;cognitive-needs-can-be-explored-as-topics-related-to-analysis&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cognitive needs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; can be explored as topics related to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Analysis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://llord1.github.io/2020/06/08/AnalysisMnemonic&quot;&gt;Back to: Cognitive needs: Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Biological and physiological needs: topics related to Ambience</title>
   <link href="http://llord1.github.io/2020/05/08/Ambience"/>
   <updated>2020-05-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://llord1.github.io/2020/05/08/Ambience</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h2 id=&quot;biological-and-physiological-needs--can-be-explored-as-topics-related-to-ambience&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Biological and physiological needs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;  can be explored as topics related to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ambience&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Transcendence needs: topics related to Altruism</title>
   <link href="http://llord1.github.io/2020/04/08/Altruism"/>
   <updated>2020-04-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://llord1.github.io/2020/04/08/Altruism</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h2 id=&quot;transcendence-needs-can-be-explored-as-topics-related-to-altruism&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transcendence needs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; can be explored as topics related to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Altruism&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An online creole dictionary resource has been provided by SIL(Summer Institute of Linguistics) International Publications, however, it is incomplete. Many words are missing altogether, and some present words bearing multiple meanings (many of which are not stated).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there an existing model for implementing community discussion of dictionaries?  Is it possible to create an infrastructure for community collaboration of an endangered language?
Is it possible to explore the implementation of an online dictionary resource through a systems dynamic model? And would other models be more applicable (for example, the application of the predator-prey Lotka-Volterra model,  or the WORLD3 Model)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discussion:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Online dictionaries allow users and compilers opportunities far beyond those of traditional publishing constructions. For an endangered language, the use of such a resource becoming increasingly essential. However, the use of static online dictionaries may not be sufficient to meet the demands of language that is slowly dying. Static dictionaries with dynamic qualities may better serve the needs of cataloging an endangered language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Online dictionaries can benefit from using technology to update their records regularly. This not only pertains to new sections of the alphabet but “also with words of particular interest to its users at the time”. Words such as LOL and YOLO were online slangs that were added to the Oxford English Dictionary (OED) in 2011, and 2016 respectively. The third edition of the OED appears to no longer suppress widely‑used slang terms, however, it certainly is incapable of documenting the meaning and use of every fleeting term used among small assortments of speakers within the entirety of English‑speaking world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Urban Dictionary is the free service of an online dictionary of contemporary English slang usage; it is a “collaborative project of over 1 million definitions for over 400,000 unique headwords”. It serves as an online lexicography where public contributors explain the meanings of words and phrases not readily covered by traditional dictionaries; contributors collaborate, cooperate, and compete for meaning-making. Eventually, depending on the proliferation of use in society, official dictionaries, such as OED, may elect to officially adopt a word from such a collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The collaborative compilation of online lexicography is, therefore, known to linguistics. In fact, there is a webpage, similar to Urban Dictionary, that strategically caters to Caribbean consumers. While the region bears various peoples with differing histories, they do share similarities. Most of these similarities, however, are the unfortunate result of colonialization from similar superpowers, certain words are ubiquitous due to the ease of traversing and settling in neighboring countries. Persons of these areas experience similar flora and fauna, and environmental and social phenomena that are endemic to their setting and way of life. The website, Wiwords, is a dynamic online dictionary that highlights instances of shared vocabulary, as well as allowing for contributions that are unique to certain countries in the Caribbean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should, however, be noted that Saint Lucians do not appear to be highly active in this online linguistic community. For example, there are no contributions to the section outlined for local “quotes” or sayings, when these are quite abundant in the local language. Most participation from Saint Lucia pertains to discussions of food, and animal and plant life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the Antillean creole spoken in Saint Lucia can benefit from utilizing online language resources. A pidgin is language variety developed by speakers in contact who share no common language; it would have limited functions of use, is linguistically simplified, and has developed its own rules and norms of usage. Creole languages are developed from pidgins, and severe as the first language of some members of a speech community, where it is used for a wide range of functions. Since creole languages seldomly achieve official status, the speakers of a fully formed creole may eventually feel compelled to conform their speech to one of the parent languages. This decreolization process typically brings about a post-creole speech continuum characterized by large scale variation and hypercorrection in the language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, to better preserve the creole language within Saint Lucia,  a dynamic online community dictionary would be very useful in keeping certain words active. However, there are flaws in this structure that can be improved upon. Public contributors may understand the language in terms of speaking it, however, they may not be the best teachers; that is to say that contributors may not always be clear in their explanations or contributions. Overall, straying from official spellings of words can contribute to data entry issues. For example, one can observe the accents used with “chofé” - “to heat up”,  and “chofè” - a “driver”. These words without context and accents would be very difficult to decipher. Persons being inaccurately applying accents, or unable to access the necessary unique characters were required (diacritics) for formal grammar can present problems in documenting the language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue with dictionary compilation in this region may deal with the overlap of meanings attributed to certain words. Many-to one-relations between words and their meanings (e.g. homonymy and polysemy) are often not included in lists when studying this grammatical phenomenon for a unique language like creole. In addition to synonyms, frequent polysemy, the presence of homonyms and homophones and the phenomena sometimes referred to as the “false friends” of the translator.
Dictionaries recognize the distinction between polysemy and
homonymy by making a polysemous item a single dictionary entry
and making homophonous lexemes two or more separate entries; polysemous terms can though different can be derived from one basic idea, and the related terms reflect that image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polysemy is a common occurrence in the endangered language of Saint Lucian Antillean creole. An indication of a polysemous verb in English is one that corresponds to different verbs when translated into other languages. For example, one can review the English word for “ask” (for information) and “ask” (for action); this can be interpreted as one word “vragen” in Dutch, however, the majority of other languages use different words for each interpretation in English, like “fragen” and “bitten” in German, and “preguntar” and “pedir” in Spanish. In Saint Lucian creole,  this can be seen where the term “mwen” can mean “me” or “my”, or the term “asou” can mean “on” or “lean against”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the word, “Creole” can be viewed as a contested, polysemous term in the English language. The term has been used at different times and in various geographical regions to describe distinct identities, languages, peoples, ethnicities, racial heritages, and cultural artefacts. As an adjective, Creole was applied as an indicator of higher status bestowed upon Louisiana-born slaves to distinguish them from those born in African. It was also used as a noun to designate local birth in Louisiana, regardless of racial heritage; later Creole was used by Americans when referring to people of Spanish or French descent, yet it has often been conflated with the term “Cajan” (which described French colonists that settled in Canada’s Acadia region, then migrated to Louisiana). In fact, for some time, there was also a misconception that the term only referred to whites born in Louisiana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, Creole primarily refers to one’s linguistic heritage (French culture and a unique Franco-linguistic dialect) as the main source of their ethnic identity (particularly those of mixed or foreign ancestry). Creole, ‘Kreyol’ or ‘Kweyol’ also refers to the creole languages in the Caribbean, including Antillean Creole, Haitian Creole, and Jamaican Creole, among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polysemy may indeed present an issue for when attempting to study a language or dialects, however, it is in fact, the premise of much of the active literature in this language. Calypso, and most other endemic forms of music, may celebrate this ability to utilize words or phrases bearing double meanings to indirectly discuss topics that are often crude. Philips suggested that Calypsos can engage this method via ‘lamina lyrics’. &lt;em&gt;Much like an onion, these Calypsos have a number of different levels of meaning, concealed one underneath the other. Achieving this phenomenon, Calypsonians use frames and masks that manifest in Calypsos as a metaphor, metonym, polysemy, irony, and satire&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1863, August Schleicher, the German linguist, discussed languages as &lt;em&gt;natural organisms that come into being, develop, age, and die according to laws that are quite independent of man’s will&lt;/em&gt; (cited by Arens 1969:259). This perception of language is contrary to recent the modern view that it is one’s set of communication habits that have principally been defined by their social experience, led by an innate sense to decipher and learn the language practices of others. However, despite having a few members of “native speaking generation” left, often communities lack the implementation of structures dedicated to the retention of language. Therefore, successive generations may require resources that express the necessity of the language as well as its desirability to ensure its continuance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mohan is of the view that living languages can die before “the last trace of memory has vanished”; that these languages may be experiencing a feigned guise of life through its observation of “sympathetic post-users from outside its system” (1979:42). To further quote Mohan, there are two senses in which an obsolescent language becomes dead before its forms have completely disappeared:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A small part of the non-native speaking generation has preserved dead tokens of the language. Also, the time gap between the age of the youngest native speaker and the latest possible age of language acquisition, in infancy, shows the language dead at its source, but with a now finite community of native speakers continuing, like the earlier light of a dead star, to travel its original course and give an illusion picture of vitality. (313)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover,  Sasse (2001) lists ten changes occurring during language obsolescence;  several of which bear similarities to those described by Campbell &amp;amp; Muntzel (1989) and Palosaari &amp;amp; Campbell (2011), namely: &lt;em&gt;loss of phonological distinctions, regularization of morphophonemics, loss of function words, analyticity, loss of morphology, loss of syntactic complexity, agrammatism, phonological and grammatical variability, reduction of vocabulary, and an increase in polysemy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evaluating and creating structures is crucial for the preservation and promotion of endangered languages.
&lt;strong&gt;Need to expand on the definition of systems dynamic model and other models here…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perceptions of the locals’ attitudes towards the creole language are often complicated. Language change in Saint Lucia has been a pressing concern for academics for many years. As recent as 1970,  Douglas Midgett highlighted that the formal teaching of Patois would be viewed as “unjustifiable and in any case, would never be tolerated by even its most ardent user”. At the time, he noted that most people agreed that increased proficiency in spoken and written English (or French) would be an educational must, however, writers and other academics and actual educators had differing views; the former group believed that use of creole in schools could aid with recognizing English as a second language, whereas educators adamantly argued against any use of Creoles in the schools. He believed that the use of Patois in the schools interchangeably with less formal, more colloquial English would aid in establishing English in the minds of students as a functional Patois equivalent. He suggested that as long as educational institutions reinforce the conventional traditional opinion of separating the two languages, the campaign for English literacy and spoken usage will not have widespread effectiveness. Midgett, however, underestimated how pervasive the English language would be; in fact, it is the creole language that currently lacks proper literacy among the public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1998, Frank explored and even expanded the written form of the creole language in Saint Lucia while attempting to effectively translate an English bible into the local language. Upon concluding his tasks he remarked that the bible would indirectly boost creole literacy through the motivational passages of the bible:
 &lt;em&gt;“… for all practical purposes Creole remains an unwritten language for the majority of the population, which remains unaware of the books published in Creole. Attempts to teach Creole literacy have not met with much success because of lack of interest. Motivation is the most important factor in the success of any literacy program, and having something people want to read is the most important motivating factor”&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ultimately leaves one to wonder if it is logical and possible to merge an official online static dictionary with a dynamic slang dictionary to increase fluency of an endangered language? Such as system would require access to an existing dictionary, as well as opportunities for dictionary contributions. The creation of an interactive dictionary may assist with reinvigorating the usage of the language through active use and contributions to this resource, but also offer opportunities to actively discuss and clarify words and concepts associated with creole.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Love and belonging needs can be explored as topics related to Affiliation</title>
   <link href="http://llord1.github.io/2020/03/08/Affiliation"/>
   <updated>2020-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://llord1.github.io/2020/03/08/Affiliation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;affiliation-through-language&quot;&gt;Affiliation through Language:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How effective has the vocabulary of Indian origin been in its contribution to St. Lucian Creole Vocabulary? Are the words strictly isolated to food, and a few racial descriptors?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hypothesis&quot;&gt;Hypothesis:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vocabulary of Indian origin are present in low rates and strictly isolated to food and racial descriptors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;null-hypothesis&quot;&gt;Null hypothesis:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vocabulary of Indian origin has no effect on beyond food and racial descriptors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;commentary&quot;&gt;Commentary:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only relevant literature on this topic thus far is a statement on one of SIL’s reports :
“Vocabulary of Indian Origin. Most of the few words in St. Lucian Creole of Indian origin have to do with cuisine: dal (Hindi), dalpouri, goulgoula, gwodja, kirou, kòri (Tamil), mango (Tamil), roti (Hindi), sohari and talkari. There are also two words, kouli [&amp;lt; Hindi qūlī ‘hired servant’] and dogla [&amp;lt; Hindi dogalaa ‘hybrid’], that have to do with ethnicity.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;http://www.saintluciancreole.dbfrank.net/workpapers/sources_of_vocabulary.pdf&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One may find data to support this experiment as Trinidad has a high Indian population of creole speakers, and Antillean creole shares some vocabulary (can check Wiwords for similarities).&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Aesthetic needs: topics related to Artistry</title>
   <link href="http://llord1.github.io/2020/02/08/Aesthetic"/>
   <updated>2020-02-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://llord1.github.io/2020/02/08/Aesthetic</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h2 id=&quot;aesthetic-needs-can-be-explored-as-topics-related-to-artistry&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aesthetic needs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; can be explored as topics related to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Artistry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
